Hey! Yo!
False alarm! Hold it!
It's ok! I'm here.
Here we are!
It's alright.
Yeah.
Set it down nice and easy?
Yeah, sure. At the impound.
Next time read the sign.
Hey! You don't understand. Look.
I'm just here to meet my wife's plane.
You got to let me have this car.
Yeah, sure. Tomorrow, 8:00 to 4:00.
You pay 40 bucks, we give it back.
Don't write it up!
Come on, man.
This is my mother-in-law's car, alright?
She's already mad at me
because I'm not a dentist.
Look, I'm a cop L.A.P.D.
How about a little team spirit?
Oh, I was in L.A. once.
Hated it.
Well, I can understand.
I don't like it much myself.
Hey! That's a plastic fender up there!
Take it easy!
Back off!
I'm doing my job!
Cut me some slack, will you?
Look, I used to be a cop in New York City.
I only moved to L.A. because
my wife took a job there.
Come on.
What do you say?
Here we are. Washington, D.C.,
the heart of democracy.
One hand washes the other.
Come on, man.
It's Christmas.
So ask Santa Claus
to give you another car.
Merry Christmas, pal.
It's all yours, Murray.
Son of a bitch.
Hi. Where are the telephones?
Right over there.
Thank you.
Thank you, Fred.
Leonard Adkins is in a warmer clime,
with a story that grows
hotter by the minute.
Security was tight today at Escalon Airport
in the Republic of Val Verde,
where government authorities report
that deposed general Ramon Esperanza,
will be delivered for immediate
extradition to the United States.
Only two years ago General Esperanza,
led his country's army in a campaign
against communist insurgents.
A campaign fought with
American money and advisers.
Esperanza's fall from power caused ripples
not only in his country's recent election
but closer to home as well,
when high-ranking Pentagon
officials were charged
with supplying him with weapons
despite the congressional ban.
But mounting evidence
that Esperanza's forces
violated the neutrality
of neighboring countries
made Congress withhold funds.
Funds which Esperanza
is accused of replacing
by going into the lucrative
business of cocaine smuggling.
Although Esperanza was removed
as commander in chief earlier this year.
The agreement to extradite him
was not reached until yesterday,
and Washington insiders say
it was a phone call that made it happen.
A phone call from a...
Alright. Alright.
If I could find a phone,
I'd call you, whoever you are.
Excuse me.
Thank you.
Yes, this is Lieutenant McClane.
Somebody there just beep me?
I'd like to think I'm somebody.
Honey!
What are you doing?
Where are you? Did you land yet?
Honey, it's the '90s, remember?
Microchips, microwaves,
faxes, air phones.
Yeah, well, as far as I'm concerned,
progress peaked with frozen pizza.
Listen now,
we're gonna be about half
an hour late landing, ok?
I just wanted to let you know.
The kids ok?
Well, they're about to lose their minds,
from all the sugar your parents
are giving them.
Did Mom give you a hard time
about borrowing her new car?
No.
Not yet.
Listen honey, when you land,
can we, can we just like...
you know rent a car,
check into a hotel?
Leave the kids with your parents.
Order some room service,
a bottle of champagne.
What do you say?
You're on, Lieutenant.
I'll see you in about
a half an hour, honey.
I love you. Bye.
Isn't technology wonderful?
My husband doesn't think so.
Well, I do.
I used to carry around
those awful Mace things.
Now...
I zap any bastard that screws with me.
I tried it on my little dog.
Poor thing limped for a week.
Excuse me.
Boy, you look really familiar to me.
I get that a lot.
I've been on TV.
Yeah. Me too.
Grab the tools, will you?
You got it.
This is Amy Nichole reporting live
from Escalon Airport,
where deposed general
Ramon Esperanza
has just arrived under heavy guard.
Strangely, the deposed
dictator's mood seems jubilant.
He is smiling and waving
to the crowd
like a man running
for political office.
Thousands of political
prisoners in the past decade
including the new president
and there is no doubt
that he still has some
ardent supporters
both here and abroad.
Rumors abound on Capitol Hill
that there were other.
Yeah?
Sorry to bother you, sir.
We're checking our equipment.
Any problems with the conduit
line in your backyard?
Gee, I don't know anything about that.
Would you mind if we take a look?
Help yourself.
It just don't seem right somehow
closing down this church.
Oh I know, the parish is gonna keep on
using it, but it won't be the same.
Been here a lot of years,
and I've been right here with it.
Yeah,
I kind of feel like a piece of me
is dying along with this church.
Well, you're right about that.
Cocaine smuggling,
racketeering and bribing
government officials.
He certainly doesn't show it,
but no matter how high his spirits
they can't hide the fact,
that America's war on drugs,
has finally taken its first prisoner.
This is Buckwheat.
The clubhouse is open.
Here at Dulles,
the quiet men from the
Justice Department
wait to hand-cuff the man
who has come to symbolize the enemy
in America's fight against cocaine.
That battle may be almost won,
but the war is still in doubt.
Samantha Coleman, WNTW,
for Night-Time News.
Roger that, Colonel.
Out.
That was the colonel.
Everyone's in position.
How's the weather?
We got flurries
all along the Virginia coast.
New storm front coming in
from the north east.
God loves the infantry.
Amen.
Carry out your assignments.
15:51.
Mark.
Check.
Later.
Adios, man.
At 16:30 we'll start.
Hey, it's cold out there, man!
I stomped my feet for five minutes.
Yeah, yeah.
Two cappuccinos.
Make it fast.
Scotch, straight up, please.
Excuse me, Officers.
This may sound like a wild-goose chase,
but I think I just saw...
Saw what?
Elvis.
Elvis Presley.
Fucking tourists.
Ought to be a law.
Can I get you something else?
Excuse me, sir.
There's a large number of you from
the Justice Department here this evening.
Is there any particular reason for that?
Just routine.
Just routine?
Yes.
Any comment, sir?
No. Not right now. Thank you.
Thank you, sir.
Thanks.
Hey, that's Colonel Stuart over there.
Got a little problem with personnel.
Last-minute replacement.
How's the security around this place?
Just like we figured.
It's a joke.
Colonel Stuart, could we have
a few words, please?
You can have two,
fuck and you.
No pictures, you pinko bitch.
Old news.
Excuse me.
Hey, man.
What is it?
You got a key for this door?
Yeah. Why?
Because I want you to open it up.
That's why.
Is there a cop on duty around here?
The airport police.
Go get them.
Hand me the wrench, will ya?
Who made you foreman?
Next you're gonna want overtime.
Good idea.
Ok, hold that end.
Watch it, man.
Alright. Perfect.
Perfect.
Good to go.
Hey!
It's a restricted area.
What's the matter?
Couldn't wait for the skycap?
We work here.
Let's see some I.D.
Sure. No problem.
No problem.
Take him!
Jesus H. Fuck!
What is this, a tag team?
You say he came in here
and flashed a badge?
Yeah. He said to bring you guys back here.
Shit.
Christ.
Fucker!
Freeze!
Nice guess, asshole.
I'm a cop.
That was the bad guy.
Where's your I.D.?
On its way to Cleveland?
No, you did not explain anything.
All you did was shove me back here
into this cattle car.
Sir, you were told when you boarded
that we were overbooked.
Fine. Done. I accept that.
But why in hell can't I get
the first-class meal my network paid for?
Do you know who I am?
Yes. We've all seen your program.
Your episode Flying Junkyards
was a very objective look
at air traffic safety.
It wasn't nearly as edifying
as Bimbos of the Sky, was it Connie?
You think you're funny.
Fine.
I've got your number.
And I've got yours.
So park it, sir.
Fine.
Stewardess.
Mr. Thornberg,
you cannot monopolize my time.
You cannot put me near that woman.
Excuse me?
He means he's filed
a restraining order against me.
I'm not allowed within 50 feet of him.
Fifty yards.
So by keeping me in this section,
you are violating a court order.
I can sue you and this airline.
That woman assaulted me,
and she humiliated me in public.
What did you do?
Knocked out two of his teeth.
Would you like some champagne?
Sorry, Officer McClane.
I had to check.
Here's your piece and shield back.
Thanks.
Hey, over here, Officer!
We understand that
there was shooting.
The presence of Justice
Department officials.
Jesus! Oh, Christ!
Hey, come on. Just a word, ok?
What the fuck are you people.
What are you doing here, man?
This is a crime scene.
You got to seal this area off,
for Christ's sake.
That's up to the captain.
Oh, it's up to the captain?
Maybe you better take me
up to the captain then?
Where's Cochrane?
He didn't make it.
Oh, man.
You're late.
We ran into trouble, Colonel.
Some cop.
He killed Cochrane.
I barely got away, sir.
Did you accomplish your mission?
Yes sir but...
Cochrane, sir.
Well, then the damage is minimal.
The penalty could be severe.
You fail me again,
and the chamber won't be empty.
Dismissed.
Who is it? Come in.
Captain Lorenzo?
Yeah.
I'm John McClane.
Yeah, yeah. I know who you are.
You're the asshole
that just broke seven F.A.A.
and five District of Columbia regulations,
running around my airport with a gun,
shooting at people.
What do you call that shit?
Self-defense.
Well, what you think that L.A. badge
is gonna get you,
a free lunch or something around here?
No.
Maybe a little professional courtesy.
In an airport on Christmas week?
You got to be kidding.
Ok. Fuck courtesy.
How about just being professional?
Your boys just walked away
from a crime scene, Captain.
You can't wrap this thing up
in 10 minutes, and you know it.
You got to seal the area off,
take pictures, dust for prints.
Hey, don't lecture me, hotshot.
I know what I'm doing.
We're gonna dust it down.
We'll take all the pictures.
We'll sweep for fibers.
When are you gonna do this?
After three or four hundred
more people go through there?
You'd be lucky to get a print
from one of your own people.
Just shut down that area and
Oh, just shut the area down?
It's that simple?
I just shut the area down?
Shit.
And I got everybody from
the Shriners convention,
to the goddamn Boy Scouts
traipsing through here!
I got lost kids,
lost dogs...
Not now! Later!
I got international diplomats.
I got a fucking reindeer flying in here
from the fucking petting zoo!
But,
John McClane, he's got a little problem.
Hell, let's shut down
the whole fucking airport!
What do you think they're gonna
say upstairs when I tell them that?
Why don't you pick up
the phone and find out?
Because I don't need
full fucking forensics to tell me
all this was, was some punk
stealing luggage!
Luggage?
That punk pulled a Glock 7 on me.
You know what that is?
It's a porcelain gun made in Germany.
It doesn't show up on
your airport x-ray machines,
and it costs more than
you make in a month.
You'd be surprised what I make in a month.
If it's more than $1.98,
I'd be very surprised.
Hey, McClane
don't start believing your own press.
Yeah, yeah, I know all about
you and that Nakatomi thing in L.A.
But just because the TV thinks
you're hot shit, that don't make it so.
Look, you are in my little pond now,
and I am the big fish that runs it.
So you capped some lowlife.
Fine.
I'll send your fucking captain in L.A.
a fucking commendation!
Now in the meantime, you get
the hell out of my office
before I have you thrown out
of my goddamn airport!
Hey, Carmine, let me ask you something.
What sets off the metal detectors first?
The lead in your ass
or the shit in your brains?
Fat fuck.
Any I.D. on this guy?
That's somebody else's problem.
Wait here.
Ok, your car's ready.
If you'd just sign right here
Hi.
I need to borrow this and this.
I'll bring it right back.
Hey!
Hey! Yo! Hold up!
Yo!
Hold up, boys.
Hold up. Hold up.
We got to check something.
What are you doing?
Pretty gruesome fucking job.
In all the confusion in there,
we forgot to get this clown's prints.
Believe that?
Christ.
Hey, you're supposed
to do that at the morgue.
Not anymore.
Got a new S.O.P.
for D.O.A.'s from the F.A.A.
I don't think this one's
gonna make it, boys.
Thanks a lot.
Powell here.
Take that Twinkie out of your
mouth and grab a pencil, will ya?
Hey, John.
How you doing?
Holly stood me up a day,
and I'm here alone in D.C.
with my in-laws.
The old in-laws?
Man, they do love their policemen
son-in-laws, don't they?
Listen, Al, what is the...
fax machine telephone number
there at the station?
Let's see.
555-3212.
3212.
Hold on a second, alright?
I wanna send you something here.
Excuse me.
You and faxes?
This is a first.
Yeah, well, Holly told me I should
wake up and smell the '90s.
This way?
No. That way.
Wait. It's upside down.
It doesn't matter.
Ok. Here it comes.
I'm sending you something right now.
Hold on a second, cowboy.
Fingerprints?
Got an unidentified stiff here.
I've circled the whorls in pen
in case the transmission is a little fuzzy.
Listen, run it through state and federal,
and if you can run it through Interpol.
Will do.
Well, what's this about?
Just a feeling I have.
When you get those feelings,
insurance companies start to go bankrupt.
Listen, the fax number is...
ls on the top edge
of the transmission he just got.
Is on the top edge
of the transmission you just got.
Oh, an airport?
Listen, you're not pissing
in somebody's pool, are you?
Yeah, and I'm fresh out of chlorine.
Just as this storm starts breaking,
the satellite feed up
and drops the other shoe on us.
Look at this new front moving in.
Makes its baby brother
look like chickenshit.
Well, I can sand down
all the runways and...
keep the plows going between landings,
but you got to downshift them up there,
give me time to work.
You got it.
Alright, everyone.
Let's call all our birds
and slow them down
before we get a parking lot
over our heads.
The line starts at the Mississippi
and they better start taking numbers.
Can I get you another?
No, thank you.
I only have to look at his face
for another 15 or 20 minutes.
Ladies and gentlemen,
this is the captain speaking.
I've just been informed
by Dulles Traffic Control,
that there is a weather front
moving in ahead of us.
We may be up here
a little while longer.
Thank you.
On second thought.
Al?
Hey, I'm right here, partner.
Your stiff's dossier
is coming through right now.
What can you tell me about him?
He's dead.
You needed a computer
to figure that one out?
No, no, no, no.
You don't follow me.
According to the Department of Defense,
he's been dead for two years.
What?
That's right. Sergeant
Oswald Cochrane.
American adviser in Honduras.
Killed in a helicopter accident 5-11-88.
Officer?
Read between the lines, and I'd say
it looks like a lot of black-bag stuff to me.
Yeah, I see it.
Alright, Al. Thanks a lot.
Hey, anytime.
Ok.
Say, I close in about an hour.
Maybe we can go get a drink?
Just the fax, ma'am.
Just the fax.
Hey, wait a second.
I see somebody.
I'll call you back, ok?
Hold on. Hold on.
The Ghost of Christmas Past.
Nakatomi? L.A.?
You're John McClane, right?
Who are you?
Sam Coleman. WNTW News.
Excuse me.
Hey, come on.
Give me a break.
I saw the stiff.
Word is, that was your handiwork.
No.
I only do needle-point.
Great.
National just shut down.
Totally iced.
They're gonna be sending us
their planes.
Happy, happy holidays.
The worst part, Mr. Trudeau,
was the press.
They were here anyways, crawling
all over the Esperanza story,
so they got it right on the fucking news.
You know, bloodstains and all.
Personally, I'd like to lock every
damn reporter out of the airport,
but then they'd just pull
that freedom-of-speech crap on us.
Then the A.C.L.U. would be all over us.
Murder on television.
Hell of a start for Christmas week.
What is it?
A gang thing like last time?
Only if your gangs get
their training at Fort Bragg.
Who the hell is this?
John McClane.
I'm a police officer.
In an unauthorized area.
L.A., Mr. Trudeau, don't mean shit.
Yeah? That's what I said about
my last cholesterol test.
So what's your problem,
Lieutenant McClane?
I'm sure Captain Lorenzo
has explained to you,
the minor little fracas
with the minor little thieves.
Maybe he can explain this.
All systems tapped, Colonel.
Fire it up.
H minus five minutes.
Stand by.
Alright.
We've got a body in the morgue
that seems to have died twice.
Assuming it's not a computer error,
what do we assume?
That somebody's about
to seriously fuck with this airport.
What the hell is that supposed to mean?
I mean, I know
we're dummies up here, McClane
so give us a taste of your brilliant genius.
I mean, you're talking about a hijacking,
a robbery or what?
Look, I'm not sure
Oh, he's not sure.
Well, I'm stunned.
I got to lie down.
The only people that go to this
much trouble are professionals.
Not luggage thieves and not punks.
Professional at what?
What the fuck do you think this is?
The safety patrol here?
This is the résumé
of a professional mercenary.
You got the world's biggest
drug dealer on his way here,
now what you need, a slide
rule to figure this out?
Or maybe another body in a zipper bag
before you start asking questions?
Hey pal, you're the one that gave us
that fucking body, remember that.
Yeah, I remember that.
Lorenzo,
have all your shift
commanders report in.
Now.
What? You're not buying into this?
I want them to report
anything out of the ordinary,
no matter how trivial.
You got that?
Yeah, I got it.
Oh, my God!
What?
The runways. Look.
Son of a bitch!
What the hell?
They're shutting down.
Jesus Christ.
Go to emergency lighting, now.
Emergency.
We are in a code yellow.
Backup systems won't come up.
Shunt to another terminal.
Bobby, what do you got?
Nothing. The whole network is down.
The whole network is down.
Maybe we should call the power company?
We're on the same goddamn grid,
and we're hot.
Dulles, what's going on?
I'm on approach.
Maintain position. Repeat.
What's going on down there?
Roger. We're on it. We're on it.
Western, we're unable right now.
Please delay.
Fuji 604,
execute published missed
approach procedure and hold.
T.W.A. 23, unable to clear you
for approach at this time.
Climb to and maintain
one zero thousand.
I've checked all systems.
It ain't happening!
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
What's it look like?
Approach control it's gone.
Jesus.
Instrument landing system is down.
Confirmed. I.L.S. is dead.
Every goddamn system's dead,
and NMAC monitors are down.
Attention all controllers. Attention.
We have a code-red alert.
Every aircraft approaching our sector
who are not already
in our landing pattern
gets diverted to their
alternate airport now.
Everyone already on approach
or inside our pattern
holds at the outer markers.
Stack them, pack them
and rack them.
Move.
Get someone on it!
Alright. Not a word
of this leaves this room.
There must be 15,000 people
in this airport,
and we don't need panic on our hands.
We just bought ourselves
maybe two hours.
After that, those planes low on fuel
aren't gonna be circling.
They're gonna be dropping
on the White House lawn.
McClane,
this what you expected?
No.
This is just the beginning.
F.A.A. hotline.
How could they know already?
They can't.
Maybe it's the boys
that pulled all your plugs.
Put it on speaker.
Attention, Dulles Tower.
Attention.
They say that blind men
become very attentive
by way of compensation.
Now that you're both blind and deaf.
I think I've got your attention.
I'm aware your recorders are active,
so I'll be quick.
You can play me back later
to your heart's content.
How did you get on this line?
Who is this?
Who I am is unimportant.
What I want...
Well, if you don't want those planes
to start splashing into the Potomac
as they run out of fuel,
what I want is very important.
A plane will be landing
at this airport in 58 minutes.
It is FM-1, Foreign Military One.
Now, I'm sure you gentlemen
are well aware of the unique
nature of this flight,
Esperanza?
And the importance of its cargo.
This plane will not be met by anyone.
It will land on a runway of my designation,
where it will remain isolated
and unapproached.
That will conclude my interest
in this aircraft and your responsibility for it.
At the same time,
I want a 747 cargo conversion,
fully fueled,
and placed at my disposal.
You have two more minutes to advise
your inbound aircraft
to hold at their outer radio marker.
After that, you will be able
to receive only.
Any attempt to restore
your systems will be met
by severe penalties.
He's bluffing.
Damn it, you can't do this.
I am doing this.
Ok, you guys, listen up.
I need you to punch up a code 15.
I got an idea, and I need your help.
If Esperanza gets on that plane
and makes it to a country,
that has no extradition treaties,
we're fucked.
They're talking to us on
our own goddamn system.
They got to be close.
I'll have my men tear this airport apart.
Just in the nick of time?
Hey McClane,
I got a first-class unit here,
SWAT team and all.
We don't need any
Monday-morning quarterbacks.
Fuck Monday morning.
My wife's on one of the goddamn planes
these guys are fucking with.
That puts me on the playing field.
And if you'd have moved your fat ass,
when I told you to we would
not be hip deep in shit right now.
That's it. Security. You're out of here.
Mr. Trudeau!
Mr. Trudeau, do I have to remind you
about F.A.A. regulations,
regarding unauthorized personnel
in the control tower?
All we have to do is find
a way to transmit.
Yeah, right.
Somebody wanna run down
to Radio Shack and get a transmitter?
We already have one.
The new terminal wing they're
building 20 airlines when it's done,
all with their own
reservation computers,
all tied in to a nice big antenna array.
Alright, better see Mr. McClane out.
Take him out of here
Get your fucking hands off me!
You got no business being up here.
I'm telling you guys.
Everything we need is over
by the annex sky-walk,
just sitting there,
waiting to go on line.
The annex sky-walk?
Goddamn it, Trudeau.
You're dealing with pros here.
You can't fuck with these people!
Listen to me!
Sam Coleman, WNTW news.
Mr. Trudeau, there are a lot of
rumors flying around here today.
No way. No way, lady.
Hell, no. No. You...
This is off limits, Coleman.
You know that.
Get them out of here.
Out of here.
Anything you can think of,
they'll think of too!
What's the hell!
Get your fucking hands off me.
For shit's sake,
just get them both out of here!
Lobby Security, come in.
Tomlinson here.
This is Captain Lorenzo here,
with two unauthorized personnel
in the fucking tower.
Now, would you get your
thumb out of your ass,
get them out of the elevator
or you're gonna find a goddamn
pink slip in your Christmas stocking.
10-4.
Let's go.
Goddamn!
Anything who can think of?
Can't fuck with what guy?
Shit. Hang on over there.
What for?
Just hang on.
Big drug dealer on his way to prison,
gunfight at airport,
every controller in the coffee shop
getting beeped and hauling ass
and you rocking the boat.
Connection? Come on, McClane.
Just a few words.
Ok, just a few words.
Fuck off.
Thanks, but I already
got that from Colonel Stuart.
Stuart?
The guy that got canned by Congress.
That's who he was.
Who he who?
What? Hey just...
It's ok.
I've done this before.
Hey.
Hi.
Where's the other one?
Claustrophobic, I guess.
It's a VHF system, but the planes
are so close it doesn't matter.
I can rig our frequency in 30 minutes,
wire in a crossover, and we're hot.
Even the planes would not
know the difference.
Get what you need.
Borrow. Steal. Kill.
I want my SWAT team
to go with him as cover.
Whatever we can think of,
they can think of too.
Oh, man.
I can't fucking believe this.
Another basement.
Another elevator.
How can the same shit happen
to the same guy twice?
Who are you?
I'm Marvin.
Marvin. Marv... I'm...
I thought you was trying
to steal my records, that's all.
I'm just the janitor.
This is Dulles Approach
to all aircraft holding at Potomac VORTAC.
We are experiencing
some technical problems here.
The weather conditions,
which have been deteriorating all day,
have now been complicated by,
by an unforeseen human factor.
This has affected all
of our electronic equipment,
and their redundant backups as well.
As a result, our nav
and approach systems are down and...
we expect to lose voice
in another minute.
We want you to continue holding
at the outer marker as directed
and wait for further instructions.
As soon as we're back on line we'll
expedite your landings
on a fuel-emergency basis.
Good luck.
God bless.
Alright. Change the boards.
Ok, stand back.
The sky-walk annex.
No, goddamn it. The annex sky-walk.
Listen to me. The annex sky-walk.
It's the last thing I heard before
they kicked me out there.
Well, let me see here now.
Well, this must be it right there.
See?
That's the raised platform,
and there is the new terminal.
There's your sky-walk.
Goddamn bottleneck.
Nice place for an ambush.
What's the fastest way you can
get me out to that spot?
This kind of thing wasn't
in my job description.
Don't worry, Mr. Barnes.
We'll watch your back.
Yeah? Who watches yours?
Main ventilation duct.
And bingo.
Just once.
I'd like a regular, normal Christmas.
Eggnog,
a fucking Christmas tree
a little turkey.
But no,
I got to crawl around in
this motherfucking tin can.
We're in the annex sky-walk.
I can see the array.
I'll give you a call for a protocol test
as soon as it's hot.
That's all for now.
Sergeant, we may need
some more equipment.
I'd like to send one
of your guys back for it.
Right, sir. You got it.
What the hell?
What the hell's going on?
Hey!
Put that back on!
Hey asshole,
what do I look like to you?
A sitting duck.
Take him!
Shit!
Damn it.
I hate it when I'm right.
Look out!
Get down!
Keep your head down!
You son of a bitch!
Stay down!
Fuck!
Motherfucker!
Come on.
Fucking son of a bitch!
Shit.
Fuck.
I'm gonna kick your fucking ass.
Geez.
You alright?
Yeah. Yeah.
But the antenna array,
I got to get to it and set it up.
Get down!
Goddamn.
Bait.
Jerk us off
make Lorenzo sacrifice his best men.
Make you waste your time,
time we don't have.
I think you're closer than 50 yards.
So's that airplane.
Practically.
Yeah.
There's quite a few of them out there.
It looks like a regular traffic jam.
There's nothing regular about it.
See? You're intrigued.
That's my gift, Mrs. McClane.
I notice things,
things other people would not see.
That's how I make people curious.
Don't you mean nauseous?
Look. The people have a right to know
everything about everybody.
You got in the way of that.
Listen buster,
you endangered my children,
and you didn't do it for anything
as noble as the people.
The only time you even see the people
is when you look down to see
what it is you're stepping.
Me? Yeah, I'll live
but Lorenzo's SWAT team is dead,
and the antenna array is gone.
Didn't you see it?
I'm tired of looking for a new miracle.
Just hold a minute.
No, I'll be right back.
Just hold for a second.
Something's going on here.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Just hold on for a minute.
I say again, Annex Team,
give us a sit rep.
Annex Team, come in.
Do you copy?
It's got some kind of scramble on it.
Can you do anything with it?
No.
This scramble mode must
activate on this code panel.
Even if we scan their frequency,
we can't listen in.
These guys are pros.
So you break the code.
I wanna hear what these bastards
are saying to each other.
This is a 10-digit control panel,
six-digit readout.
Hell, that could be
a million combinations.
Next time you kill one of these guys,
get him to enter the code first.
Sir,
we just monitored a call
from their chief engineer.
Our people took out
their SWAT team completely.
You were right.
They went for the antenna array.
We're right on schedule.
Losing our own team
wasn't part of the plan.
Attention, Dulles Tower.
Attention, Dulles Control Tower.
Mr. Trudeau, I know you're listening.
Unfortunately, you're not obeying.
Try me face-to-face, and we'll see.
You were warned not to try
to restore your systems.
You've wasted lives and precious time
on a futile and obvious target.
Now you're gonna pay the penalty.
I got five dead officers down here,
Colonel Stuart.
Isn't that penalty enough?
McClane, you keep out of this.
You've been nothing but a pain...
Oh, McClane.
John McClane.
The policeman hero who saved
the Nakatomi hostages.
I read about you in People magazine.
You seemed out of your league
on Night-line, I thought.
Hey, Colonel, blow me.
How much drug money
is Esperanza paying you to turn traitor?
I think Cardinal Richelieu said it best.
Treason is merely a matter of dates.
This country's got to learn
that it can't keep cutting the legs off
of men like General Esperanza,
men who have the guts to stand up
against communist aggression.
And lesson one starts
with killing policemen?
What's lesson two, the neutron bomb?
No. I think we can find
something in between.
Watch this.
Give me a flight number,
one that's low on fuel.
Windsor 114.
Transatlantic from London.
Fuel tank's dry as a martini.
Activate the I.L.S. landing system,
but recalibrate sea level
minus 200 feet.
Oh, Jesus!
They've reset ground level minus 200 feet.
Windsor Flight 114.
This is Dulles Approach.
Do you copy?
Dulles Approach, this is Windsor 114.
Where the devil have you been?
Windsor 114. Dulles Approach.
We've been right here
all along, old buddy.
Our systems only came back
on line just this very second.
Windsor 114 you are cleared
for I.L.S. approach,
runway two-niner.
Contact Dulles Tower frequency
at the outer marker.
Jesus Christ!
He's gonna crash the fucking plane!
Roger, approach and about time.
I've got 230 people up here
flying on petrol fumes.
Roger, 114. Understand.
Calibrate Dulles altimeter
Oh, Jesus.
Setting 2-9
They'll fly right into the concrete.
9-2.
Son of a bitch!
Why are they listening to him?
It's our frequency why should not they?
Dulles, this is Windsor 114.
Barnes!
This is Dulles Tower.
We have radar contact.
Give me your coat!
What are you gonna do?
Whatever I can.
Ladies and gentlemen,
as you've probably noticed
we've started our descent.
We're sorry for the inconvenience
but we'll all be on the ground
in a few minutes.
Thank you.
Please keep your seat belts on.
Oh, not to worry, we've made
arrangements for your next flight,
so you won't miss it, ok?
Thank you.
In your seat, please.
Come on. In your seat.
Oh, hey.
We're just like British Rail, love.
We may be late, but we get you there.
Don't worry.
Good luck, McClane!
Dulles, this is Windsor 114,
inside the outer marker.
Roger, 114.
This is Dulles Tower.
We have radar contact
and show you on I.L.S.
You're in the glide path,
and you're looking good.
There's somebody out there!
It's McClane.
Christ.
Approach flaps.
Approach speed, 140.
130.
Altitude 1,000 feet.
800, guys!
You're only at 800 feet!
Fire and Rescue,
this is Cummings.
Roll everything out
to runway two-niner!
Ref-speed plus 20.
600 feet.
Looking good, Windsor.
Now watch it.
30-knot crosswinds
and the runway is icy.
Attaboy. We've got you.
We've got you.
No!
Pull up!
Jesus!
We're gonna die!
We've got you.
No.
God.
Motherfucker.
That concludes our object lesson
for this evening.
If the 747 we requested
is ready on time
and General Esperanza's plane
arrives unmolested
further lessons can be avoided.
Out.
God.
Come on, you guys!
Hurry! Hurry!
We need a truck over there!
We got no sign of survivors down here!
It's a goddamn nightmare!
Barnes!
We've got to warn those planes there is a lunatic
down here who likes to pretend he's the tower.
Get up to the cabin.
Get me on the air.
How?
You figure it out!
Here's the manifest.
McClane, I know how you must feel.
I wanted to help those people tonight.
I was pretty goddamn useless.
We called the government for help.
They're...
gonna send in a special army unit
a counter-terrorist team.
Your wife's plane?
Well, they're still broadcasting
even though we can't answer.
They're gonna run out
of fuel in 90 minutes.
Listen, Dick.
That is your name...
Dick.
If you're going to continue
to get this close,
do you think you might consider
switching aftershaves?
Anything else?
Stronger mouth wash might be nice.
Well Colonel,
they've done everything
we've anticipated...
so far.
But still there has been
no official word from authorities.
Meanwhile, despite the fact that only one
runway has been closed due to the tragedy,
several dozen airliners are
visible from where I stand,
endlessly circling the field.
Other reports say that there was
trouble in the tower before the crash
and that that may have
even contributed to it.
One thing is certain,
with weather
conditions worsening
the problem here and in the sky above us
will continue to grow.
I'm Samantha Coleman
at Dulles International Airport.
Victor. Victor. Victor.
Yeah, what's up?
Did you pack the radio mikes
from the shoot
or did you put them in your carry-on?
Are you crazy?
I would not let those assholes check them in.
I love you.
Give me one of the receivers.
Can you tune in to the cockpit frequency?
Yeah. Why?
I wanna hear what's going on.
Should be right here on our band.
Nothing.
You just told me it would work.
Is it working or not?
It is working, but it's...
All I'm getting is some
kind of airport beacon.
It's weird.
It's like the tower isn't there.
Stay on it.
Let me know when there is
something there.
Ok.
Major Grant. We're Blue Light.
Rollins, Department of Justice.
Trudeau, chief of air operations.
Lorenzo, terminal police.
You want something, you got it.
This is it?
One fucking platoon?
One crisis, one platoon.
Who are you? John McClane.
McClane, you showed
some balls out there, man.
Yeah.
Now show some good sense.
Let the pros handle this.
Well, it looks like the pros
are on the wrong team tonight.
Isn't Colonel Stuart one of your men?
No, not anymore he's not.
Now we're here to take
Colonel Stuart down.
And we will take him down.
You see, I served with him.
I taught him everything he knows.
Well, maybe he's learned
a few more things since then.
Let's hustle!
Command post will be set up
in the airport police station.
I want to be tied in to the tower
in 15 minutes.
Alright, let's do it!
Hey, Trudeau.
Things just get better or worse?
Lights big, portable lights.
We set up the field,
and then we...
Wait for those lunatics
to shoot them out?
And where do we get those big,
portable lights borrow them from Batman?
What about the air phone idea?
There's 18 planes up there.
Only five of them have those phones.
We got through to three.
We're still trying on the others.
That leaves 13 accidents
waiting to happen.
Are they still bucking headwinds?
I just checked the weather.
Headwinds are slamming
everybody over the outer marker.
The planes with enough fuel
have already been shunted to Atlanta,
Memphis and Nashville.
Outer marker.
Damn!
The outer marker!
It's a beacon, right?
A radio beacon that sends out
this beep, beep, beep
so they know they're over it, right?
So?
So who says that radio signal
has to just beep?
Right. We switch the frequency,
from the tower over
to the one in the beacon.
We pump up the wattage.
And we can talk to our planes and those
bastards who did this will never know!
Traced the signal.
Found it in the luggage area.
They've been tapped
into your tower chatter all night.
Punks stealing luggage, Carmine?
How you doing, Telford?
No good.
I called Langley.
They're rigging a portable decoder.
It'll be here in two hours.
My wife doesn't have two hours.
I was only transferred
to Grant's team yesterday.
The regular guy got appendicitis.
The word is nobody's better
at this than Major Grant.
Attention!
Except maybe Colonel Stuart.
I want to hear about the plane
those bastards asked for.
Then I'll fill you in on my orders.
Pilots' briefing room. Now.
Keep working.
Albertson!
Sir!
With me.
Yes, sir!
No civilians.
What the fuck?
What is it?
The outer marker beeper.
It isn't beeping.
It's talking.
Attention all aircraft
in Dulles landing pattern.
This is Chief Engineer Leslie Barnes.
I have been authorized
to brief you in full.
At this time, this is the only
channel available to us.
Here is the situation.
Approximately two hours ago,
Wait till you get a load of this.
Do not accept any instructions
claiming to be from our tower
unless you hear your own
flight recorder access code.
The terrorists have got all our systems
Holy shit!
And now have control of everything
Get this on tape.
Except this channel.
This channel is secure,
Give us a second here, please.
But your own transmissions are not.
Do not repeat,
do not attempt to reply on your own
frequencies to this broadcast.
These people have already caused one
crash by impersonating our tower.
Jesus.
Repeat.
The terrorists have cut off
the two systems
that can allow you to land
field lights for a visual landing,
and the I.L.S. for an instrument.
A special U.S. Army unit
is already here
and preparing to take out the terrorists.
My God.
Don't accept any instructions
Yo, Marvin.
Hey, you interested in a nice coat?
No. It never looked good on me anyway.
Come here.
Listen, you got to get me
up to the pilots' briefing room.
They're having a little soiree.
I got to hear what they're saying
even if I got to put a fucking glass to the door.
Which one of these maps gets me in there?
Don't touch it!
Find the map, Marvin.
I'll find it. You'll mess up my
whole damn filing system here.
Let's see. Pilots' briefing room.
I think that's in the main terminal.
So would that be under,
P for pilots' briefing room?
Now, Marvin.
Or maybe it would be under M,
for miscellaneous.
Oh, shit!
This is Garber.
Request permission to reduce
sentry duty to 30-minute rotation.
My men are getting cold.
They're getting antsy. Over.
This is Colonel Stuart.
Garber, please have the men not on
watch assemble for a briefing. Over.
Roger, Colonel.
Over and out.
What's the matter?
Gentlemen,
tonight the pattern ends.
The dominoes will fall no more,
and the ramparts will remain upright.
Sir, General Esperanza's plane
just came on the scope.
Tracking.
Attention, Dulles Tower.
We will be lighting up a runway.
Do not, repeat,
do not attempt to land any planes.
Remember, we're monitoring you.
What do we do?
Obey.
Dulles Tower to Foxtrot Michael One.
This is Foxtrot Michael One, Dulles.
We read you. Over.
Foxtrot Michael One,
you are to come in on runway
1-5, repeat, 1-5.
I found it on the floor, by the coat,
next to the luggage belt.
What the hell you so excited about that for?
The code's still punched into this one.
You like it?
How about you give me 20 bucks for it?
How about I let you live?
Man knows how to bargain.
This is contrary to our instructions.
We are to land at runway 1-0.
Where we are to be met
by representatives of your Justice...
Captain,
please tell the tower
you will proceed as ordered.
Roger, Dulles.
Proceeding to runway 1-5.
Foxtrot Michael One, come in, please.
What are you going to do now?
You going to shoot me?
So who will fly the plane?
Don't worry about it.
It's not your problem.
Michael One, do you copy?
Foxtrot Michael One, come in, please.
Eagle Nest.
This is Falcon. Mayday.
This is Falcon. Mayday!
Go ahead, Falcon.
I've lost cabin pressure.
Near zero visibility.
I must drop out of this weather
and land now,
on the first accessible runway.
Repeat.
I've lost cabin pressure.
Near zero visibility.
I must drop out of the storm.
I can land,
but I must land now
on the first outgoing runway.
Repeat.
I cannot circle around to runway 1-5.
I'll make you a deal, Marvin.
You show me a shortcut
out to those runways
and I'll get you a liner for that coat.
Repeat. I cannot circle around
to runway 1-5.
Shit.
Stand by, Falcon.
Here, sir.
He's coming in from the ocean, sir.
A bullet has damaged my instruments.
I'm not sure of my bearing
and I must make
a visual landing immediately.
Do you copy, Eagle Nest?
Roger, Falcon.
That would be 2-5 right.
What?
Repeat, 2-5 right.
Roger.
Make up your fucking mind!
Repeat.
Runway 2-5 right.
Oh, we are just up to our ass
in terrorists again, John.
Affirmative. 2-5 right. Over.
2-5 right.
I got to quit smoking cigarettes.
Thank you for telling me, Eagle Nest.
But if you could show it to me as well,
I would be grateful.
I see the lights.
They are directly in front of me.
Gracias, compadre.
Reducing airspeed.
Approaching runway.
Wish me luck.
Roger, Falcon.
We copy.
We'll have you in five minutes.
That's right, asshole.
I see your lights.
E.T.A. 90 seconds.
Come to papa, scumbag.
Oh, shit!
Freedom.
Not yet.
You're supposed to stay in your seat
until the plane reaches the terminal.
No frequent-flyer mileage for you.
Who are you?
A cop.
A cop?
Yeah, one of the good guys.
You see you're one of the bad guys.
And now that I got your sorry ass,
I'm gonna trade it for my wife.
Sit down!
I'm going in!
I got you covered.
Where'd he go?
In there.
I don't believe this 2 months of planning,
and you can't anticipate one
pendejo nfa cop.
Come on, General.
Where the hell is Colonel Stuart?
General!
I am alright.
He said he was a policeman.
I thought you had this place secured.
He went in the cockpit.
He's going to hell!
McClane!
I assume it's you, McClane.
You're quite a little soldier.
You can consider this a military funeral!
How many grenades we got?
Three each!
Use them!
Oh, fuck.
Shit
Go!
Oh, shit!
You lucky fuck.
Fire trucks, sir.
Fall back to the church.
Now!
Where's the fucking door?
You know they're getting a little
nervous back there.
In fact, so am I.
We're right over Washington.
See if you can get any TV.
That'll settle them down.
Works for me.
Writing your acceptance speech
for the Video Sleaze Awards?
Try Pulitzer.
Ladies and gentlemen
while waiting to land, our cabin attendants
are turning on local Washington broadcasting.
The sound is on channel three.
Ok.
Ok. Ok.
Please sir, we may land at any moment.
If you'll take your seat.
I'm gonna be sick.
Excuse me. I'm gonna be sick.
Sir, the seat belt light is on.
Moron.
WZDC.
Yes, this is Richard Thornberg.
Put me through to Ruben
in the newsroom.
He's about to go live.
I know he's about to go on.
That's why I need him.
You'll have to hold on.
Put me through, Celia,
or start typing your résumé.
Esperanza's down.
But he's hurt.
He took a round in his shoulder.
Plus I got one more of their guys.
That's six they lost altogether.
Well maybe if we knew how many
they had to start with, we could get excited.
But if they got 50 guys,
it's a little early to break
out the champagne!
We appreciate your effort, McClane, but
we don't need a loose cannon on this deck!
What if they decide
to crash another plane
in retaliation for your little stunt?
They can't do that anymore, right, Barnes?
Besides, if I grabbed
Esperanza, this would all be over by now.
Well, maybe they're just
a little bit more creative than you think!
Well, at least I'm thinking, goddamn it!
Listen, you wise-ass,
we're here to jerk off that cocksucker
until he tries to take off, period!
Now you're the wrong guy
in the wrong place at the wrong time!
The story of my life.
Major,
Pentagon Situation Room, sir!
Pentagon. I'll take it in here.
Thank you, Telford.
You men come with me.
McClane.
Yeah, Barnes.
You said those guys showed
up out there right away?
Yeah.
So. So that must mean
they're on the field or close.
And I think I know where.
Come here.
Let me show you something.
These are the old plans when the longer
runways went in. That's, that's 12 years ago.
Looks like they've done
some modifications on-site,
moved TRACON phones, I.L.S.,
all the underground stuff,
so they could handle drainage.
If I'm right,
all of it would run right
along the airport property
and go right past this neighborhood.
We should have been
on the ground two hours ago!
I understand,
but if you just relax a little.
Come on, lady.
Who you trying to kid?
It's hopeless.
Somebody ought to get their ass
kicked for this mess. That's for sure.
Well unfortunately there really isn't anyone
we can blame for the weather.
Oh, yeah?
What about that porker Willard Scott?
I should have taken the bus.
At least they can pull over
for food and gas.
Excuse me.
Yes?
I was just wondering.
This flight originally was supposed
to be five and a half hours, right?
Do we have enough fuel
to keep circling like this?
Oh, of course.
They anticipate little problems like this.
Barnes, we looked at 12 fucking houses,
and we're nowhere.
This is our last possibility.
Over here there is an old church.
Let's go.
Wait.
There's the church over there.
Could be a sentry.
And he could just be out for a walk.
Then why is he going over
his own footsteps?
Come on.
Alright.
Just stay here and get
ready to call the marines.
I thought they were the army.
Who gives a fuck? Just be ready.
Oh, shit.
Not now.
Lorenzo, it's Barnes.
Barnes, where the hell did you go?
Where's McClane?
He's with me.
We're at the Highland Lake Community
Church on the west side of the airport.
You're where?
Goddamn it!
You crazy idiot, why didn't...
This must be their base of operations.
Shut up and get your ass over here!
Move it!
Code red! Sit rep.
We got positive I.D. on Stuart's location.
Let's move.
Yo!
Yes, sir.
Our escape plane will be ready
within 30 minutes, General.
If there are no more surprises.
Gentlemen, we have a situation here.
Over here.
Geez, McClane, you alright?
You want a medic?
McClane, what the hell you think
you're doing out there, playing John Wayne?
How would you like
to spend the night in a cell?
Lorenzo, shut the fuck up
and do something useful.
Go seal off the street.
Hey, you can't talk to me like that.
Oh, no, Carmine?
Sergeant, get this bureaucrat
out of Mr. McClane's face now.
With pleasure, sir.
Major,
the men are in position, sir.
Close up the back.
Then we go in.
Fire only on my order.
Roger that, sir.
Guess I was wrong about you.
You're not such an asshole after all.
No, you were right.
Well I'm just your kind of asshole.
Garber, sit rep!
Army Special Forces on three sides,
closing in fast around the back!
Another problem, Colonel?
No problem, General.
Gentlemen, you know what to do.
Down!
Get down! Get down!
General!
It's time.
Come on. Let's move it!
They're pulling out!
What?
Out the back!
Move it!
Albertson, take your men
around the back.
This equipment,
it could land our planes.
Don't touch anything.
There were trip wires outside.
They could have booby-trapped...
They did.
Got one here. Looks like C-4.
The motherfucker is armed.
Clear the area!
Everybody, now!
They booby-trapped all the equipment.
Seal off the building!
Shit!
Secure the area.
Post sentries. No civilians allowed.
Hey, where the fuck is McClane?
Miller, take him!
I'll cover you!
Goddamn!
So much for the element of chance.
Let's move out.
I had the bastard in my sights.
I know I did.
Oh, Jesus Christ.
Attention, Tower.
Attention, Dulles Tower.
This is Colonel Stuart.
Is our plane prepared?
It is.
It's in Hangar 11.
It's the most remote building we've got.
We're on our way.
Have a ground crew there
to confirm the condition of the plane.
Do you believe the balls
on this son of a bitch?
Colonel, you're quite capable
of confirming it yourself.
Now please, don't ask us
to gift wrap potential hostages for you.
Major Grant, isn't it?
If you remember me Colonel,
then you remember I know
the drill as well as you do.
Check out your own fucking plane.
We move out in five minutes.
Flak-jackets for everybody.
Body armor for the assault team.
Night scopes for the snipers.
We will take them in the hangar,
and I will pull that detonator
out of Stuart's dead fucking hand myself.
Lorenzo,
take all your men back to the airport. Sir.
Seal off every exit
in case any of them tries to slip past us,
to break out onto the ground.
You got it.
Alright, here we go.
Dick, this is nuts. Every station
in town has people at the airport
and none has heard
a whisper of this shit you're running!
Well, none of them is me.
You want proof? Try this.
Repeat.
Terrorists have murdered civilians
and cut off the two systems
that can allow you to land.
A special U.S. Army unit is already here
and preparing to take out the terrorists.
Jesus Christ.
I want you to go live now.
Key me in from the files
a publicity shot, whatever.
Connie's got one and a map.
Steal one from weather.
We're on it. We're on it.
We're cutting in five minutes!
Tell the affiliates if they want in,
they got three minutes to shout.
Let's do this.
Network, here I come.
Hey Telford, what was your chickenshit
outfit doing while we were taking Grenada?
Grenada,
five minutes of firefight,
five weeks of surfing.
I wish I was with you guys for that.
Yeah.
Me too, kid.
Really, sir?
Sure.
Then we would not have to do this.
Eagle Nest, this is Hatchling.
On schedule
and in position.
Roger, Hatchling.
We are secure here.
You have a green light.
I repeat,
a green light.
Jesus Officer,
where'd you come from, Pearl Harbor?
Alright, let's clear it out, please.
Stand by.
Five, four, three
This is a special bulletin from WZDC News.
There was a plane crash
earlier this evening at Dulles,
where other aircraft continue to circle,
with no explanation from airport
or F.A.A. officials.
Quiet!
And now, with an exclusive WZDC report
here's Dick Thornberg reporting
from the skies over Washington.
Can you turn it up?
I'm one of the thousand people who
has been circling our nation's capital
under the assumption
that whatever problem
was going on far below
was a normal one.
But the truth is far from normal.
The truth is terrifying.
Look out!
Lady, look out!
Look out! Look out!
Get out of the way!
Move!
Get out of the way, lady!
Go! Go! Hey!
Hey! Look out!
This is a recording of a conversation,
between Dulles Tower
and the captive aircraft overhead.
Hey! Get out of the way!
Scary!
Lorenzo!
McClane, are you out of your fucking mind?
The Blue Light Team, where are they?
Stuart's got explosives on the equipment
in the church rigged with a remote.
Where's Grant?
Grant's boys are gonna kill that
son of a bitch and get it problems.
They're gonna do, they're gonna
get on the same goddanm plane
with him and take off with him!
Get the fuck out of here!
When the army canned Stuart,
he must have loaded
that unit with his own men!
Are you nuts? That firefight out...
That firefight Sideshow to jerk us off,
buy them some time.
McClane, you are completely
around the fucking bend.
You know that and you know
what else you're under arrest.
You motherfucker!
Here!
These are the bullets
they used out there tonight!
Blanks!
Jesus Christ.
This is Chief Lorenzo.
I want every officer recalled
and assembled in body
armor and full weaponry
in the motor pool in five minutes.
It's time to kick ass.
Just like lwo Jima!
Since then, this reporter
has learned that the terrorists
have virtual control of the entire airport.
A fact that the authorities have repressed.
The terrorists promise more bloodshed
unless their demands are met.
And now that the special army commandos
have arrived at the airport,
the likelihood of a full-scale
and deadly battle is dangerously close.
That stupid, arrogant son of a bitch.
It's all over the airport.
And unfortunately they may not be the last.
The horrifying fact is that no one is safe,
either in the planes above Dulles
or in the terminal below.
The threat of a new and higher
body count at the airport
hangs over the heads of everyone
and the holiday season
of peace and love has become a nightmare.
Alright, listen up all units!
I want you to converge on Hangar 11.
All sides!
This car, McClane! Get in!
When the city blue show up
with their backup,
they'll pick up the pieces!
Now, move out!
McClane, say hi to my brother Vito.
Merry Christmas.
Hi.
Shit!
Goddamn it to hell!
Move that piece of shit!
What's the matter with you?
I didn't even see you, man.
Will you move that goddamn
piece of shit out of here!
Vito, get the fuck out of the car and get your
ass in gear and help me, for Christ's sake!
Will you get move that car back right now, lady!
Right there. Right there.
Get that.
Hey!
Coleman!
Sam!
Sam Coleman!
Hey, Coleman!
Hi!
Coleman!
But at least the truth,
is not among the hostages,
because I,
Richard Thornberg,
just happened to be here,
to put his life...
and talent,
on the line for humanity
and country.
And if this should be my final broadcast
Amen to that,
Dick.
Dick?
We're live, Dick.
Where are you now?
Dick?
Truck lights approaching, sir.
They're here,
right on schedule.
The hangar door, open it.
Clockwork.
Geez, you give me this story,
and I'll have your baby.
Not the kind of ride I'm looking for.
Colonel, if I may say so,
you are some piece of work.
Thank you, Major.
You're not so bad yourself.
Congratulations on your escape, sir.
Thank you, Major.
Maybe you should save them
until we are all safe?
Sir.
My congratulations, gentlemen.
You've won a victory for our way of life
my pride, my admiration,
and a kick-ass vacation.
Now get on board.
What's the matter cowboy,
ride too rough?
I don't like to fly.
Then what are you doing here?
I don't like to lose either.
Ok!
Here we go!
I don't know about you guys, but I've seen
enough fucking snow to last me a lifetime.
They don't get much of that
in the tropics, Major.
For you, gentlemen,
we'll import it.
Shit! They left the hangar!
Right there. Right there.
Get that.
Alright, now what?
Get in front of them!
Take it down!
Block their path
so they can't get out of there!
I'm not playing chicken
with a 200-ton plane!
I'm crazy man, but I ain't that crazy.
Forget it.
Dulles, this is Northeast 140.
Request clearance on first available runway.
That's Holly's plane.
Repeat. Request emergency clearance.
I know you're not gonna answer to me,
but you Goddamn better listen!
We're down to fumes and we have to land,
and in five minutes we're coming in,
one way or another.
Goddamn it.
That's my wife's plane!
Take it fucking down!
I'm not getting in front of that plane!
Alright, how about getting over top of it?
Ladies and gentlemen,
this is the captain.
Your attention.
We have no choice,
but to attempt an emergency landing.
Please fasten your seat belts
and assume crash positions
as instructed by your cabin attendants.
Let's have the emergency checklist.
Attention all air traffic on
this frequency in Dulles area.
This is Northeast 140.
We're going to attempt
an emergency landing.
Be advised.
I don't want to die. I don't want to die.
I don't want to die.
Just buckle your seat belt.
I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
You're gonna be alright.
Lean forward now.
Thank you.
God!
Oh, God.
Thy rod and thy staff, they comfort me.
Hang on!
What are you doing?
You wanted a story, didn't you?
Nice and easy, boys.
Get me in low!
You got it!
Where are you going?
Bring me down!
You'll get yourself killed!
Come back inside!
Bring it in low!
Keep over the wing!
Lower!
John,
what the fuck are you doing
out on the wing of this plane?
Damn!
Mierda.
What?
There's something wrong.
The ailerons.
We can't take off.
Hijo de puta.
It's McClane again.
Son of a bitch!
I'll do him.
This time do it right.
You just get us in the air, General.
You're the only man who can do it.
Don't shoot.
That wing is fully fueled.
Too bad, McClane.
I kind of liked you!
Goddamn traitor!
I got enough friends!
Ok, McClane,
time for the main event!
This is for Flight 114, motherfucker!
How's it going?
Bon voyage!
Happy landings, asshole!
Yippie-kai-yay, motherfucker.
Yeah. Alright.
Fuck.
Holly!
Here's your fucking landing light!
Oh, God.
Look! Look!
Ok. I see it! I see it!
They used the fire to see!
They used the fucking fire to see!
They can all do that. Let's tell them.
They already know.
We had a visual on Northeastern's landing.
Listen.
They were following
the fire trail in as a guide.
If they can do it, so can we!
Any landing you can walk
away from is a good one.
That's great.
Jump!
I got you!
There you go. That's it.
Holly!
Come on!
We got you!
You're gonna be alright, ma'am.
Oh, God.
Oh, baby.
I thought I was never gonna
see you again.
That's what I thought about you.
I love you so much.
They told me there were
terrorists at the airport.
Yeah. I heard that too.
God, that's beautiful.
Yeah.
Yup, it sure is.
I love you so much.
Oh, John.
Why does this keep happening to us?
Let's go home.
Somebody help me, please!
Oh, honey, help me up here, please.
Asshole!
Hey, Officer! Hey!
Come on! Come on! Hey, hey!
Hey! Hop on in there!
Get your missus in!
What do you say, Marv?
I'll be damned if I'm gonna
clean up this mess!
Hey, McClane!
You get this parking ticket
in front of my airport?
Yeah.
What the hell.
It's Christmas!
Take off, Marv!
By LESAIGNEUR
Sync & corrections July 2020