What the fuck, Caleb?
Oh, wait till you see the shot I got.
You looked like you were gonna
shit a brick out sideways.
You could have taken my head off.
It wouldn't have been a clean
decapitation with these blades.
You'd just scramble
your face up real good.
Shouldn't you go see
if Jessica is feeling any better?
She'll be fine. I gave her Klonopin
so she can sleep off
whatever the fuck is wrong with her.
Girl is such a pain in the ass.
Jessica?
Hey.
How you feeling, cuz?
Since none of these other friends
of yours bothered to show up
can I take your car and escape
the hell of being stuck here
with your latest boyfriend?
Great chat.
You better wake up
in the next half hour
or I'm gonna be forced
to go drown that brainless
meat puppet's sorry ass.
"The intense horror
of my nightmare came over me.
I tried to draw back my arm,
but the hand clung on
and a most melancholy voice sobbed
'Let me in.
Let me in!'
As it spoke, I discerned, obscurely
a child's face
looking through the window.
Finding it useless to attempt
shaking the creature off
I pulled its wrist on to
the broken pane...
- Jess? Please shut up.
- And rubbed it to
and fro
till the blood ran down
and soaked the bedclothes.
Yet still it wailed...
'Let me in!'"
Jessica!
Shit... shit!
No, Jess. Jess? Jess? Jess?
Who's the brainless meat puppet now?
Caleb.
What the fuck?
Oh, my God.
What the hell happened?
Jess?
Jessica?
What the fuck? What?
No, no, no...
Caleb!
No...
No, Caleb!
Caleb!
Beth!
Beth, you in there?
Just give me five, all right?
Brandon is losing his shit.
He can't find the Strat
he won in that
arm wrestling contest last night.
It's already tuned
and racked, stage left,
like I told you
it was half an hour ago.
You feeling all right in there?
I'm fine.
Just go man your station.
I'll be back before curtains up.
You got it, boss.
Have you seen
my favorite black T-shirt?
I need it for
the Labor Day protest tomorrow.
Mom?
You're not going to any protest
on your own.
Sophie's dad's taking us.
I've told you, like,
ten times already.
Remember?
Well, did you remember
to check the bathroom hamper?
Tell Danny to turn the music down.
Mom says, "Turn the music down!"
I could've done that myself!
Kassie, you better
not have my scissors.
Don't got 'em, Mom!
It's dirty.
Well, stick it in the laundry,
and I'll do it later.
You'll forget. You always forget.
You know
where the washing machine is.
Hey, Bridget. Mom's on nights
and we're watching
all the Freddy movies in a row.
Even the shitty ones.
There aren't any shitty ones.
So, you... wanna come over and...
In your dreams.
Your boyfriends are weirdos.
You're the weirdo.
Kassie!
Big crowd in tonight, Dan?
Get out, Bridge!
I would, but...
Let me in!
Somebody get that, please!
All right, all right!
Boo!
Beth.
You bitch.
Surprise, sis.
When did you get into town?
I Uber'd straight here from LAX.
You been sleeping? You look like Mom.
Beats looking like a tampon.
You know, the downstairs buzzer
is totally busted.
I was able to walk in
right off the street.
Whole building's busted.
It's getting knocked in a month.
You're kidding me.
Nope. We're out.
Have you guys found a new place?
Not yet.
Shit, El. You and Jay
have been here forever.
Was Bangkok awesome?
Insane. Crazy,
obsessive fans over there.
Did you drink snake blood?
Hey, that's culturally insensitive.
What about monkey brain barbecue?
Oh, yeah. That's so much better, Dan.
Who's your friend, Kass?
She's called Staffanie.
Oh. Hey, Staffanie.
What's her situation?
Danny told me that
when this building used to be a bank
a teller got caught stealing
and hunged himself
and if you walk around
with coins in your pockets
his ghost hears the jingle.
And he scares you to death
so he can take all your money.
It's true.
If he comes after me
Staffanie will
scare him to death first.
Ghosts aren't real.
Have you ever seen one?
Then how do you know
they don't exist?
Because...
I only believe what I can see.
For me?
It's for badass rock chicks only.
Look, Mom. I'm a badass.
Please don't indoctrinate her
into your groupie world.
What's a groupie?
Your mom's favorite nickname for me,
even though she knows
I'm a guitar technician.
If you say so.
Hey, be nice or you don't get a gift.
Speaking of which,
check out what I got your dad.
What's going on, El?
Danny, go take my car
and get pizza with your sisters.
Sure thing, Mom.
I just can't wrap my head
around all this.
What, did he meet someone else?
No. He believes paying child support
equals co-parenting from afar.
Why didn't you tell me, El?
I would've jumped right on a plane
to help you work through this.
I called you.
Twice.
First time, when he told me
he was leaving.
Second, the night he moved out.
That was
two and half months ago, Beth.
I'm sorry, okay?
You know when I'm on the road,
I get sucked in deep
and I'm trying to make
chief tech right now.
And if I do, I'll be the first woman
in my crew to do it, so...
Please, Ellie, we need
to talk this through properly.
El...
Look, you can sleep
on the sofa tonight
but I gotta pack and move.
Hey, Bethy-boo.
It's Ellie. Just...
calling to say hi. And...
me and Jay, we...
You know what...
I don't blame you.
I hate the sound of my voice too.
What's going on with you, Beth?
I screwed up again, like I always do.
And I need you
to help me figure it out.
Again.
What happened?
Hurry up, Bridge.
You wanna carry them?
You wanna get your license?
Come on, Kass.
Earthquake!
Come on.
Go!
Stay down!
Shit.
That was intense.
I think I peed my pants.
Is it warm?
It's probably just soda.
All right. Come on.
Holy shit. Bridget, check this out.
What is it?
There's a hole.
Careful, Dan.
There could be aftershocks.
It's an old bank vault!
Danny, don't!
Dan?
Come on, Danny. Let's go!
Just hang on!
Danny!
Relax a minute, Bridge!
Danny, are you okay?
I'm fine.
Anything?
The network is totally screwed.
I'm sure they're fine, El.
Hey.
Is everyone okay? Anybody hurt?
Hey, Gabe.
The kids went to go get pizza
and I can't get through
on their cells.
Can I borrow your car
to go find them?
- How about I drive you?
- Thanks.
Let me get the keys.
Who are you?
Beth.
Ellie's sister.
Ah, yeah, yeah.
The groupie.
Let me ask you somethin'.
Can you hear her up there?
What?
Quake.
Sent her hiding in the ducts.
Here, kitty... kitty.
Let's roll.
Is that them?
Good to meet you.
You never take the elevator
after a quake.
Bridget dropped the pizza.
Oh, honey. I love you guys
so much more than pizza.
The magnitude 5.5 earthquake
hit just north
of the Puente Hills fault
less than an hour ago
jolting downtown Los Angeles
and everywhere from La Habra to...
You think it might
be worth something?
Mom could do with some extra money
right now, don't you think?
I don't think Mom wants cash
from something you stole.
It's not stolen.
It's probably been locked
in that vault forever.
Yeah, and weird shit like this
gets locked away for a reason.
Just leave it, Dan.
Fuck!
Let me see it.
It's just a nick.
Dan...
Danny, please close it.
I don't like this, Dan.
You need to put it back right now.
Mom's not letting any of us
out the front door again tonight.
First thing in the morning then.
Promise me?
You going deep sea diving?
I gotta see under before I get in.
I got stung by a jellyfish
at the beach before.
I don't like going underwater.
I don't think there's
any weird sea creatures in the tub.
Oh, my God... oh, my God.
It's a... It's a...
You okay?
I'm good, sweetie.
I hate when my tummy hurts too.
Amen.
Good afternoon, my fellow clergymen.
I am Father Marcus Littleton
the library keeper
here at Saint Patrick's Cathedral
and I welcome you all today
to the City of Angels.
You've been invited here
to witness the unveiling
of a unique artifact
that was discovered
by our overseas missionaries.
I would like to present
what I believe to be
one of the three fabled volumes
of Naturum Demento
The Book of the Dead.
My tests to date have revealed
that its bindings
are made of cured human flesh
its passages and etchings
inked in blood.
This is heresy!
Today, I seek church approval
to translate the spiritual mysteries
its pages undoubtedly hold.
Destroy it!
It's called The Book of the Dead
for a reason!
I seek to look at this book
for the good of man!
Rejected by the elders of our church
myself, Canon Damien Shanahan,
and Father Hugo Cortez
have been working
in secret to translate
The Book of the Dead's
myriad writings and glyphs.
Its pages contain
ancient rituals and incantations
the recitation of which
proclaim to allow contact
with supernatural forces
that exist beyond
the thin veneer of our known world.
It is January 24th
in the year of our Lord, 1923.
And I, Father Marcus Littleton,
shall now commence reading aloud
the first of
the spiritual resurrection passages.
Kandar.
Estrada.
Kandos.
Thrus.
Indactu.
Skeridus.
Kandar.
Dematos.
Hey!
Help!
Shut the fuck up!
It's okay. It's okay.
It's just a blackout.
Bridget?
You all right?
Yeah.
Looks like it's just us that's out.
Really?
Mom?
El, are you sleeping?
Where is she?
Mom?
El?
What's up, sis?
I had the most beautiful dream.
We were together,
sitting in a tall forest.
The wind was clean and the birds were
singing the sweetest mel... melo...
mel...
melo... me...
melodies.
It was a perfect day
and all I could think about
was how much I wanted
to cut you all open
and climb inside your bodies so that
we could stay one happy family.
It's in me.
Don't let it take my babies.
Mom!
Bridget, take her back inside.
Now!
What's wrong with her, Bridge?
Stairs. Go! Go, go, go.
Come on.
Wake up, Ellie. Come on, wake up.
Danny!
They're gone.
One minute she was fine
and the next
she was talking crazy and...
and now she's gone.
Network's still fucked.
May I pray?
She's not religious.
Wasn't.
It's just a few words.
Join me.
Eternal rest grant
unto her, O Lord...
and let perpetual light
shine upon her.
May her soul and the souls
of all the faithful departed
through the mercy of God...
What the hell happened to her face?
Rest in peace.
Looks like someone beat her up.
There's an old fire-escape ladder...
on the north side of the building.
I could try to get down that
raise the alarm,
get some help in here.
You have to go through 82.
Ah, shit.
That's unoccupied, right?
Yeah. Like most of
this condemned dump.
You got the tools?
We could just cut
right through the door.
In my truck.
You ain't gettin'
through those old doors
without something heavy-duty.
I want Dad to come home.
He will.
When we get the phones working again,
he'll come right back.
How do you know he will?
You said Mom was gonna be okay.
I thought she would be.
I'm so sorry, Kass.
I'm gonna get my shotgun,
and we're gonna blast it open.
Just give me a minute, okay?
I don't like being trapped.
Everyone is on edge enough
without guns getting fired in here.
I don't know what to do, El.
You're the one
who always has the answers.
I'm too scared
to even face your kids right now.
No matter how busy you ever got,
you always found time for me.
For everyone.
I can't believe I'm never gonna
speak to you again.
Hey, Bethy-boo. It's Ellie.
Just...
calling to say hi. And...
Beth.
Beth!
You have to help me, Beth.
You have to.
I'm burning. I'm burning alive!
El?
- Mom?
- She's alive?
She's burning up.
I'll get ice.
Mom?
Mommy's with the maggots now.
Mom, stop it!
Stop it!
It's not my fault, Bridget.
Get away from her, Bridge!
What's happening to me, sweetheart?
I don't know, Mom.
I do.
I'm free now.
Free from
all you titty-sucking parasites.
Let me kiss it better.
Who wants to rot next?
Eeny...
meeny...
miny...
You.
Ellie?
Fuck!
Grab the cabinet.
Get away from the door.
Please, we need help!
Let me in!
Hello!
Can you hear me?
Don't you think Mom looks just like
one of those pictures from that book?
Answer me, Danny.
You never should've stolen it.
This isn't my fault.
This is your fault!
- Get off me!
- Stop it!
- Get off!
- Hey!
- This is all your fault!
- Hey, hey!
Hey. Hey.
You don't turn on each other.
Ever.
I need to show you something.
What is this, Danny?
Does it hurt bad?
Bridget?
I'm okay.
Gold-haired girls
With curling tresses
Hush-a-bye, baby
Babe not mine
Mothers who nurse
With sad caresses
Hush-a-bye, baby
Babe not mine
Mom?
Beth?
I took these too.
There's this creepy priest on them,
reading passages from the book.
It's like a weird dark prayer.
And when he spoke the words...
Bridget's right.
This is all my fault.
Bridget...
And black knife bring
To cross my sorrow
Hush-a-bye, baby
Babe not mine
Oh, there you are.
Hey there, cutie-pie.
What's wrong with you, Mom?
I was just feeling sad
about me and your dad.
But he's here now.
He came home to see us.
We're getting back together.
We love each other.
Isn't that right, my darling?
And we love you too.
Open up and let us in, Kassie.
We can be a big, happy family again.
You don't look so good, Mom.
Oh.
Nothing a big old hug and kiss
from you won't fix.
Open up now
like a good girl.
That's it.
Come on, now.
Do it for Mom and Dad.
Mom!
- You okay?
- I'm sorry.
I thought Mom was better.
Open the door like you open your legs
you stinking groupie slut!
I'm not a groupie, you psycho bitch!
Beth.
Go to your room.
It'll be okay, Danny.
Staffanie will protect us. Right?
Yeah.
What are you looking at, hon?
I gotta kill the creepy-crawlies
that I got inside my tummy.
I don't like having things
inside my tummy.
Do you, Auntie Beth?
Hey.
Is this a nightmare?
It's just like a nightmare, Kass.
Is what happened to Bridget and Mom
gonna happen to us?
I'm not gonna let that happen.
I promise.
You'd be a good mom someday,
Auntie Beth.
Oh, yeah?
Yeah.
You know how to lie to kids.
I thought I should tie her up.
Just in case.
I wanna listen to that vinyl.
It's too dangerous.
- Those words...
- Yeah, well, maybe there's words
on there that can help
stop all of this.
We've got no power
to run a turntable.
I can fix that.
I listened to the first and then
he spoke the words on the second.
I guess I'll start
at the other end then.
Just in case.
It is now two nights
since I read aloud from the book.
My want to understand
and commune with the other side
could not have been more misguided.
I make this final recording
as a warning to whoever next
comes into contact
with its malignant pages.
Naturum Demento cannot be destroyed.
When you find it,
bury it deep in our secret vault
for the words I uttered
have unleashed a demonic entity
beyond my darkest nightmare.
Is Bridget gonna come back like Mom?
I don't know, Kass.
The demon possessed Cortez first,
rotting him from the inside out.
With the might of our Lord's words
we tried to drive out the foul entity
but it mocked our prayers
and took Shanahan under its control.
Fellow priests came to our aid
but the possession
quickly spread amongst them
without rhyme nor reason.
This evil is not governed
by the rules of man.
No, it takes its pleasure in creating
terror through total chaos.
Desperate to end this curse
I tried to kill
what were once my brothers.
I led them to the woodshed
and set it ablaze.
But they danced in its flame
and reveled in its burn.
Mr. Fonda's kitty
hides up there sometimes.
I don't think it's a cat.
I buried their squirming
spitting corpses
in consecrated earth.
But they arose again
rotting and rage-filled.
Careful, Danny.
After hiding in the cellar
for a night
I knew only one choice remained.
Complete bodily dismemberment.
Told you, you should've
put the book back, Danny.
I chopped, and I hacked
and I...
I failed.
I can hear them outside the doors
now, begging for me.
It is only a matter of time
before I am taken too.
Nothing can stop this demonic force.
Even its final remnants
will come after you.
You must run.
All you can do...
Is run!
This horror will not stop
until innocence is destroyed.
Until evil...
be thy name.
Danny...
I'm sorry, Kass.
I will swallow your soul.
Two souls?
Please. El...
Ellie waits in hell for you
and your unborn bastard baby.
No.
Auntie Beth!
Are you hurt?
Are you gonna be a mom?
Yes.
And I'm getting us out of here.
How?
Fire escape. Let's go.
Don't look back there.
Get back. Cover your ears.
Bethy-boo!
She's trying to take your mommy
away from you, Kassie.
I know you're not my mom anymore.
Don't take me from them.
You have no idea what it's like
to bring a child into
this world, Beth.
That's my gun, you thieving cunt.
Auntie Beth!
Everybody here dies by dawn, Beth.
Run!
Dead by dawn!
Here.
No way out!
- Auntie Beth!
- Come here!
Kassie. Kassie.
Kassie. Kassie. Kassie.
Am I dead?
Come on. Get in.
Kass, where's the beeper?
Come on. Come on.
It's coming.
Get under!
Kassie!
All I want is
your little head, baby girl.
Come get some.
Turn it on, Kass!
Please.
Help me, Bethy-boo.
Only my sister gets to call me that.
You know,
you really do look like Mom.
And you're gonna
fail miserably just like her.
You stinking, horrible groupie cunt!
There's been no cell signal
until, like, five minutes ago
and the thunder kept me awake, so
I got basically less than zero sleep.
Anyway, all my early morning
moans aside
we are still gonna have
such a fab weekend at the lake.
Caleb's dad's cabin is so awesome
and you're gonna absolutely
love his friends.
I'm sure one of them
will be perfect for you.
I don't mean to be
a downer or anything
but I was actually thinking
of taking a rain check
on this whole trip thing.
Not a chance.
I'm picking you up in 15.
Bye!