Master Yu... I beat Yim Chun-loi
I really did... I am not lying
Take me as your disciple
Get up
I saw it... sit down
lp Man, you are not afraid of hardship
You have the drive, you are smart
I'll be pleased to have you as my disciple
But you still have a test to pass
Master Yu, this is underhanded
You are right
What's the test?
I am going to teach you three moves
You have to use them to cut off a queue
A queue?
Watch carefully
That's it?
That's it
Oh no
Give way...
Brother Ching-shan
You are going to a western country
Don't forget to write me
I'll let you know
Fu Hung-mo can't be more wrong
lp Man, what Fu Hung-mo told you
was not true
Britain has been the most powerful
country in the past 200 years
I am going there to find out
the meaning of revolution
I'll find out the meaning of
queue cutting
Brother Ching-shan
Truth will tell
What Fu Jing-wan said was all nonsense
Brother Ching-shan, don't you forget me
Don't you forget Sangyuan
Brother Ching-shan, bon voyage
Don't forget to write me
You have to write me... Brother Ching-shan
Who sent you here?
Why are you trying me out?
Tell me or you are dead!
Master Chan, you picked up
Wing Chun from Mr Tsan?
Mentor Yu
The queue, look
Really Cashier Wah's queue?
You cut it?
Yes, I cut it
Or he cut it himself?
You sure are smart, how did you know?
What happened?
I worked hard on the three moves
you taught me
I first used this move
Then this
I was this close to getting his queue, but...
You can't get my queue, just go back
I may not be able to cut it today
But I will if I come every day for a year
Please, what a pest you are
Alright, you win
You satisfied now?
Take it back to Master Yu
Mentor, take me as your disciple
I won't take you as my disciple
But I will teach you martial arts
Get up
No obeisance as a disciple
Mentor, why?
You know what Wing Chun is?
Wing Chun?
Boss Chan
Excuse me
What now?
What are you doing?
What's wrong with you?
Young Master...
Thank you, I have to run
Hey... your ticket
Sorry
Halt
Chun-loi, I am going to Canton
Don't get in my way
lp Man, don't you give me
a hard time again
What are you doing?
I've been given many a slapping
and made to kneel because of you
You mean it? We are brother
I am not your brother
Yim Chun-loi, you can't fight me
I've gotta get on board
lp Man... one day, you'll be the one
pushed into the water
Mentor, it's the Canton Martial
Arts Convention
How can you not take me with you?
How many times have I told you?
I'd teach you martial arts
I have not taken you in as my disciple
Don't call me mentor
Old habits die hard
I am sorry
Mentor, it's said martial arts practitioners
of the South will all attend the convention
Tip me off
The championship is yours to lose
Or is it within your reach?
I'm going there to watch and learn
not to fight
Mentor, with your cultivation
If you don't take part in the convention
the convention will be but a sham
There's always someone out there
who's better
Bear it in mind
A true martial arts adept doesn't
make his name in the ring
Then by what?
Generosity of the heart
Halt...
Bravo...
A sound physique, a strong country
Don't run...
Halt...
Here he is...
General Wu, you are going to the frontline
What are the prospects ahead?
Usurpers are running amuck
The revolution may end in vain
It really hurts us to see it
I am going to the frontline
There are only two possible outcomes
Flowers for sale... fresh flowers for sale...
Either the revolution prevails in the end
Or I'll die for the revolution
Bravo...
Mentor, Canton really is different
Help...
Who gave you permission to sell here?
Please, don't stamp on my flowers
I need the money for my mom's medication
Please...
Mentor, just a moment
Go back with me and be my concubine
Then you'll have money for medication
Let go of her
What are you doing here?
You have to pay for her flowers
How does that concern you?
Indeed
Beat him up...
Bring it on...
All right
What are you doing?
Miss, don't worry
I am standing up for you
I'll bear the consequences
Stop it...
Mok's Family School
Hello folks, I am from Foshan...
What are you doing?
What's wrong with you?
Get up
Miss, what now?
Chivalry is not welcome here in Canton?
You really can't tell?
We are doing a modern play
What?
You can't tell it's acting?
Modern play?
Yes
It's acting, it's not real, it's a play
I really am sorry
It's my first time in Canton
I really am sorry...
Don't be such a fool next time
You guys alright?
This man...
No pictures...
Mentor, let's go
Modern play?
Mentor, could you tell?
Since you couldn't either, how could I?
This is not Foshan
We have to be more careful
Stay out of trouble
Take mine...
He's a cripple, it'll be
a bumpy ride for you
What nonsense
I dare you for a challenge
I'll put a bucket of water on my rickshaw
Not a drop of water will be spilled
I don't believe it
Well? Any spillage?
Any?
Not a drop of it!
Boss, take mine
Alright, guys
I'll take yours
Boss, his is all wet
Cripple, you'll see
Go!
Sir, how should I call you?
Zi
Zi, you speak with a Foshan accent
You have lived in Foshan before?
None of your business
Young man, you are competitive
The loser will go hungry
Mentor, you go in first
Let me call on a friend
This is not our hometown.
You be careful
I know
Zi, Taojin Street
Go!
Foshan Guild Hall
He's got nothing to do with it
Let him go
It's alright, I am an out-of-towner
I'd love some fun
Let me just watch from here
Zi, you know how many rickshaw
pullers are there in Canton?
Three thousand
Three thousand!
They are all my men
I have more men than the police force
I am somebody here
Brother Lo, save your effort
He's not giving you face
I hear that you won't pay your dues
What nerve
You don't mean to pay me your respect?
I make my own living with my own hands
What have you got to do with it?
I am somebody, I am not petty
Young man, listen very carefully
Pay your dues and keep a low profile
Then you can be a rickshaw puller, get it?
I make my own living with my own hands
Every copper belongs to me
Hands off my money
You...
Sit tight
Beat him up!
Try him out!
Chase...
Give way...
You stay out of it
But I am in it
It's not your concern
They hit me
Stay away and they'll leave you alone
But I am on your rickshaw
Not anymore
Alright
So?
Who is he?
The Crane School?
Come down
Hey, I've told you
This doesn't concern you
Hey, mind yourself
Does it hurt?
Halt! All halt!
Young man, your mentor is
Yu Fung-kau of the Crane School?
You know my mentor?
My pleasure
I have never met your mentor
But it'll be my honour to meet him
It's said he had a match with Wong Fei-hung
Young man, could you inform your mentor
That Brother Lo asks him to join him for
a drink at the Phoenix House this evening?
Thank you indeed
Let's go
Are you going?
Sure
You sure pull all stops
You may stand up to one
You may stand up to ten
You may stand up to a hundred
But can you stand up to a thousand?
The world is full of stray dogs
I am one of them
There's only one piece of bone
in the rubbish bin
If I don't take it, other dogs will
And they will come for me afterwards
I may get killed, but I'll try
to get them first
We may have to live like dogs
But we aren't dogs
You are human, you don't know dogs
Who was that Brother Lo?
Lap dog, Marshal Lo's
Marshal Lo? Lo Cheung-yee?
How come a martial arts practitioner
is linked to a warlord?
Here you are, just go over
Keep the change
I earn my own living with my own effort
Not from alms
How can I get in touch with you?
Isn't he the fool I met earlier?
Uncle... Yes?
You've come to the right person
Others can't do it for you
Just watch
Be careful...
You... alright?
I am fine...
But your suitcase...
Kid...
Hey...
Siu-lin, answer the door
Who do you want?
Cheung Wing-sing
Wing-sing
lp Man?
You sure look good
Good?
Wait till you see me at the gate of
the Forbidden City
After the northern expedition
Northern expedition?
So we are fighting up north?
It's confidential
I never thought you would join the army
You didn't see the warlords very highly
But I believe in Brother Ching-shan
Brother Ching-shan? Where's he?
He's now Deputy Chief Secretary
of the provincial government
It's he who convinced me to join the army
Let me take you to him sometime
I should have come earlier to see you guys
Oh yes, did you meet my sister
when you got in?
Your sister? Who's your sister?
My cousin
Her parents died early
She has been living with us
My dad is her paternal uncle
He sees her as his own daughter
Cousin?
Cheung Wing-shing?
Yes, you have forgotten about it?
We used to go play in your house
when we're small
Oi-dor, the Cheung family and the lp family
are in different fields
But we are equal in status
I do hope that we can be in-laws
What do you think?
Great, of course! We can't be happier
But... you are marrying down
Please don't say so
Good... so lp Man and
Miss Wing-shing are betrothed
It's a deal
lp Man... Ip Man?
Good
Good? About what?
Nothing...
You alright?
I am fine
You don't look right to me
Wing-sing, it's too loud
Dad, see who's here
Uncle...
Ip Man?
Come on over
Let me have a good look at you
Not bad at all
Oi-dor has raised up a fine man
Uncle, I got it from Dad that most
of your time has been spent overseas
But it's my first time in Canton
Even so, Dad and Mom were
reluctant to let me come
Uncle, you should talk them over
Tell them that a man has to see the world
You can't wait to enlist me
to your cause
Stay as long as you like in Canton
I'll tell your dad about it, alright?
Uncle, thank you
Where's Wing-shing?
She's with him again?
Dad, why are you prejudiced against him?
You and Wing-shing...
are too young to understand
lp Man, make yourself at home
Take care of him
I have to go back to my work
Please, don't let me get in your way
Alright
Him? Whom were you talking about?
Brother Ching-shan
He and Wing-shing were schoolmates overseas
How long will it take?
Lt'll soon be done
Dad, Mom, I can't be happier
with this betrothal
Ching-shan, how do I look?
Gorgeous
You will steal the limelight
tomorrow night
You two sure make a pretty pair
A match made in heaven
Tomorrow night, I'll have an
announcement to make
The alteration first
Sir, hello, it's for members only here
Members Only
Members only? What does that mean?
You can't go in unless you are a member
But you open your door for business
Sir, I am sorry
Sir, you can't go in...
Sir...
Wing-shing...
Excuse me... but where's the girl?
She's here not just now
She has left by that side
Sorry, Sir, you can't come in
Please leave here, sorry
This way please
You may disrupt our members
I am sorry...
Mentor
How come my suitcase is here?
I got it back for you
Why look so dejected?
Nothing
Oh yes, Mentor, do you know Brother Lo
of Shahe Gang?
He's well-known to everyone
That's good
He can't wait to meet you
He's inviting you for a drink this evening
I am not going
But why not?
You think it's just for a drink?
Shahe Gang has been tailing us
since we got off the boat
What?
So has the Mok's Family School
Mok's Family School?
Ching-shan, can this
Mok Yan-chiu beat Yu Fung-kau?
No
But you referred him to be our coach
Ching-shan, many warlords
have come to Canton
Our coach has to beat everyone else
This convention is not just
about martial arts
It's also a power contest amongst
the warlords
No wonder Zi called Brother Lo
Marshal Lo's dog
What about the Mok's Family School?
Marshal Chu's
Marshal Chu?
If I can't win, I'll have to step down
But Marshal, you will win
I have found you the right man
He stands head and shoulders above others
Who is he?
You can meet him tonight
the Foshan Hero, Yu Fung-kau
Good
Hence we have to be careful
Then should we go to Brother Ching-shan
to get the invitations to the convention?
Soldiers are not difficult to recruit
Money is not difficult to make
Firearms not difficult to get
Cannons not difficult to handle
But talents are hard to come by
You have to get him for me
Marshal, rest assured of that
Winner takes all, you will be the winner
The moment of truth is
in a couple of days
Very good
Guangdong Provincial Government
Who do you want?
Lam Ching-shan
Second floor, turn left
Thank you
So many rooms, which one?
Excuse me
Which one is Lam Ching-shan's room?
Down the corridor, the one on the left
Thank you
You're welcome
Sir, Miss Cheung's here
Alright
Sorry, Marshal wanted me
I couldn't go away
No need to apologise to me
You should apologise to yourself
and your ideals
What do you mean?
You are a man of ideals and aspirations
But you are here mapping out
strategies for Marshal Chu
To help him win the civil war
Even if he wins
Will it contribute to the revolution?
Hush
You do see it eye to eye with this
female reporter by the name of Ha Kui
Marshal Chu and Marshal Lo
One wears revolution on his lips
One wears interest on his lips
But they are two of a kind
We shouldn't trust such old school
warlords with our revolution
Which part of it is wrong?
Very insightful
Who do you want?
Where is Lam Ching-shan?
Inside
Thank you
Excuse me, where is Lam Ching-shan?
He's having a talk inside
Please wait over there
You will be notified
Secretary Li, you are wanted
Come try this firearm
What are you doing?
Come on, be still, aim, hold it tight
When the points are in line
pull the trigger
Stop kidding
Don't worry, it's not loaded, try it
Ready?
Hold it tight, aim, be still, aim
Now fire
Wing-shing
Chief Secretary Lam
It's alright, we were trying out
the firearm
Now you see how powerful it is?
It's loaded
Stop
Who are you?
Let me tell you
The magazine may be out
There's still one bullet in the bore
I can still kill you
Lam Ching-shan
What? You know each other?
We've met twice
Brother Ching-shan
You... Ip Man
You sure have grown up
I wouldn't recognise you if we
bumped into each other out on the street
You came to Canton alone?
I came with my mentor
for the martial arts convention
Master Yu Fung-kau
Master Yu, it's my honour