Come on, Laurie Anne. It's going to storm.
Hi.
Laurie Anne?
Honey? Don't scare Mama now.
Excuse me. Move along.
Mmm-hmm.
Chief's going to have a cow
when he sees you nosing around, Mike.
Iwon't tell him if you don't.
What you got, Sam?
There's not much left.
Just like the last time.
- Anybody see anything?
- The mother said she saw--
I thought I told you
to stay out of this, Hanlon.
I'm just a concerned citizen, Chief.
And I call six kids missing or dead
a major cause for alarm here.
It may be just a rash of runaways.
Kids get itchy feet.
Right. A five-year-old in a toy car
gets itchy feet.
What, a seven-year-old trots down
to Acapulco for a wild weekend?
The boy's father took him.
The other one...
Chief, there's something terribly wrong
here in Derry. And you know it.
Hey. I'm the cop. You're the librarian.
Okay?
Georgie.
May 2am.
Another killing today.
But this time, there was something more.
Something that makes my skin crawl.
A picture that shouldn 't. ..
No, no, that couldn't have been there.
It's time to tell the others
what's happening.
I can't put it off any longer.
But I hope I'm wrong.
Oh, I hope to God I'm wrong.
Taggert steps onto the moors
as the fog curls around his ankles.
He shivers, buttons his coat,
and walks on, disappearing into the mist.
A shadowy figure Iurches into frame,
dripping with foul water
and dark oozing mud.
Yeah. Yeah.
Bill, for the last time.
In a minute!
That's what you said a half an hour ago.
- And a half hour before that.
- Okay!
Okay.
- It's cold.
- Sorry.
I like the changes, Bill.
They're wonderful.
- I wish you'd tell that idiot, Greco.
- I do. Every day.
You didn't have to
take this job, you know.
It's not as ifwe need the money.
In case you've forgotten,
I took the job to be with you.
Besides, if they're gonna hire somebody
to mangle one of my books,
it might as well be me.
Of course, the idea of actually taking
a vacation didn't even occur--
So I could hang around the set
with a bunch of actors?
That's not what I do, Audra.
Writing is what I do.
At least when you're doing a novel,
you're in a good mood.
Audra, could we--
I'm asleep, unless it's Greco.
Greco.
Yeah?
- Bill, is thatyou?
- Sorry, fella, do I know you?
This is Mike Han/on, Bill, from Derry.
Swear to me.
Swear to me that if it isn't dead,
we'll all come back.
- Sorry, Mike, for a minute there...
- You didn't know who I was.
For a minute there, I didn't.
Bill,
It's back.
You're... Sure?
Yeah. I found a photograph of George.
George?
What is it?
Who was on the phone?
Nobody. Wrong number.
Bill?
I have to go back to work.
Georgie.
Please, Bill. Tell me a story.
Maybe later.
The magic stone story.
Please, Bill. Please.
Go bug somebody else, you little cootie.
I don't feel so hot.
Georgie?
For me? You made it for me?
Can I go sail it?
Oh, well, you have to seal it
first with paraffin.
- What's that? Where is it?
-lt's in the cellar.
I wish you could come, too.
She's your boat, really.
Thanks,BHL
Yuck. You got cooties all over me.
Uh, Georgie.
Don't stay out too long,
or Mom will have a bird.
- I won't.
- Georgie.
Be careful.
Sure. Sure, lwill.
SS Georgie!
Come on, come on!
SS Georgie, out of the way!
No, please, no!
Hi, Georgie.
Aren't you going to say hello?
Oh.
Come on, bucko.
Don't you want a balloon?
I'm not supposed to take stuff
from strangers.
My dad said so.
Very wise of your dad, Georgie.
Very wise indeed.
I, Georgie, am Pennwvise,
the Dancing Clown.
You are Georgie.
So, now we know each other.
Correct?
I guess so.
- L've got to go.
- Go?
Without this?
- My boat!
- Exactly.
Go on, kiddo. Take it.
Oh...
You want it, don't you, Georgie?
Of course you do.
And there's cotton candy and rides
and all sorts of surprises down here.
And balloons, too. All colors.
- Do they float?
- Oh, yes.
They float, Georgie.
They float.
And when you're down here with me,
you float, too!
"Fear no evil for thou art with me,
"thy rod and thy staff, they comfort me.
"Thou preparest a table before me
in the presence of mine enemies.
"Thou anointest my head with oil,
my cup runneth over.
"Surely goodness and mercy
shall follow me all the days of my life.
"And I will dwell
in the house of the Lord forever."
Oh, Georgie.
No.
Billy?
- Billy, are you all right?
- What's wrong, son? What is it?
The picture. Georgie's picture.
Mom, don't you see?
Mom.
- What were you doing in Georgie's room?
- Nothing.
Dad, listen!
I don't want you ever coming
in here again, son. Do you understand?
- Dad.
- I mean it, Bill.
I forgot.
How could I forget?
Leave? Have you lost your mind?
We're in the middle of making a movie.
They can replace me.
This is something I have to do.
Who was that on the phone?
The call was from a guy named Mike Hanlon.
I haven't heard from him in almost
30 years. Not since we were kids.
- Audra. My brother, who died--
- Yes, George.
He didn'tjust die.
He was... Murdered.
- Why didn't you ever--
- Tell you?
Because I forgot. Because I forgot.
Almost as if it never happened.
I know this doesn't make any sense,
but I have to go.
For God's sake, why?
Because we made a... promise.
Why are you stuttering like that?
I don't know.
I used to stutter when I was a kid.
What happened? Tell me.
Damn it, Bill, talk to me! Let me help.
- If you're going back, I'm going, too.
- Don't even think that!
- Why not? You're scaring me.
- You promise me you'll stay here.
- Promise me!
- You're crazy.
- This is crazy.
- Pro--
It's just crazy.
I love you.
- Oops.
- Oh, no, Ben.
Your architect award.
And you just received it. It's a tragedy.
Yeah, honey.
We've got ourselves a real tragedy here.
This is an American tragedy.
Oh, look at this.
Would you hang on to this?
I got this, and this, all right.
- Okay.
- Come on.
Here you are, my good man. Recycle.
Here, wait a minute.
I got my magic, uh, opener.
Come on, honey.
Oh! Limbo! How low can you go?
BENZ Whoo!
No, no, no. You don't have to be quiet.
- Is, is all this yours?
- Uh-huh. Come on in.
Here, let me see what I can do with this.
- Oh...
- Oops.
It's so nice.
Come here, beautiful. Come on.
God, look at you!
Ooh
- I love your body.
- Ooh, I like yours, too.
- Would you believe I used to be fat?
- I bet you were real cute.
No, notjust fat,
but a regular butterball.
You bet your fern I was.
We used to say that as kids.
You bet your fern, but I was F-A-T.
- No.
- Yeah.
I hear bells. I'll be right back.
Hello?
Haystack, it's me, Mike.
You're dead, fat boy.
It's payback time, piggy.
You're gonna die, fat boy.
Hey, fat boy!
Ben?
Ben, are you there?
- Mike?
- Yeah, buddy. Listen.
- It... It's come back.
How much do you remember?
Very little. Almost nothing.
Will you come?
I'll come.
Are you okay?
I don't think I am, sweetheart.
Not tonight. Not at all.
Are you gonna kill yourself?
No, I don't think so.
Though it might be better if I did.
My name is Ben Hanscom.
Until last week,
I lived with my mom in Houston, Texas.
We moved here to live with my cousins.
Look at that gut.
Go on, Ben.
Have you any hobbies?
Well, I like to read a lot.
Especially about old civilizations,
the Egyptians, the Indians.
We have a wonderful library here, Ben.
Welcome to Derry.
- Thank you, Miss Douglas.
- Oink, oink.
What a porker.
Henry Bowers,
you will stay for one hour after school
every day this week.
My father will tan my hide.
You should've thought of that
before you picked on Ben.
Now, report to the principal's office.
You're dead, fat boy.
Boy. It's going to be
some funeral, friend.
Now, class,
as you know, the sheriff
has instituted a 7:00 p.m. curfew.
We live in dangerous times,
boys and girls.
I want you to be careful.
Like this place so well
you're going to stand there all day?
School's over, you know.
- Excuse us, please.
- Can we get through?
Honestly, Loni, some people have no class.
Some people have janitors for parents.
Well, so long, Ben Hanscom.
I'm Beverly Marsh.
Well, see you tomorrow, Beverly Marsh.
Beverly Marsh. Beverly Marsh.
- Hey, look, it's the fat boy.
- Top of the day, fat boy.
- What do you want?
- I want to teach you something, porky.
You like to learn new things, don't you?
Mmm-hmm.
I want to make sure you remember my name.
I'll remember, Henry. I'll remember.
How am I gonna make sure? Huh?
Hey, Henry.
Come on, don't really cut him.
Cut him? Huh?
Cut him?
Let's see, first comes...
Oh, God!
You're going to die! You're dead!
I'm gonna bury you!
You're going to die!
Nobody kicks me, porky!
- Nobody kicks me! Nobody!
- Come on, fat boy.
You better run, boy.
You're going to die, man!
Come on, let's get him!
You're dead, fat pig!
Hey, what's this?
Looks like
a geek wading pool to me.
So what are you two girls
doing down here?
Hey, look at the dam,
a stupid little baby dam.
You didn't have to do that.
Why did you do that?
'Cause I felt like it. Give me that.
- That's for my asthma.
- Oh, is that a fact, sissy?
- Leave him alone.
- Shut up, you little creep.
I said stop that,
or I'll pull your ears down
and tie them underneath your chin.
- You seen a fat kid run by here?
- No.
- Big, fat kid, all messed up.
You sure, mush-mouth?
You better be sure.
I'm sure.
Let's go.
Ta-ta, girls.
Oh, no.
It's empty-
I can't breathe.
Are they gone?
Yes. Look, can you stay here
with my friend
while I go get his medicine?
Yeah.
Here. Eddie, it's okay.
Take it easy, kid. You'll be okay.
- You'll be okay.
- Yeah?
What are we gonna do if...
They come back?
Want some?
- My dad, he died of the big
-"The big 'C"'?
Cancer. I was just a little kid.
Yeah, my dad died, too.
He was shot down in Korea.
- Remember him much?
- Sort of, lthink.
- So, who's the other guy?
- Bill?
Bill's my best friend.
He's a really great guy.
Hey!
I'm
back.
- Does he always stutter that much?
-lt's worse since his kid brother died.
Some guy killed George.
Pulled one of his arms right off,
just like a wing off a fly.
That's awful.
Ijust told you because
if you want Bill to be your friend,
it's better not to talk to him
about George.
- He's all messed up about it.
- Man, lwould be, too.
- "Would be, too," what?
- Oh, nothing. Thanks.
Yeah.
Thanks for staying.
Jeez. He's really got it bad.
I was scared he's going to
slip into a coma like on Dr. Kildare.
- Me, too. You're Ben.
- Yeah, and you're Bill.
- Yeah, and this is...
- Eddie. He knows.
I hate it when you stutter my name, Bill.
You sound like Elmer Fudd.
Sorry.
No, no, no. No, Elmer Fudd has a lisp.
It's Porky Pig that stutters.
Okay, 0K8)'-
- Why don't you come back tomorrow?
- Yeah.
Me and Eddie, we're trying to make a dam.
Well, you gotta have some boards.
You get boards and you put them in a row,
facing each other.
- Like the bread of a sandwich and then--
- But we--
Huh?
- But we do it.
- Oh, yeah, "we."
- What are you doing, coz?
- Just something for school.
Let's see.
- Ooh. A poem.
- That's private.
"Your hair is winter fire.
"January embers."
Hey, Mom, listen to this, Benny's in love!
Give this back.
- Oh, Mom! Mom!
- Stop that! Benjamin!
Hanscom, stop that immediately,
you young ruffian!
I hate you!
You're only here because
Mom says it's our Christian duty.
Nobody's ever going to say
a sister of mine is on welfare.
So you're welcome here
as long as you need to stay.
But I have to say
you're spoiling the boy, Arlene.
You need a firm hand, discipline.
We'll have a home of our own
one day, Benny. I promise.
I know, Mama.
Benny, as long as we're guests
in this house, I need you to help me.
They wouldn't treat us like this
if Daddy were still alive.
Come on inside now and apologize.
Apologize? But he was--
- Benny, You must!
- No! I hate it here. I hate it here.
Benny, come on. Benny.
Benny!
Ben! Benny! Up here, Ben.
Daddy?
Benny!
Ben!
Hi, Ben.
Daddy?
That's my home now, son.
Do you want a balloon, Ben?
They float.
They all float.
Come here, son. You'll like it down there.
You'll never have to grow up.
They float.
They all float.
And when you're down here with me,
fat boy, you'll float, too.
Please.
Please, stop.
Beverly By Hand. One moment, please.
Miss Marsh's office.
Hold a moment, please.
Bev, someone calling from Maine,
says it's important.
Maine?
- Pam, I said no calls until--
- We've got a minute. I'll take it.
No. Get their number and close the door.
Your hands are shaking.
I'm scared to death, Tom.
That stuff spreads like cancer.
I won't have it around.
Ah.
There. That's perfect. Don't touch it.
Listen to me, Bevy.
We've got a bunch
of well-heeled Japanese gentlemen
waiting for us downstairs.
We're gonna show 'em around.
You're gonna play
the charming flamboyant designer.
We're gonna sit down, make a deal,
I'm gonna play hardball,
and when it's over, we're gonna be rich.
If you get a hold of yourself right now.
- Do you understand?
- Mmm-hmm.
Okay. Kiss for good luck?
Okay, let's go.
And Bevy, don't ever contradict me
in front of Pam again, okay?
Okay.
Good afternoon, gentlemen.
I'm Beverly Marsh.
This is my partner, Tom Rogan.
- Hello?
- Beverly, it's Mike Han/on.
- Who?
- Mike Han/on. Remember me?
Mike Hanlon. Of course I remember.
How are you?
Fine. Look, are you sitting down?
There you are.
Whoa.
Who was on the phone?
I know you're going to think
this is crazy...
I certainly think it's crazy,
but I've gotta go to Maine.
It's... It's hard to explain. Um...
That was Mike Hanlon on the phone.
You remember the call at work today?
He's an old, dear friend. I have to--
Shut up! That's what you have to do,
just shut up!
The very day I make a deal
of a lifetime for you,
you wanna run off to Maine
with some old boyfriend?
What do you take me for?
Oh, boy. I've seen this coming.
Oh, yes. You've forgotten
your manners, little girl.
Contradicting me here,
smarting off there, and now this.
You've forgotten your lessons, Bevy.
It's been too long since last time.
Put that thing down.
I have to get out to O'Hare
as fast as I can.
There's some trouble,
some very bad trouble.
It's come back, Beverly.
It's come back. Remember your promise.
- Put these clothes back.
- No.
- You get into bed!
- No!
Then maybe you can
leave this house in two days--
- No!
-...Instead of two weeks.
Not ever, ever, ever again!
Listen to me. If you ever come
near me again, I will kill you.
Do you understand? lwill kill you.
Bev, you need me!
Bev!
O'Hare, please.
What airline, miss?
Uh...
I, uh, I need to go to Maine.
All right. We'll find one
that goes to Maine.
What's in Maine? Family?
Fﬂends.
The best I ever had.
Daddy, breakfast is ready.
I'll get it.
"Your hair is winter fire.
"January embers.
"My heart burns there, too."
Who was that at the door, Bevy?
- What do you got there?
- Nothing.
Let me see that.
You been doing something you shouldn't?
You been fooling around with some boy?
Poetry from some boy?
I worry about you a lot, Bevy.
- Sometimes, I worry a lot.
- Daddy, please.
Not even 12
and already running with some boy.
Let me alone, you just let me alone!
Come here!
Don't make me go over there
and collect you. You come to me.
No.
- What did you say?
- I said no!
You get right the hell back here, Bevy!
And in front of God,
I'll whip the skin off of you!
Hi.
I'm sorry if I scared you. Are you okay?
Yeah.
Haven't you got anything better to do
than go sneaking up on people?
- Sorry.
- You should be.
Well, lwas thinking,
it being Saturday and all,
and if you didn't have
anything better to do,
you could come down with me
to the barrens.
The barrens?
This is Eddie,
and this is Bill.
Hi.
Do you guys know each other already?
Well, Bev wants to help. I hope it's okay.
I mean, she's a girl.
Sure.
Hey, what's this? By George, Martha,
it's the river Nile.
And four, count them, four sphinxes.
Richie.
You were expecting maybe Gunga Din?
That's Richie. He can drive you
to the bughouse and back, but he's okay.
I heard that, you skirt. Hi, Bill.
How you doin', Eddie Spaghetti?
Don't do that. I hate it when you do that.
And don't call me "Eddie Spaghetti."
Oh, you love it, Eddie.
It's what makes you so chuck-a-licious.
Richie Tozier's my name.
And doing voices is my game.
This is Stan "the Man" Uris.
Stannie's a Jew, which means
he's really smart and says "oy" a lot.
Richie's got a high metabolism,
and it tends to make him hyperactive.
So you, um, Haystack,
what, are you building a dam or something?
Yeah.
- You ever built one before?
- No.
How do you know it'll work?
- Well, of course it will. Why wouldn't it?
- Yeah, but how do you know?
Ijust know.
- Yeah, he just knows.
- Yeah.
VVeH,okay.
- You're a genius, Haystack.
- Oh, it's not so much.
- Yes, it is. It's great.
- We stopped that sucker cold!
- Yeah.
-lt's great.
We could flood out the whole barrens
ifwe wanted to.
We did it! We!
- Yes!
- Yeah! Yeah!
Listen, I'll go this way.
- See you later, alligator.
- After a while, crocodile.
- See you, Ben.
- Yeah, see you, Bill.
Hi yo, Silver. Away!
See you, Beverly.
See you.
My heart burns there, too.
77 Sunset Strip will continue
following station identification.
Help me.
Help me, please.
- Help me, Beverly.
- Hello?
ls someone there?
The clown brought us down here.
We all float.
Who are you?
- I'm Vickie Burrows.
- I'm Matthew O'Connor.
We're all the dead kids.
Come closer, Beverly.
We all want to meet you.
- We float.
Daddy!
- What in the name of heaven?
- The bathroom, Daddy, the bathroom!
- Was someone peeping in at you, girl?
- The sink, in the sink!
Well, what is it you think you saw?
Speak up, girl!
I worry about you, Bevy.
Sometimes I worry a lot.
Now explain yourself!
There was a spider.
A big, fat spider.
It crawled out of the drain,
and I guess it crawled back down again.
Now, these buildings are old,
with drains the size
of the Holland Tunnel.
There's nothing there now.
Get to bed.
Say hello to your friends, Beverly.
You'll die if you try to fight us.
You'll die if you try.
You'll die
if you try to fight us, Beverly.
You'll die if you try.
Eddie!
Eddie, where are you?
Eddie ?
- Eddie, where are you?
-l'm in here, Ma.
Eddie.
Ah.
Where... Where are you going?
I have to go away for a while.
UAWayu?
Eddie, this isn't like you.
Tell me where you're going.
Eddie, stop!
You're in trouble, aren't you?
Eddie?
Tell me who was on the phone. Answer me.
Answer me.
Mom, please, please. Don't cry, okay?
Eddie, you're scaring me so bad,
you've got to tell me.
Eddie.
- Where are you going? Derry?
-l've gotta go back to Derry.
Why would you want to go back
to that dirty little town?
There's nothing for you there.
There never was, Eddie.
Please, Ma. Please.
Eddie!
- Let's get out of here.
- Jeez, Eddie.
- What's going on?
- Nothing.
- You look like you've seen a ghost.
- Move it!
MRS. KASPBRAKI Eddie!
Joey, I'm sorry
to be leaving you holding the bag.
Do we have enough drivers
lined up for next week?
It's covered, Eddie.
All right, lwant you to do
the Pacino job yourself.
Remember, he likes the Lincoln stretch.
I know, Eddie.
The business is under control.
Great.
- It's you I'm worried about. Yeah?
- I'm fine.
So where are we going?
Penn Station. The 11:30 to Boston.
They saw me.
- We-- We better go.
-l'm a dead man.
If I were you guys,
I wouldn't pay to see a monster movie,
I'd just stay home and look in a mirror.
BENZ Richie!
Let's get out of here!
Yeah, let's go!
- Oh, did you see those guys?
- I saw you make it worse.
Oh, come on, Eddie Spaghetti.
- It was just a joke.
- Sometimes you joke too much.
Yeah, well, sometimes you gotta
make jokes, or you die of boredom.
- I mean, are we men or are we mice?
- We're mice!
Then let's act like mice.
Oh, look.
That place scares me green.
I think it's haunted.
Honestly, Eddie, such things
just aren't empirically possible.
In English, ain't no such thing.
You know, you're a pretty swift guy
for a girl, my little chickadee.
Why, Richie Tozier, was that a compliment?
On our very first date?
0n...
How come Richie's so special?
Well, the date wasn'tjust with him,
Eddie dear. I love you, too.
- Ooh.
- Ew.
Hey, don't trip!
Whoa!
You know, Eddie,
it's been great, but see you later.
- See you later.
- Bye, Eddie.
I wish this summer would never end.
It's the best summer of my whole life.
MRS. KASPBRAKI Eddie.
Eddie Kaspbrak,
I was worried sick.
I almost called the police.
- Eddie was with us, Mrs.--
- Go away.
Go home.
Ma, these are my friends.
- See you tomorrow, Eddie.
- Eddie has to rest tomorrow.
I don't want you to play with them
anymore. No good will come of it.
But, Ma, they're my friends.
You don't need any friends, Eddie,
except for your own ma.
- You feel warm.
- I'm fine.
No gym and no showers
with the other boys this week.
- I don't want you catching their germs.
All right, you guys, quit that running,
this is a hallway, not a track! Come on!
- Did you take a shower, Kaspbrak?
- No, sir.
Now look, I'm gonna explain this to you
only one more time.
You take phys ed, you sweat,
you take a shower. Got it?
PENNYWISEI It's okay, Eddie.
Hi. I just wanted to say hello.
Hot enough for you up there, is it?
This is a little inconvenient, Eddie.
Just hold on
while I make a few adjustments.
Here I am, wheezy.
Hey. You're gonna like it down here.
Won't do any good to run, girly boy.
See you in your dreams.
Oh, come back anytime.
Bring your friends.
So I say, "Go ahead,
"make my day."
And the next thing you know,
I'm feeling my way to the toilet.
I mean, how much power
does the electric company have, huh?
How much power does the electric company--
Remember Godzilla ?
I mean, a plane couldn't stop him,
the atom bomb couldn't stop him,
hell, Nancy Reagan couldn't stop him.
But you get him in front of
one high power line...
Look, look!
The creature is attacking the city.
You guys are great!
Good night! Good night!
Bobby!
Hey, hey, guys!
Thank you!
Beautiful!
I don't know. That
political material is getting real old.
Who the hell knows Betty Ford?
We've got to work on this, man.
We've got to work on--
Oh, hold on, hold on, hold on. Oh.
There she is. Hey.
How's my favorite niece?
I'm so glad you made it.
I want to see Miller first thing Monday.
First thing Monday,
I want to see Miller, okay?
- I've got it arranged.
- Okay?
If I'm host...
Listen. If I'm hosting next week,
I've got to have that new material.
I've got somebody you've got to meet.
- I can't tell you-- Okay.
- Hold on, hold on, hold on.
Buona sera.
Yeah, this is Richie Tozier.
Who's this, Elvis?
- Mike Han/on.
- Who?
Who?
Mike Han/on, from Derry. Do you remember?
Yeah. Sure, I remember you, pally.
What about subbing for Carson
on Monday night?
Who's going to sit behind the desk
and make funny?
- Let Leno do it, ldon't care.
- Richie!
What am I going to tell them?
You tell 'em whatever you have
to tell 'em, Nat! I need a couple of days.
Couple of days for what?
The reunion of your Cub Scout pack
at Grover's Corners?
Come on, boychik, what is it?
A broad? The mob?
I don't know what it is.
Now, don't insult my intelligence.
I made a promise.
We've been through a lot together, Rich.
You're doing fine. You can handle this.
No, this can't be happening!
Help!
Oh, God. Help!
Help! Help!
They felt its breath,
hot and horrible, against their faces.
But at that moment, they released
the stones and ran out of the cave.
And now, they were back home,
but nothing could change
the way they felt.
They had learned to be strong together.
They had beaten the dragon
with their magic stones,
and nothing would ever be the same again.
You gotta write that one down, Bill.
That's my favorite.
- Really excellent.
- Beautiful.
Yeah, Bill's going to leave
this one-horse town and meet Sandra Dee
and all the other babes in Hollwvood.
Dream on, Richie.
I'm not sure I want to grow up at all.
Well, I do. lwant to be
a train conductor and see the world.
That is if your mom
ever lets you cross the street.
I want to be
the first rock 'n' roll singer from Derry.
Either that or an impressionist.
Your voices all sound the same, Richie.
Thanks a bunch, professor.
- How about you, Bev?
- A painter, maybe.
My dad's been teaching me how to draw.
Fighter pilot. When I'm old enough,
I'm gonna join the Air Force.
An ornithologist.
I like cataloging things
and finding their logical order.
Can I tell you guys something?
If you guys laugh, I'll never--
YOUNG BENZ We won't, will We?
N0.
The other night, in Georgie's room--
What on earth? For the love of Mike!
Look at this mess. The saints preserve us.
Officer Nell.
Don't "Officer Nell" me. You're fixing
to back flood all the drains in town
- Whose brainstorm was this, eh?
- I showed them how, it's my fault.
It was my idea.
- Me, too.
- Yeah, lwas in on it, too.
And me.
- I suppose it was your idea, too, lass?
- Yes.
Now listen to rne, all of you.
There's been another murder.
- Little Velma Daniels.
- Velma Daniels?
Her poor body was found this morning
down by the canal.
So, if you come down here to play,
come together like you are now.
Understand?
That means together, all the time.
Your hands on it?
So what do you think
Bill was going to tell us yesterday?
I don't know.
He's been acting awful moody lately.
In fact, they all have.
Of course, with this food,
who can blame them?
Well, hey.
- Larry, Curly and Moe.
- Beep, beep, Richie!
All right, twerp. Who threw it, huh?
Was it you? lt was you, wasn't it?
Tell me. And you might live
through this, four-eyes.
At the Paramount theater, who did it?
Hey, way to go, banana-heels.
Tozier!
Bowers!
Go downstairs and get a mop
from Mr. Marsh and clean this up!
Go on!
Mr. Marsh?
Great. Just great.
Yoo-hoo. Mr. Marsh, you down here?
Probably drunk as a skunk.
Mr. Marsh?
Uh, Mr. Marsh,
I had a little accident in the cafeteria.
No, this... This isn't happening.
Help!
Oh, God, help!
"Beep, beep, Richie"!
Come back, anytime!
I'll show you how to float down here.
They all float down here.
Help!
You've got to help me. Somebody, please.
In the basement, there's a werewolf.
Stop him.
I remember the day
I took that photo,
one of the best days of my life.
We were lucky that summer,
lucky we didn't get
our fool selves killed.
Or maybe there was something
more than luck at work.
If so, I hope it returns when they do.
Lucky seven.
Ibrought this
old photo album from home.
My dad was stationed in Derry
during World War ll,
and he started collecting these old photos
that go way back to the olden days.
Who'd want a history of this toilet?
Henry, how many years
will you be in here with me?
Continue, Michael.
This is the old ironworks.
One Sunday, back in 1930,
there was an Easter egg hunt here.
But the ironworks exploded
and all these people got killed.
This is the Derry Standpipe.
It supplied all the water to the town
until a big disaster back in 1900.
Maybe the biggest mystery
is how 253 settlers
just disappeared without a trace.
Thank you, Michael, for that illuminating,
if somewhat morbid, history.
Now, who's next?
Howdy, partner.
- Give it here.
-"Give it here."
Or what, boy? Or what?
The nigger here lives down the street
from me and my daddy, isn't that so?
Give it here.
You've been giving me and my daddy
grief for a long, long time.
You like fireworks, boy?
Huh?
What do you say
to a rocket in your pocket?
Hey, you!
Stop that right now.
Get him!
I'mjust glad I'm not
the only one who saw something.
It wasn't a clown at first.
It was a werewolf.
I didn't see a werewolf.
Just a clown.
Don't you see
it was a werewolf for Richie
because he saw that dumb movie.
But it was a clown underneath.
So, maybe it's some kind of evil being
that can read our minds
and take the shape of stuff
we're afraid of.
And that's what happened
to all the kids around here?
Pfft. Get serious.
Come on, come on!
Why didn't any of us say anything?
Personally, lthought
you guys would think I was nuts.
Me, too. I thought it was just me.
You're not alone.
Such a thing
just isn't empirically possible.
Real. It was so real.
Yeah, Stan, it almost had
my guts for garters.
Probablyjust the influence of the movie.
Couldn't it be just some crazy guy
dressed up in a clown suit?
N0.
It's some kind of monster,
and it's right here in Derry.
I'm going to bury you!
God, Henry Bowers.
We better get out of here.
- Dummy up. All of you. Rocks.
- Rocks?
Rocks. Ammo.
Help me. Please, help me.
You're dead!
Well, what do you know?
It's the fat boy, the Jew and the sissy.
Four-eyes and the patch girl, too.
Nigger, you know how to pick them.
The loser's club.
Yeah, yeah, the loser's club.
I got bones to pick with you,
but I'm willing to let that go for today.
Today, lwant him. So buzz off.
Why don't you guys get out of here?
- Who's going to make me?
- We are.
What did you say, chubs?
Hey, dig the wax
out of your ears, barf breath.
You're through... Bowers.
Get out!
You stuttering freak.
You're going to get a surprise.
You're going to get such a surprise!
Come on, Bowers!
Ow!
RU". Henry!
Come on!
Ow!
Get out.
What if I won't?
I think the six of us
could put you in the hospital.
Seven.
I'll kill you all.
Get some new material, champ.
I'll kill you all!
Thanks.
Anytime.
Who are you guys anWVaY?
We're sort of a club.
Yeah, the Loser's Club.
Yeah.
You want in?
Yeah. Yeah, I do.
Hey, we're seven now.
Lucky seven.
Hey, wait a second.
Camera.
My dad says there's no way
to date this one.
He says it's probably
from the early or mid-1700s,
when Derry was a logging town.
Hold this.
- Pennwvise the Clown?
- That's him.
That's him!
Two hundred years ago? He was here then?
Come on! lt'sjust a...
It's just a drawing.
Now look.
Here he is again.
The same man.
It's not a man.
It.
It!
That's what happened
back in Georgie's room.
Look!
I'll kill you all.
I'll drive you crazy,
and I'll kill you all.
I'm every nightmare you've ever had.
I'm your worst dream come true.
- I'm everything you ever were afraid of.
4R0ARs)
4ALLSCREAM)
- No.
- Yes.
- Stan.
- No.
- Yes.
- Don't let it get to you, man.
- You saw it, too.
- I didn't want to.
- But you did.
Yes. Okay. That's what you want?
Yes.
Yeah, yeah.
That's what I wanted, you turkey.
- What are we going to do?
-"Do"? What do you mean "do"?
I just want to forget about it.
It's notjust us.
It's all the other kids, too.
Like Velma Daniels, she was in my class.
Who's going to be next?
Bev's right.
We've gotta do something.
- We've gotta tell somebody.
- They don't see what we see.
VVhy?
When you grow up, you stop believing.
Theyjust laugh their heads off
and put us in a nuthatch.
- It kills kids, damn it.
- We've gotta do something.
Help me.
You killed my brother, George,
you bastard.
Let's see you now.
It's scared of us, you know?
I can feel that. I swear to God I can.
I want to kill It.
Help me.
Please, help me.
Balki. Balki, Iel' go.
- You let go.
- You let go first.
AII right, Balki.
On the count of three, we'll both let go.
- Ready?
- One, two, three.
Oh...
We got a letter from Mom today.
She asked when we were going to
make her a grandma.
The woman's uncanny.
I was just thinking the same thing myself.
Well, I was, really.
Does she know I'm a sex maniac
and you prefer Perfect Strangers, huh?
You want to pay attention to me?
Don't move.
Uris residence. Stan speaking.
This better be good.
Hello, Stan. It's Mike Han/on.
- Who did you say?
- Mike Han/on.
- Mike Hanlon?
- Yeah.
I'll be damned.
Stan, It's come back.
- Are you sure?
- Yeah, I'm sure.
- You understand? I am sure.
- No, I understand.
Look, I hope you know
how hard it is to call--
I get the picture.
Can you make it, Stan? Please.
No, I can't absolutely promise that.
- Don't you remember, Stan?
- But I'll... I'll certainly consider it.
- Don't you remember your promise?
- What? Yes, Mike.
- You promised.
- Yes, I remember.
I hope you come.
- Good bye.
- Bye, Stan.
Ican't even ski
in my own living room.
This isn't going to work.
Who was it, honey?
But I'm glad.
Now you can make a new beginning
and tell Jennifer the truth.
Stan?
No one.
No one, really.
Ithink I'll take a bath.
Now?
A scout is trustworthy,
loyal, helpful, friendly, courteous, kind,
obedient, cheerful, thrifty,
brave, clean and reverent.
- You okay?
- I think this is crazy.
One out of 10.
You're worse than I am, kiddo.
At this rate, we might as well
let that damn clown take us one by one.
Beep, beep, Richie.
Who's left? Ben? Bev?
Yeah, and one of them
better be good, Bill,
'cause you're in the lead right now
with a pathetic three out of 10.
Richie, will you please shut up?
- You know, you don't stutter all the time.
- Ladies first.
Ten out of 10.
Don't think I need to shoot.
It's like it's supposed to be Bev.
- Yeah.
- Whoa.
- This is still crazy.
No, it's not.
- l'm with Stan.
So what if I can shoot good?
You think a handful of stones
are going to stop--
Show them, Richie.
My mother's earrings, baby. Solid silver.
That's just stuff in movies.
What good is it going to do against--
They're silver. They can kill It.
Believe, Stannie. We have to.
"On my honor,
I will do my best
"to do my duty to God and my country,
"to help other people at all times,
keep myself physically strong,
"mentally awake and morally..."
Maybe this isn't
such a good idea.
- What are you mumbling about?
- Shh.
Now, listen.
You guys don't have to do this.
My dad says you have to know
when to take a stand.
Lucky seven, Stannie.
Isaid lwas in.
Yeah, you think we're going to
let you have all the fun there, Billy-boy?
Eddie?
I'm with my friends. Right?
Give me that.
Yuck. It tastes like battery acid.
- Where are they going?
- Down in the sewer, stupid.
Yeah.
And guess what?
They're not coming back out.
You mean
we gotta go down there?
Stan, if you don't want to go...
Now's the time to turn back.
Great choice. Let's go.
All right.
They're going down into the pipes.
Remember when we chased that dog
down in there?
- Yeah.
- Okay.
You go how we went.
You'll come out ahead of them,
chase them back towards us.
Me and Belch are gonna catch up to them.
Hurry or there will be nothing
left for you.
Go by myself, Henry?
"Go by myself, Henry?"
Yeah, go by yourself.
What are you afraid of, huh?
The boogeyman?
Hardy-har-har.
Yeah, well, at least we know
we're on It's trail.
Maybe this is where lt wants us to be.
Eddie, which way is Derry?
Okay. Look, Bev, you get up front
where you can get a clear shot.
And you guys, stay together.
No stragglers.
Hi, kid.
I, uh, guess you're the first.
- Who's missing?
- Stan.
Oh, no!
Now, before you die,
I want you to think about
every rock you threw,
and everything you've said.
I want you to think about that
before you die.
Hey, Henry.
What was that?
Belch!
God, he's not in there anymore.
Help!
IT'S Stan!
It's coming! It's coming!
Hands, quick!
Is that it? Did We do it?
Look!
Quick! Take hands
before we get lost in this stuff.
Grab hold!
Is everybody here?
-L'm here. Stannie?
- Yeah.
Richie?
Yeah. Uh, Mike?
Here.
- Whose hand is this?
- Mine.
That you, Ben?
Yeah.
Okay.
Whatever happens, hang on.
It's not as strong as it thought it was,
or it could've killed us just then.
We have to resist!
Bill! Bill!
Georgie?
N0, Bill!
That's not George. Don't break the circle.
Bevy!
Bevy, what do you think you're doing
down here with these boys?
Now, get home.
Daddy? Daddy, I'm...
Wake up, hot stuff.
That ain't Daddy.
There ain't nothing there.
lsaid...
I said there ain't nothing there.
...l will do my best
to do my duty to God and my country.
On my honor, I will do my best
PENNYWISEI Stan.
Stanley, boy.
Ben?
- Stanley, resist!
- That's it!
Let go! Be afraid!
Bev, the stones!
You all taste so much better
when you're afraid!
Hurry, Bev, kill il'!
"Kill"?
- PENNYWISEI Me?
- Oh...
Oh, you are priceless, brat.
lam eternal, child.
I am the eater of worlds
and of children.
And you are next.
This is battery acid, you slime!
Please, God.
- YOUNG RITCHIE; Kill it! Kill it, Bev!
- Kill it! Kill, Bev!
- Kill it, Bev!
- D0 it!
Help me! Help me!
- lt's dead?
- I don't think so.
- We got to get out of here.
- We've got to go after it!
- No, it's dead.
- We have to make sure!
- It sounded like it was dying.
- Yeah, what if it didn't?
-lt's over.
Right?
Swear to me...
Swear to me that if it isn't dead,
we'll all come back.
I swear.
I swear it.
Yeah, I swear.
I swear, too.
I swear.
Swear.
Stannie?
I'm coming upstairs to scrub your back
and your chest.
And...
Stanley?
Stan?
Here you go.
- You sure you don't want me to wait?
- No, thanks, I'll walk back.
Georgie.
How could I have forgotten?
I'm so sorry.
Take your pick...
Billy-boy.
0m
Except for the one on the end.
That's already taken.
Sorry.
I remember you.
And I remember we beat you.
I'm not afraid of you.
I know how old I look.
It's just that I remember you as a kid.
Welcome home, Bill.
I only wish it was under happier...
Come on, let's go out.
It occurred to me in there
that I didn't create any more paranoia
than we already have here.
I got a taste of it myself, earlier.
At least people seem to care now.
Or maybe it's just that
I'm a grown-up now.
I feel so thick, Mike.
I don't remember much of it at all,
what we did.
I don't even remember why I came back,
except for Georgie.
I'll bet it doesn't all come back at once.
How come you remember?
I never left, how could I forget?
All I do is look on the street corner
and there we were. Seven of us.
Lucky seven.
Oh, man, thatjust came back.
Something else.
- One of us lived around here.
- Right.
Bev!
Right down the street.
Her father...
She was poor. Her father was the janitor.
This was Poor Town.
Yeah, still is.
Yours?
Hey, I'm a bachelor, Bill.
It's all I need.
It's clean and better yet, it's paid for.
Feeling hungry?
Frankly, I haven't had an appetite
since you called.
I've arranged
dinner tonight for all of us.
Have you seen any of the others?
No. But I've had a feeling all afternoon
I could tell whenever one of us hit town.
I don't think we're all here, yet.
No.
You, too?
Whatever it is, it's powerful stuff.
Well, here's to remembering.
What?
Maybe this will stimulate
those old memory banks a little.
Silver.
Yep, I ran across it in the pawn shop
about a year ago.
I don't know, something made me buy it.
It's got a flat tire,
but that's all that's wrong with it.
But here's the real kicker.
I bought this tube repair kit on impulse.
About three months before I saw this bike.
There was some kind of force
guiding us that summer.
I don't know if it came just to help us
or if we created it.
But maybe it's still here.
I'm going to change clothes.
Oh, come on!
Not the Paramount, you slimeballs!
Where are the people of this city
supposed to get their culture?
- May I help you?
- Mike Hanlon.
He stepped out a short while ago.
- L'm pretty sure he's coming back.
- Good.
Uh... I'm gonna sit here
and I'm gonna wait here for him.
Come on, Tozier, get a grip.
You look like you could use this.
It's just water.
Thank you.
A little young for you,
isn't she, Richie?
Beep, beep, Richie.
I didn't hear that.
I didn't!
I beg your pardon?
PENNYWISEI Come On up, Richie!
I got a balloon for you.
Don't you want a balloon?
What's the matter, one balloon not enough?
Try a bunch!
ls everything all right?
- Yes--
- Last chance, Tozier.
Get out before it gets dark tonight.
You're too old to stop me.
You're all too old.
- Tell Mike Hanlon if you see him--
- Excuse me, sir.
Do you have Prince Albert in a can?
You do?
Well, you better let the poor guy out.
Tell Mike Hanlon that I had to go.
That I had to get cleaned up. Tell him.
Tell him.
Tell him I'll see him tonight.
Get out!
Last chance, Tozier. Get out!
Get out while you can.
Excuse me, ma 'am.
Is your refrigerator running? It is?
Well, you better catch it
before it runs away.
MIKE; Whoa!
Whoa!
All right!
Son ofa gun.
Not just any cards, Bicycle.
They always made the best noise.
Bill?
I see it.
All right, you follow up on this
Miller thing. I'll call Todd myself.
What about the engineer's report?
What's that?
You're breaking up, Fran.
I'll call you from the hotel.
Pull over here, will you?
Wait for me.
You're it! You're it!
- You're dead, fat boy.
- Come on!
You're going to die!
- Yeah!
- Get him!
You're dead! You're dead!
Run, fat boy!
- You're it, porky.
- You're it!
- Have a nice trip.
- See you later, porky.
- Hey, you okay, buddy?
- My knee.
Lucky for me you have that hankie thing.
Be prepared.
Here, why don't you just keep it?
I think I'll be okay now.
Hang tough, champ. You're gonna make it.
Ben Hanscom!
It's nice to see you again.
What have you been up to all these years?
We can't wait
to get you down here with us.
You're in my mind. Only in my mind.
Any spare change, mister?
Hey, who walked all over your grave?
I wasn't going to hurt you.
I don't even know you.
Let's go.
- Derry Inn, did you say?
- Yeah.
Reliving your childhood down there?
Something like that. Just saying hi
to some old ghosts, you know.
Oh, hell. Time does go by.
Here's that prescription.
How old are you now, son?
Eleven. Almost 12.
Old enough. Come with me.
Come on.
Relax, Eddie. I'm not gonna bite you.
Now, most of your troubles come from
you being so tight and stiff all the time.
You take your asthma, for instance.
Do you know what a placebo is, Eddie?
I got to go.
It's water, Eddie.
Water with a squirt of camphor
to make it taste like medicine.
No.
Your doctor is weak and your mother
is determined that you're ill.
And you, my friend,
are caught in the middle.
It's all a lie, a great big lie!
I do have asthma. I do!
Sir?
Your prescription.
Nothing like a good pull
on the old lung-sucker, huh?
Thank you.
Junior, bring me a cigar.
You know you can't have one, Granddad.
Mr. Keene?
Mr. Keene. Hello.
Cigar for the old man?
I'm sorry. I don't have any.
I'm Eddie Kaspbrak, Sonia Kaspbrak's son.
How about some licorice?
I was always partial to licorice.
Mr. Keene, ljust wanted to thank you
for trying to tell me the truth
a long time ago.
You look a little peaked, sonny.
I'd better go.
Hyd rox.
What?
H20.
Water.
It's only water.
It's all in your head, sonny.
You do remember me.
Oh, Mr. Keene...
Mr. Keene?
Get out of Derry while you still can.
Mr. Keene, please.
Beware, little Eddie.
Beware, girly-boy.
No cigar, sonny.
I was always partial to licorice.
I'm sorry, I must have rung the
wrong bell. lwas looking for Marsh.
- Marsh?
- Yes.
There's no Marsh here. Unless...
You don't mean Alvin Marsh?
Yes, my father.
Oh, Miss...
I hate to be the one to have
to tell you this, a stranger,
but your father's been dead
this last five years.
But on the bell...
Oh...
Kersh. I thought it said "Marsh."
I'm Mrs. Kersh.
I knew your father a little.
- Come in. Let me give you tea.
- No, lcouldn't.
You could and you will. I insist.
Feel free to look around.
Perhaps you'd like to freshen up?
Did you fall
asleep in there? It's teatime.
Tea.
Tea would be nice.
I love what you've done with the place.
It's so different, so cozy.
How kind you are, miss.
I call all the pretty young girls "Miss".
Don't take offense.
No.
Well, go on, dear,
drink it while it's nice and hot.
Don't trouble your
pretty little head, dear.
I'll get it.
It did say "Marsh" on the doorbell.
If you're wise, you'll run, dear, run.
Because to stay will mean
worse than your death.
They float down there.
They float.
I worry about you, Bevy. I worry a lot.
It won't do you any good to run, Bevy.
You're not real! You're not real!
Beep,beep!
I told you the first time
you introduced me to him
that he was a twit, Audra.
Do you remember?
Greco, I didn't ask you over
to insult Bill.
- How dare he do this to me.
- Come on.
You've been complaining about him
ever since we started this picture.
He'll never work in movies again.
I suppose you know that.
If you could have seen his face.
It was frightening.
Nothing like a little crisis to bring
the estranged couple closer together, eh?
Or perhaps pull them farther apart,
if the gods are smiling.
Greco, please.
I'm simply pointing out that this
could be a blessing in disguise.
Would you consider giving me a few days?
I shall pretend I didn't hear that, Audra.
I can replace your imbecilic husband.
I cannot replace you.
Don't even think about leaving, Audra.
You've worked very hard
to get where you are. Very hard.
I know you'd do nothing
to jeopardize that.
Or to damage
our professional relationship.
Or to turn a friend overnight
into a violent enemy,
ready to crucify you at any cost.
But there's no need to talk about that.
See you tomorrow.
International reservations, please.
Yes, I'd like a seat on your next
flight to the United States.
Excuse me,
I'm looking for the Hanlon party.
- Eddie?
- Ben?
- Eddie Kaspbrak.
- Haystack!
- What happened to the rest of you?
- Gone but not forgotten.
Hey. buddy!
Oh, my God.
Where's Richie Tozier
when you need a good line?
- Ben?
-l'm afraid so, Bill.
I can't believe it. Look at you.
Hey, Bill.
- Hey.
- Michael, God.
- Mike, is that you?
- Such as I am, Haystack.
Hey, listen. Who wants a drink?
- Set them up.
-l'll have one.
- What is this?
- That's my dog.
- I'll have a club soda, okay?
- This is pretty good.
Come on, Tozier, don't let them
see you like this, get a grip, man.
That was a hallucination.
lt was a flashback deal.
It was too much fun in '67.
Just get ahold.
You're working too hard, kid.
Jeez, you 9W5-
I got a toast. I propose--
All right, who got bald, who got wrinkled,
and how many of God's children got wings?
- Beep, beep, Richie!
- Richie!
- Richie, beep, beep.
- Mike, hey!
- Hey, buddy, how are you?
- Fine, fine. You?
Beverly?
What a bunch of handsome old men.
EDDIE; Oh!
Hi, good-looking.
Oh, Richie.
Oh...
Eddie!
I'd rather catch you than anybody else
in the whole world, Beverly Marsh.
Oh...
I just saw all of you standing there
and so much came flooding back,
it was like a tidal wave.
Oh, Mike.
What are we getting ourselves into?
- Hi, Bev.
- BEVERLYI Hey.
Oh, I'm so proud of you.
Where's...
Are you all right, Bev?
Yes.
No. I...
I saw something today.
- Same with me.
- Oh, man!
- What I saw at the library, whoa--
- Was it Pennwvise?
With both barrels, it was Pennwvise.
He's working on us already.
- Trying to chip away.
- Maybe that means he's afraid.
It. It's afraid.
Oh, man. It!
Help us remember, Mike.
Help us fill in the gaps.
Yeah, please, because I don't know
what you are guys talking about.
I can't remember much of anything
and when I try, it kind of clouds over.
I mean, didn't you feel it?
As soon as I crossed the county line,
it was like this veil
dropped over my eyes.
Maybe it's the water.
The water? Maybe it's the sewer.
This is battery acid, you slime!
- Eddie!
- Take a breath, man. Breathe.
I'm okay.
I think I remember who Pennwvise was now.
Big white guy, red nose,
about 75 feet tall,
mouth full of razor sharp teeth.
Oh, Eddie.
What the hell is happening, you guys?
What is going on?
I'm sorry.
It was just a very vivid memory.
I had forgotten that I stared
that creep right in the face.
And you saved Stan's life.
You remember that part?
Yeah.
Yeah, now I do.
Hey, speaking of Stan. Stan? Stan!
Where is his royal straightness anwvay?
He wouldn't fink out on us,
would he, Mike?
You talked to him, right?
Yeah, I think he'll be along.
I think we ought to go ahead without him.
When he gets here, we can fill him in.
Come on, Mike, talk to us,
help us remember.
No. Wait a minute.
I don't know about you guys,
but this is the first time
since I got here that I feel good.
I mean, I feel halfway safe. Come on.
Let's have a couple of drinks,
chew on some good food,
have a couple of chucks.
And let'sjust leave
the wolf out the door.
Spoken like a real loser, Richie.
Hey, to the Loser's Club.
- All right!
- To the Loser's Club.
Talking about your wives?
How many times have you been
to the altar, Richie?
Four or five.
Who the hell keeps count?
Women all want the same thing.
No offense, Bev.
None taken, creep.
Welcome to the fourth century.
What about you, Ben, you married?
Nope, I've dodged the bullet
a number of times, now.
- How about you, Eddie?
- Me?
Yeah, I'm seeing this
really wonderful woman,
but with the business and all,
I really don't have too much time.
You take it from me, spaghetti man,
better dead than wed.
Any little crumb
snatchers for you, Richie?
None that I know of.
- How about you, Bev?
- What?
- How about you?
- Oh, uh...
Well, I live with a--
No, I'm not married.
Richie, what ever happened
to those glasses?
Contact lenses.
Richie, for the number of times
you broke those glasses of yours,
you should have had stock in
an adhesive tape company.
Me and Henry Bowers.
Somebody please tell me
he was hit by a freight train
and put out of his misery.
No such luck. You wanna see Henry Bowers
you'll find him up at Juniper Hills.
Ever since the trial, where he confessed
to all the murders of all the children.
- He was down there with us in the sewers.
- That creep was gonna kill Stan.
He was going to kill us all.
I remember when they pulled him out,
his hair had turned white.
- He was babbling about a bright light.
- And a clown.
And no one believed him.
Except when he said
he killed all the kids.
- And we didn't say anything.
- Not a word.
But lt was the killer and we stopped lt.
We thought we did.
PENNYWISEI Henry.
Henry Bowers.
Up here, sharp stuff.
UP here!
You helped me once. Remember?
You chased those brats.
Almost got them, Henry. Almost.
Don't you want another chance?
You've got to go back and finish the job.
You've got to go back to Derry
and kill them all.
For me, Henry.
Kill them all.
Henry, kill them all.
Kill them all. Kill them all.
Kill them all.
Kill them all!
Well, sports fans,
this has been a real hoot,
but I got a plane out at 6:00 a.m.
Richie, you're not leaving?
Bev, girl, what do you want, an adventure?
You got some high-toned idea
that you're gonna go relive
that old nightmare?
I love you, but count me out.
I'm going to a hotel.
I'm gonna get some sleep,
and in the morning, I get on a plane
and I'm out of here forever.
- I will remember all of you very fondly.
- Richie?
Hey, man, we're all scared.
It's nothing to be ashamed of.
Maybe he's right.
I mean, if you are talking about
going back into the sewer?
We don't know
what we're talking about yet
mainly because we haven't talked
about it yet.
Yeah, suppose we give Mike
a chance to fill us in
before we scatter to the four winds.
Or is that too much trouble, Richie?
All I'm saying is I'm gonna
go get some sleep.
Is that too much to ask?
Why don't we show Michael
a little courtesy--
Guys! Guys, come, on!
It's all right, Ben.
If Richie wants to go, he goes.
Now, we all came here based
on the strength of a promise.
As far as I'm concerned, everybody at
this table made good on that promise.
Wherever we go from here,
I have no expectations.
Well said, Michael.
It's all right.
It's taken care of, Richie.
No, you can't do that.
Guys, that's just the way it is.
All right, then.
A toast to Mr. Michael Hanlon.
A man without whom none of this
would have been necessary.
I can see my fortune now,
"You're gonna be eaten by a big,
greasy monster. Have a nice day."
Dummy up, everybody.
What is it? What's wrong?
ls something the matter?
Our friend had an asthma attack,
but he's better now.
I'm much better. Thank you. Thank you.
Everything was okay?
- Everything was fine, thank you.
- Very fine. Thank you, Rose.
Guys, I'm not so sleepy anymore.
Let's get the hell out of here.
ls this the Uris residence?
Is Stan there?
This is Mike Han/on, an old friend.
What are we supposed to do now?
Hey, spaghetti man, no problem.
A little soap, a little elbow grease
ought to clean it right up.
Why are we the only ones
that can see this?
Well now, there you've got me stumped.
Let's ask the answer man. Oh, Mike?
Oh, Michel...
Garg:on?
Hold on just a sec. Hello, Stan?
Mike Hanlon.
Is this the Uris residence?
I'm trying to get ahold of Stan Uris.
You tell that loser that if he hasn't
left already, he's a dead man.
We all managed to show up.
Boy, that matches your real hair.
Has anyone ever told you...
ls anyone from out of town?
I don't know about you.
ljust flew in from LA, boy, and...
Boy, is my tail section tired.
Yeah, not a chance. We're hot tonight.
It's great to be back in Derry,
breathing in that old Derry air.
I have never felt so much love in one
room in my entire life.
Eddie, get all their names
I wanna put them on my Christmas mailer.
No, Denbrough there, let's put him
on my Norman Mailer!
I love this man.
He's like the brother I never had.
Wait a minute.
He is the brother I never had.
Beep, beep, Richie. Stan?
Thank you.
Stan is dead.
He cut his wrists in the bathtub
right after I phoned him.
Stan was the last one of us to see lt
that summer.
Remember?
All summer long he kept saying,
"Thatjust isn't empirically possible."
Even seeing the clown
didn't make it real for him.
Nothing did.
Until that afternoon in August.
I remember
I was coming down Chestnut Street
and I saw Stan running through the park
like something was after him.
YOUNG STAN LEYI G0!
- Go!
- Hi yo, Silver. Away!
I can't honestly say
I saw anything that day.
Stan's the one who saw it.
I was pedaling too fast to turn around.
I didn't want to see it. Whatever it was.
It took him hours to calm down enough
to tell me what happened.
He said he was down
in Lampkin Park by a bird feeder.
Watching birds.
Like a good Boy Scout.
Remember? He used to call it
"collecting birds
PENNYWISEI Stan...
Stan...
He said he didn't mean
to go into that house,
but this voice kept whispering to him.
And naturally, being Stan, he figured
there was a rational explanation.
Hello?
PENNYWISEI Stanley.
Yeah? I'm right here.
He was trapped.
The only thing he could think of to do
was to hold his bird book out
in front of him like a shield
and say as loud as he could the names
of all the birds he could remember.
Longneck finch...
Speckled grouse, Baltimore oriole...
Great egret, hammerhead Woodpecker
and brown thrush.
Brown thrush.
The day that we went into the sewer
Stan saw lt.
Face to face.
Not the clown,
but he saw what was behind the clown.
He ran up to me in school and he said,
"l saw It, Eddie.
"L looked right into its..."
Some kind of lights.
"L looked right into its deadlights."
Then he said,
and I hadn't thought of it until just now,
I swear, he said,
"l looked into its deadlights
and I wanted to be there."
Deadlights.
- I need a drink.
- Yeah, me, too.
I'm sure I've got something here.
Anybody else?
Yeah.
Stan!
Sorry, I'm late.
Well, let's see who's here.
Billy-boy!
Richie, you still here?
We never expected you to stick around.
Nice nose job. No one would ever suspect.
Haystack, putting on a little weight, huh?
Speaking of dads, Bevy,
yours isn't worried about you anymore.
He loves your choice in men.
Wheezy, how's your sex life?
What's your sex life?
Well, Mikey, you did it.
You got us all back here.
I guess it's 'cause it's
the only way you'd ever see us
since you're so lame
you'd never leave this town.
I finally made it, guys.
I'm in the deadlights now.
And you know what?
It's true what they say.
We all float down here and you will, too.
In fact, they all float!
They all float!
My God!
All right.
I don't know about the rest of you,
I'm getting real sick of this place.
Now I'll listen to anything anybody has to
say, but could we do it someplace else?
Please!
Okay. Just help me with the stuff.
Bill.
What is it?
"He thrusts his..."
"He thrusts his fists against the post
and still insists he see the ghosts."
That's all it says over and over
and over again.
My mom gave me that to say
to help with my stutter.
No offense, pal, it ain't helping.
Let's get the hell out of here.
What do you say?
Henry!
Down here.
Belch? What are you doing down there?
You got a problem in there
you need some help with, Henry?
That's a good boy.
You don't
have to talk out loud, Henry.
I can hear you when you just think it
and they can't hear me at all.
- What do you want?
- Same thing you want.
I want to pay them back.
Yeah, pay them back.
But you're gonna have to get out of here.
You're gonna have to go back to Derry.
I need you,
Henry. We all need you.
They can't hurt you.
We didn't think they could hurt us back
then either, but they did, didn't they?
- Bested you all summer.
- Don't talk about that.
I can take care of them
if they only half believe.
But you, you're alive, Henry.
You can get them
no matter if they believe,
half believe or don't believe at all.
One by one, Henry.
I can't get out of here.
They got wires on the windows,
and Koontz is on the door tonight.
Man, Koontz is the worst.
I hate him.
I'll take care of Koontz, Henry.
Lead the way, Henry.
Lead the way.
All right, dog meat, I've had it.
Your head's
gonna be bouncing off the floor--
No, no, no, Mike. No, no, no.
I will have no need of this stuff, Mike.
Thank you very much for thinking
about me and including itjust in case.
But none for me, thank you very much!
- Richie, you're shouting.
- What? I know!
Beep, beep, Richie. Beep, beep.
Talk to us, Mike. Tell us stories.
Tell us things so we don't have to
remember what we just saw in the library.
Hey, Eddie. Come on, pal.
Don't let it get you. Fight it.
I saw myself today.
I saw myself back there.
I know it's just camphor water,
I know that, but I need it anwvay.
Take it easy, pal.
If it works, Eddie, it's good medicine.
You've always believed in it,
-that's all that ever mattered.
- Thanks.
I'm sure by now you all remember
what was going on in Derry 30 years ago.
There was a rash of killings, maimings,
disappearances, mostly of children.
Everybody was afraid,
but nobody did anything.
Until we went after lt.
We almost killed It.
Henry Bowers confessed to everything
and the killings stopped.
Until earlier this year,
exactly 30 years later.
Now, the first thing you should know is,
if you count backwards
in 30-year increments,
every date you come to will correspond
to a huge disaster in Derry's history.
In 1960, the big fire
at the Black Spot Club.
In 1930, the explosion
down at the old ironworks.
In 1900, the massacre at Drake's Creek.
And on, and on.
The biggest mystery is how 253 settlers
just disappeared without a trace.
Thank you, Michael, for that illuminating,
if somewhat morbid, history.
She didn't want to know.
You knew all about this, even then.
Miss Douglas didn't want to know.
It's a disease, Bev.
The Derry disease.
None of them wants to know.
-It's too horrible so they act like--
- They act like it didn't even happen.
I remember a man, Mr. Ross,
he was on his front porch,
I was coming home from school.
Henry Bowers was waiting
right outside my house.
I saw Mr. Ross across the street.
He looked so concerned,
I thought he was going to help me,
but I couldn't believe it,
he just turned around and went inside.
That was when it really hit me
there was something
terribly wrong in Derry, with Derry.
How did you get out of that, Bev?
Daddy came home, one of the only times
I was ever really glad to see him.
So, it's 30 years later and right
on schedule the killings start up again.
Six so far, maybe more.
There have been a number of disappearances
with no trace of a body.
I wanted to be absolutely certain
before I called anyone.
And I became absolutely certain
when I found something
at the latest crime site.
God, that was just yesterday.
Anwvay, this is it.
Georgie?
For whatever reason,
there's something
very special about us being together.
We found each other that summer
and our togetherness made us strong.
Otherwise, lt would have picked us off,
one by one.
Think about it.
Is it an accident
that none of us have kids?
Including Stan.
Or that when we came together
as young people,
we were all losers.
Now look at you.
Six of you left Derry
and became unusually successful.
Big-time breadwinners.
Leaving you here holding the bag.
Yeah. You kept the lighthouse
for the rest of us.
I feel like a real jerk about that, Mike.
Me, too.
It's nobody's fault.
Our parents decided
who stayed and who went.
When I grew up, I stayed here
because I wanted to.
I think you stayed because you had to.
I don't know what's gonna happen
when the sun comes up,
but I do know that I appreciate
what you've done for everyone.
- Good evening. You're up late.
- How much farther is Derry?
Oh...
I guess about maybe
500 yards to the city limits.
Oh, thank God.
I nearly fell asleep a while ago.
I feel like I've been driving forever.
Just cross the old bridge down there
at the barrens and hang a left.
The barrens?
Yes, where
they used to play when they were kids.
Thank you. I'll be going now.
Don't you want your balloon first,
Mrs. Denbrough?
Don't you want it?
They chased me up the hall,
past the lockers,
they got me down
and they started slapping me.
The coach found me lying there,
I was crying,
and I thought he was gonna help me.
But instead, he just made fun of rne
and something inside snapped. I got mad.
I said, "Coach, you coach track, right?"
He sort of sneered at me and nodded,
and I said,
"Well, you listen to me,
you stone-brained son of a bitch,
"l'm gonna go out for
the track team in March
"and I'm gonna run down
everything you got.
"L'm gonna run down your best
"and then
I want a flipping apology from you."
All right.
And so you did it?
Yeah, I ran everwvhere.
Sometimes, my heart felt like it was
pounding so hard I was gonna pass out.
And the first time I ran a mile,
I puked, then fainted.
Finally, I was holding up
my pants as I ran.
I mean, I ate salads
like there was no tomorrow.
By March, I'd lost 70 pounds
and I'd grown two inches.
Every time I ran, I felt like I could fly.
- And you went out?
- I went out for track just like I said.
First day I was out there
I won the 220 and the 440.
I just blew away the coaches. Best guys.
After practice,
I walked right up to the coach
and I asked for that apology.
He was so furious, he hit me.
- No! After all that--
- It was perfect!
- You beat him!
- And everybody knew it.
I graduated from El Paso High
with a letter in track.
And the coach lost his job
over that little love tap.
That's great, Ben.
You ought to write that one down.
- Bill's our writer.
- I just write horror stories.
You know, we still haven't talked
about what we're going to do,
ifwe're gonna do anything.
On, Mikey, Mikey, Mikey...
Listen, kids.
This campfire stuff is fun, it really is,
but it doesn't matter how painstakingly
we go over these sewer plans
or how many damn flashlights
or helmets you got in that box.
When the sun comes up, I'm dust,
and lwould suggest that
the rest of you follow me
and get the hell out of Dodge!
- I cleaned it up once.
- Cleaned what?
The blood.
I cleaned the whole thing up
that very same night.
I decided if I was ever
going to sleep in this house again,
I'd have to know the truth.
To see if anyone besides me
could see the blood.
What happened in here?
Somebody get murdered?
You see it? You really see it?
Come on, let's clean this up.
Until that moment,
I thought I was going crazy.
It was so strange to be happy
about something so grim.
I fell in love with all of you guys
that day.
And after we cleaned it up,
the blood never came back.
It will be morning soon.
-L'm cold.
- Me, too.
- L'll get you something.
- There's a shawl in my room.
Give me your room key and I'll get it.
Richie, you have a key?
YOUNG BILL; All right. NOW, listen up.
Stay together, guys. No stragglers.
Just get the first thing you find.
I need to stretch my legs anwvay.
Ben.
- Don't go alone.
- Uh, I need a refill anwvay.
I'll join you.
I'll take care of Richie.
Okay. We meet back here in three minutes,
no more. Keep your doors open.
Hello, nigger. I'll pay you back.
I'm gonna pay you all back.
Oh, good. You found lt.
I'm glad we're alone for a minute.
I've been wanting to say something to you.
"Your hair is winter fire. January embers.
-"My heart burns there, too."
-lt was you.
I've been waiting a long time
to thank the poet.
- Did you ask Bill first?
- No.
I knew it was you.
I've always known it was you.
I think I must have been waiting, Ben,
waiting until we were both ready.
I'm ready now. Are you?
Oh, oh, Beverly.
Kiss me, fat boy!
Belch...
Mike! Mike!
Mike!
You all right?
lgot it.
- Get him in there.
- Give me a hand.
Watch it! Okay, easy.
-ln the car.
- Hurry up!
- Go!Go!Go!
- No, Mike!
If Mike dies,
there will be five of us left.
Who comes next? Which one of us?
Why is lt doing this?
Why does It hate?
Why is It so mean?
Oh, Ben.
I want to tell you something.
You remember what my father was like?
I fell in love with a man
who turned out to be everything
I always hated in my father.
Why would I do that?
How could I be so blind?
If you see it now,
you're not blind anymore, Bev.
Congratulations. That's a miracle.
Besides, at least you fell in love
with somebody.
At least you felt something.
That's a miracle, too.
You have the heart of a poet, Ben.
"Your hair is winter fire."
- Why did you say that?
- You wrote it, didn't you?
"Your hair is winter fire.
January embers." Something.
When lwas young, I thought it was Bill,
but it was you, wasn't it?
Damn it, Bev, is that you in there
or is that the clown?
I don't know what the hell is going on!
How am I supposed to know?
It's me.
"My heart burns there, too."
- Mike's gonna be okay.
- Can we see him?
He's not out of the woods yet.
I guess one of you could go in
forjust a minute.
Mike?
Everyone else is right outside.
- Henry?
- He's dead.
- Police?
- Not yet.
Be careful. We can't trust anyone.
If anybody asks, a party got out of hand.
You were dancing on the table,
you took a fall.
Anyone who's seen me dance will buy that.
- What are you going to do?
- I don't know, man.
I honestly do not know.
Myjacket. Outside pocket.
It's silver. ll' can kill ll'.
But we left these down in the...
You went back?
I was pretty sure lt was asleep.
"Pretty sure"?
You went alone?
Ten years ago my life was going downhill.
I was close to suicide.
I think I really wanted It
to wake up and kill me.
Took me all day
stumbling around in the dark.
I found one right away.
In the drain trap.
The other one, the one that hit Pennwvise,
was lodged in a crack in the wall.
I figured we might need that kind of help
again one day.
When I came out,
I kind of I got my life together.
The only change was this.
Almost overnight.
Fean
Bill.
If you decide not use those,
if you leave, I'll understand.
People, that is a dead body.
You're not seriously suggesting we walk
out of here and leave it lying there?
Yeah. That's what I'm suggesting.
- I think we ought to call the police.
- I think Eddie's right.
You don't understand. This whole town
is It in some way. All of them.
Bill's right.
Ifwe call the police,
get the town involved,
something bad's going to
happen to one of us.
Maybe all of us.
All right. Have it your way. Stan is dead.
Mike came close. I've seen enough.
I'm with you, boy.
You can put this behind you
just like that?
I'm a little old
for monster hunting, Bill.
So was Mike.
So was Stan.
- Is that how you feel, Ben?
- I don't know how I feel.
All I know is, I can't stay
in this room much longer.
So I suggest we just turn on the TV,
hang a "Do not disturb" sign on the door,
go outside, then figure out what to do.
I second that.
Police Chief Andrew Rademacher
of the downtown branch said the victim,
5-year-old Danielle Huxton,
had been playing
at the creek near her home.
Local authorities have not yet said
whether there might be a connection
between this and a recent rash of
disappearances involving young children.
They did reveal, however,
that the body was severely mutilated.
In other news tonight,
a series of robberies in the east end
has local officials baffled...
Appreciate it if you just
put that on my card, send me a receipt.
- Oh, certainly, Mr. Hanscom.
- Me, too, thank you.
- Ditto, thanks.
- Nice time, loads of fun. Got to go, bye.
Need a ride, Bill?
- Where are you going, Richie?
- Airport.
- I guess we are, too, Bill.
- Come with us.
Ijust saw something
and I have no idea if it was real.
If any of you would have seen it or not.
I can't go.
Because if I do, I'm gonna
live with this until I go insane.
Until I can't tell the difference
between my life and my bad dreams.
For years I've been getting paid
to scare people.
But I'm the one who's been scared.
All my life.
I don't want to be scared anymore.
I'm going back in.
This time I'm gonna kill It.
Help me!
Please, help me.
I don't suppose anybody thought
to bring anything really useful,
like a machine gun?
I brought this. It's the only thing
I saved from those days.
- I remember you were a dead shot, Bev.
- You couldn't miss.
It was like it was supposed
to be Bev, remember?
You hit the clown, Pennwvise,
in the head, it broke open.
- And underneath it was a light.
- Bright lights.
Deadlights. We saw them, too,
for a second.
Bev?
- Bill, how on earth...
- Mike went back down and got them.
These are for him and for Stan.
- Lucky seven.
- We're all here now.
Oh, come on, guys. What the hell are you
going to do now? Sing Kumbaya?
Wake up. Take a breath. Do you smell that?
That's death.
It's not for Mike, it's not for Stan,
it's not for Henry Bowers.
It's for us. It's in the air.
Losers fight It, losers die.
And you know that, don't you, Captain?
- You don't have to go down there, Richie.
- Right.
I didn't have to get on a plane in LA,
I didn't have to go to the dinner,
I sure as hell didn't have to come here.
And now I don't have to go in.
I still say we should have brought
a machine gun.
I remember the first thing I saw down here
was one of those damn pom-poms.
- This purse looks new.
- Oh, dear God. It's not possible.
- Audra.
- What?
How in God's name--
She's down here.
- His wife?
-lt's got her.
- How could she...
-lt could be a trick or something.
Bill, wait, damn it!
Audra!
Audra. Audra.
- Bill.
- Come back, Bill!
- Do you want to get yourself killed?
- Oh, God, Bill!
BENZ God, Bill, you all right?
It's my fault. She followed me.
- I told her--
- Bill, that's enough!
If she is down here,
there's only one way you can help her.
Now you know what we came down here for
and we're going to do it.
Now, we need you. We need you
to stand up for us like before,
or none of us is going to get out of here.
Come on.
Stay close together.
- Looks like we're off the map.
- I think...
That way.
We're here.
- The roots all grow down.
- Yeah.
- Yeah, the walls cracked, remember?
- When It came.
Dear God, please don't let these things
come to life.
Don't you even think that, spaghetti man.
I told you not to call me "spaghetti man."
I think something is coming.
- My boat.
- Georgie.
It's all your fault.
Oh... Georgie.
All yourfault, Bill.
You sent me out and lt killed me.
N0. N0, Georgie. I didn't know.
Bill, remember, that's not Georgie.
Remember. Fight it!
It was in the drain, Bill.
It was in the drain.
And you let It kill me.
No. l loved you.
Damn it, Bill,
that thing's not your brother.
- Come on, man.
- Fight it.
You are not George.
George is dead,
and it's not my fault.
You killed my brother, George,
you bastard.
Let's see you now.
Show yourself.
You killed my little brother
and now you're going to pay.
Go while you still can.
This is your last chance.
Show yourself.
Silly boy.
You still think you can see me.
You'll never see me.
You'll see only
what your little mind can allow.
Go! Now.
For if you stay,
you'll lose your little mind
in my deadlights.
Like all the others.
Bill. We can't fight that thing.
That's like trying to fight smoke.
Don't you understand
what Mike was trying to tell us?
It feeds, Richie.
It wakes up every 30 years and it feeds.
And in order to feed, it has
to take on some kind of physical form.
It's here.
Down here. Somewhere.
Fee, fi, f0, fum.
- You think we're strong enough?
- We have to be.
I have to tell you guys something
before we go in there.
- Eddie?
- Yeah.
-l've been lying.
- About what?
When I said that I was seeing someone.
Well, I'm not. In fact, I haven't ever...
I mean, I've never even been with any...
Eddie, what are you saying?
You're a virgin?
Yeah.
Well, I can't help you with that, pal.
But thanks for sharing.
Richie, let him talk.
You see...
I could never sleep
with somebody that I didn't love.
And I've never really loved anyone.
Except you 9W5-
H9)'-
Oh, my God.
A body.
Audra.
- Bill, for God's sake!
- Wait for us, buddy.
It's Audra. I'm going to get her.
Bill...
I damn you to hell.
Please, dear God!
"He thrusts his fists against the posts,
"and still insists he sees the ghosts."
It's taking him. Bill!
Come on, guys! We got to--
Bev! Bev, where are you going? Bev...
Bev...
What am I going to do?
This is battery acid, you slime!
I believe in Santa Claus.
I believe in the Easter Bunny.
I believe in the Tooth Fairy.
But I don't believe in you.
This is battery acid. Now you disappear.
Please, God, don't let me miss again.
BENZ Eddie? Eddie.
Hey...
Nice shot, Bev.
Don't you talk. Don't talk.
You're gonna be fine, spaghetti man.
Richie, please...
For the last time, don't call me that.
You know how I...
Eddie.
This isn't over.
If that thing comes back when I'm 70...
Let's finish lt. Once and for all.
Audra.
It's all coming down.
I guess that's how
I'd like to remember us,
if I could remember us.
Standing there by the lake
with the sun going down on our childhood.
This will be my last entry.
I got it in just in time.
Just before the fog in my brain
swept all of my memories away entirely.
Now, just weeks later,
I look back on that time
not from memory,
but from the pages of this book.
The nightmare is over.
What little police involvement there was
was brief and cursory.
As is always the case here in Derry.
Now that there's no further need
for a lighthouse keeper...
Well, I feel I may move on,
see whatever's down the road apiece.
As of this writing,
Richie's still knocking them dead.
He's got a pan' in a movie.
574. Take 18, mark.
He costars with another comic,
a guy any of the lucky seven
could have told you
looks and acts a lot like Eddie Kaspbrak.
And cut.
Ben and Bev left Derry together,
headed west.
After a week, they were married.
A few weeks later, they were pregnant.
Another curse broken.
Bill and Audra are still here.
I wish the news were better.
But Audra 's condition is unchanged.
They're leaving today.
Okay, Audra. It's time to go.
Bill thought the time here,
the time away from his work,
might somehow help.
But I guess Audra 's gone for good.
One of It's many casualties.
Locked in that haunted place
where she saw Its deadlights.
Bill has been good to visit every day.
We laugh about our failing memories.
We sometimes have to ask
each other's names now.
His sadness is profound.
I wish there was something I could do.
Something I could have done.
Hi yo, Silver. Away!
Wait.
Audra, this bike saved
little Stan's life once. Mine, too.
We were going so fast,
I think we beat the devil.
I don't know if I can go that fast again.
Hold on.
Beat it.
Beat it. Beat it. Beat it, Audra.
Beat it. Beat it.
Come on. Come on.
- Bill?
- Yes.
- Bill, where are we? What are we doing?
- Yes, it's okay.
It's okay. Hang on.
Just hang on, babe, it's okay.