(CUTLERY CLATTERING)
(PEOPLE MURMURING INDISTINCTLY)
WOMAN: Who do you think
they are to each other?
MAN: Hm...
I don't know.
WOMAN: Yeah, this is a hard one.
MAN: I think the white guy
and the Asian girl are a couple,
and the Asian guy is her brother.
WOMAN: Or the Asian girl
and the Asian guy are a couple,
and the white guy is their American friend.
MAN: They are not even
talking to the white guy.
WOMAN: Maybe they are tourists,
and the white guy is their tour guide.
MAN: Drinking at 4:00 a.m.?
WOMAN: Yeah, you're right,
that makes no sense.
MAN: Hm. Maybe they're all just colleagues?
WOMAN: I have no idea.
(CARS HORNS HONKING)
(NA YOUNG SNIFFLES)
(BOY IN KOREAN)
(SOBS SOFTLY)
(BLUES MUSIC PLAYING) (BOOKS THUDDING)
(DOOR CLOSES)
(NA YOUNG'S MOM SPEAKING)
(NA YOUNG SPEAKING)
NA YOUNG: Hm?
(NA YOUNG'S MOM SPEAKING)
(INDISTINCT CHATTER)
(NA YOUNG SPEAKING)
HAE SUNG: (IN KOREAN) Ah,
I'm thinking two things...
I want you to draw a tree.
NA YOUNG: Tree? That's what I'm good at.
(GIGGLING)
A tree doesn't have feelers.
(NA YOUNG'S MOM SPEAKING)
(NA YOUNG'S MOM CHUCKLING, THEN SPEAKING)
(NA YOUNG SPEAKING)
(CHILDREN CHATTERING) (MACHINERY CREAKING)
(RAIN PATTERING)
(CAMERA SHUTTER CLICKS)
(YOUNG HAE SUNG'S MOM SPEAKING)
(NA YOUNG GIGGLING)
(CHILDREN CHATTERING)
(CAMERA SHUTTER CLICKS)
(YOUNG HAE SUNG'S MOM SPEAKING)
(CHUCKLES)
(YOUNG HAE SUNG LAUGHING)
(YOUNG HAE SUNG CONTINUES SPEAKING)
(CREAKING)
(NA YOUNG'S MOM SPEAKING)
(CHILDREN CONTINUE CHATTERING)
(NA YOUNG GIGGLING)
(MELLOW MUSIC PLAYING)
(BIRDS CHIRPING)
(YOUNG HAE SUNG CHATTERING) (BOTH GIGGLING)
(BOTH LAUGHING) (YOUNG HAE SUNG EXCLAIMS)
HAE SUNG: (IN KOREAN)
It looks all same to me.
Black barks and white... NA
YOUNG: (IN KOREAN) What is it?
HAE SUNG: (IN KOREAN)
This is called "blue".
(LAUGHING)
(IN KOREAN) This is called "yellow".
(SQUEALS PLAYFULLY)
(CAT MEOWING)
(CHILDREN CHATTERING INDISTINCTLY)
(STUDENTS SPEAKING IN KOREAN)
(GIRL GIGGLING)
(DISTANT CHILDREN YELLING EXCITEDLY)
(INDISTINCT CHATTERING CONTINUES)
(CHEERFUL MUSIC PLAYING OVER RADIO)
NA YOUNG: (IN ENGLISH) Hello.
SI YOUNG: Hello.
NA YOUNG: My name is
Nora, what's your name?
SI YOUNG: My name is Michelle.
NA YOUNG: How are you, Michelle?
SI YOUNG: I'm fine, and you?
NA YOUNG: I'm fine, and you?
SI YOUNG: (CHUCKLING) I'm fine, and you?
I'm fine, and you?
I'm fine, and you? (CHUCKLING)
I'm fine, and you? I'm fine, and you?
I'm... (BOTH GIGGLING)
ANNOUNCER: Toronto Pearson
International Airport...
(ANNOUNCER REPEATING IN FRENCH)
(CHATTERING INDISTINCTLY)
ANNOUNCER: Toronto Pearson International...
(IN KOREAN)
(YOUNG NORA'S DAD SPEAKING)
(IN ENGLISH) This is from Korea.
This is our passport, and...
(CHILDREN CHATTERING AND YELLING)
BOY: Whoa!
(SCHOOL BELL RINGING)
(CROWS CAWING)
(MELLOW MUSIC PLAYING)
MAN (IN ENGLISH): I mean,
there is so much in it that I responded to.
But the one phrase that
sticks with me most...
Mm-hmm. "The long journey of rotting".
WOMAN: I liked it too.
We liked how you used the long pauses.
(NORA IN KOREAN)
(NORA'S MOM SPEAKING)
(NORA SPEAKING)
(CHUCKLING)
NORA'S MOM: Hm?
Hm...
NORA'S MOM: Uh...
(KEYBOARD CLACKING)
(SIGHS)
(NORA'S MOM SPEAKING)
(CHUCKLES)
(CHUCKLING)
NORA: Um...
(IN ENGLISH) Oh, shit.
(TYPING UNCERTAINLY)
(NORA SPEAKING)
(MAN 1 SPEAKING IN KOREAN)
(MAN 2 AGREEING)
(MAN 1 SPEAKING)
(MAN 3 GRUMBLING)
(MAN 4 SPEAKING)
(MAN 2 CHUCKLING DRUNKENLY)
(SIGHING)
(MAN 2 CHUCKLES)
(CHUCKLING)
MAN 1: Hm.
(MAN 1 MURMURING INDISTINCTLY)
(SOBBING) MAN 1: Hey.
(MAN 1 SPEAKING)
(PHONE RINGING) (MAN 2 SPEAKING)
(MAN 4 SPEAKING)
(MAN 3 SNIFFLING)
(MAN 3 CONTINUES SOBBING)
(SIGHS SLEEPILY)
(GROANS)
(PHONE VIBRATING)
(GRUNTS)
(EXHALES)
HAE SUNG: Huh?
(CHUCKLES)
(HAE SUNG'S MOM SPEAKING)
(SIGHING)
(HAE SUNG GRUNTS)
(CUTLERY CLANGING)
(GRUNTS SOFTLY)
Hm.
(UPBEAT MUSIC PLAYING)
(PHONE VIBRATES)
(DISTANT SIREN WAILS) (INDISTINCT CHATTER)
(CAR HORN HONKS)
(KEYS CLATTER)
(BACKPACK THUDS)
(COMPUTER CHIMES)
(CALL RINGING)
(CHIMING)
(DINGS)
(NORA CHUCKLES AND GASPS)
(CHUCKLES) (NORA SPEAKING)
HAE SUNG: Whoa. (LAUGHS)
(HAE SUNG SPEAKING)
(NORA SPEAKING)
(HAE SUNG CHUCKLES)
Oh...
(NORA SPEAKING)
Hm.
NORA: (CHUCKLES) Oh...
Hm-mm.
(HAE SUNG SPEAKING)
(NORA SPEAKING)
(GASPS PLAYFULLY)
(HAE SUNG CHUCKLES)
(LAUGHING)
Hm.
Hm...
(NORA SIGHS)
Huh?
(NORA CHUCKLES SOFTLY)
(CHUCKLES)
(MELLOW MUSIC PLAYING)
(HAE SUNG SPEAKING)
(NORA SPEAKING)
(DISTANT SIRENS WAILING)
(HAE SUNG LAUGHING)
Mm. (HAE SUNG CHUCKLES)
HAE SUNG: Hm.
Hm...
NORA: Hm.
(HAE SUNG CHUCKLES)
(BOTH SIGH)
(CRACKLING)
(BREATHES DEEPLY)
(HAE SUNG CHUCKLES)
NORA: Hm.
(COMPUTER BEEPS)
(UPBEAT MUSIC PLAYING)
(KEYBOARD CLACKING)
(NORA SPEAKING OVER COMPUTER)
(HAE SUNG CHUCKLES)
(HAE SUNG SPEAKING)
(HAE SUNG LAUGHING)
(NORA CHUCKLES)
Hm...
(CHUCKLES)
(HAE SUNG CHUCKLES)
(GASPS) (HAE SUNG LAUGHS)
(IN ENGLISH) Eternal Sunshine
of the Spotless Mind.
(IN KOREAN)
PATRICK: (IN ENGLISH) What did I do?
I love you so much.
I'll do anything to make you happy.
Tell me what you want
me to do and I'll do it.
(NORA CONTINUES SPEAKING)
(HAE SUNG REPLYING)
(NORA MUNCHING OVER COMPUTER)
(GREETS IN MANDARIN)
(BOTH LAUGHING)
(NORA SPEAKING)
(HAE SUNG SPEAKING)
(WIND WHOOSHING OVER LAPTOP)
(CALL RINGING)
(BEEPS)
(HAE SUNG SPEAKING)
(NORA SPEAKING)
(IN KOREAN) Have you done your homework?
(IN KOREAN) I haven't.
You have to do it for graduation.
I got under academic
probation last semester.
(CELLPHONE RINGING)
Hm-mm. Class captain's message.
Let me see your homework.
Maybe next time.
(HAE SUNG SPEAKING)
HAE SUNG'S FRIEND: Oh. Huh?
What's your plan for weekend?
Playing games.
(CALL RINGING)
(BEEPS)
(HAE SUNG SPEAKING)
(BREATHES SHAKILY)
(SOBBING SOFTLY)
(BREATHES DEEPLY)
(BEEPS)
(MELANCHOLIC MUSIC PLAYING)
(EARPHONES CLATTER)
(CLUCKING)
(TAXI DRIVES AWAY)
(WINDCHIMES CHIMING SOFTLY)
(BIRDS CHIRPING)
(DRAWER OPENS)
(TRAIN RUMBLING)
MAN: Are you okay? We walked around a lot.
WOMAN: My leg is a bit hurt, but I'm okay.
- MAN: This leg hurt?
- WOMAN: It's okay.
Rock, paper, scissor. No, thanks.
(ANNOUNCER SPEAKING OVER PA SYSTEM)
(DOOR OPENS)
(INDISTINCT CHATTER)
(HAE SUNG'S FRIEND 1 SPEAKING)
(ALL LAUGHING)
(HAE SUNG'S FRIEND 2 SPEAKING)
(CAR APPROACHING)
(BIRDS CHIRPING) (INSECTS CHITTERING)
(DOOR OPENS)
(FOOTSTEPS APPROACHING)
(CUP CLINKS)
(BIRDS CONTINUE CHIRPING)
(INSECTS CONTINUE CHITTERING)
Hi.
NORA (IN ENGLISH): Hi! I'm Nora.
I'm Arthur. Nice to meet you.
NORA: When'd you get in?
This morning.
- NORA: You got the worst room.
- (CHUCKLING) Right?
I know.
(MELLOW MUSIC PLAYING)
(BIRDS CONTINUE CHIRPING)
(ANNOUNCER 1 SPEAKING
INDISTINCTLY OVER PA SYSTEM)
(PA SYSTEM BEEPS)
(ANNOUNCER 2 SPEAKING
KOREAN OVER PA SYSTEM)
(CARS PASSING)
NORA: (IN ENGLISH) There
is a word in Korean.
In-Yun.
It means "providence".
Or... "fate".
(INDISTINCT CONVERSATION)
NORA: But it's specifically
about relationships between people.
I think it comes from...
Buddhism.
And reincarnation.
It's an "in-yun" if two strangers
even walk by each other in the street
and their clothes accidentally brush.
Because it means there must
have been something between them
in their past lives.
If two people get married
they say it's because
there have been 8000 layers of in-yun.
Over 8000 lifetimes.
(INDISTINCT CHATTER)
(CRICKETS CHIRPING)
You believe in that?
Believe what?
That...
You and I knew each other in another life.
What, because we are sitting here...
(BOTH CHUCKLING) At the same table,
in the same city,
- at the same time?
- Mm-hmm.
Yeah, wouldn't that make this...
In-yun?
Hm...
Mm-mm. Mm.
That's just something Koreans
say to seduce someone.
(CHUCKLES SOFTLY)
(AIRCRAFT WHOOSHING)
(ANNOUNCER SPEAKING
INDISTINCTLY OVER PA SYSTEM)
Hi. Hi.
IMMIGRATION OFFICER: Where you going?
New York City.
IMMIGRATION OFFICER:
Why're you going there?
We live there.
IMMIGRATION OFFICER:
What's your occupation?
Writers.
IMMIGRATION OFFICER: You're what?
We're writers.
IMMIGRATION OFFICER: How long
were you visiting Toronto?
Ten days.
IMMIGRATION OFFICER:
What was the purpose of your visit?
We were visiting her family.
IMMIGRATION OFFICER: Are you two related?
We're married.
Thanks!
(DOOR OPENS)
(MELLOW MUSIC PLAYING)
(TRUCK HORN BLARING)
ACTRESS: "If you bought a
ticket to see this show,
"took the subway or a cab to be here,
"it cost you something to be here,"
"and spend a couple hours
with these old women,"
"that makes you some kind of immigrant.
"And all this cost me something too.
"I crossed the Pacific Ocean to be here.
"Some crossings cost more than others."
"Some crossings you pay
for with your whole life."
(ARTHUR SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY)
ARTHUR: Sit most of the
day, and in the end I...
And then I started to write about...
After Dinner.
Um, yeah, I mean, it's my kind of time.
Uh, but you're studying, right?
(MAN SPEAKING INDISTINCTLY)
(ARTHUR IN KOREAN)
NORA: (IN ENGLISH) Me, too.
I don't know.
(ARTHUR SIGHS)
(CHUCKLES)
(ARTHUR KISSING) (SIGHING SOFTLY)
(ARTHUR SIGHS)
You know what I want? What?
Chicken wings.
Holy shit.
- Mm-hm. Yeah.
- (GRUNTING)
Oh, genius.
- Mm-hmm.
- Yes.
Chicken wings!
Hm... (KISSES)
What're you thinking about?
Remember I told you about Hae Sung?
Oh, yeah.
Is that this week?
Yeah.
Why is he coming here again?
I think vacation.
(IN KOREAN)
(HAE SUNG SPEAKING)
(HAE SUNG'S FRIEND 1 SPEAKING)
(HAE SUNG'S FRIEND 2 SPEAKING)
(HAE SUNG SPEAKING)
(HAE SUNG'S FRIENDS LAUGHING)
(HAE SUNG'S FRIEND 2 SPEAKING)
(HAE SUNG'S FRIEND 1 SPEAKING)
(THUNDER RUMBLES)
HAE SUNG: (IN ENGLISH) Uh, trunk? Trunk?
(SIGHS)
(MELANCHOLIC MUSIC PLAYING)
(THUNDER RUMBLING)
(BIRDS CHIRPING)
(VEHICLES PASSING)
(EXHALES)
(NORA SPEAKING)
(CHUCKLES SOFTLY)
(IN KOREAN)
(CHUCKLING)
(NORA SOFTLY LAUGHS AND EXHALES)
(CHUCKLES)
(NORA LAUGHING SOFTLY)
(EXHALES)
(BOTH LAUGHING)
(NORA CONTINUES LAUGHING)
(HAE SUNG LAUGHS)
(NORA GASPS AND EXCLAIMS PLAYFULLY)
(NORA LAUGHING)
(NORA SPEAKING)
(HAE SUNG LAUGHS)
(HAE SUNG SPEAKING)
(BOTH EXCLAIMING)
(CONTINUE EXCLAIMING IN KOREAN)
(NORA LAUGHING)
(INDISTINCT ANNOUNCEMENT OVER PA SYSTEM)
(NORA SPEAKING)
(HAE SUNG SPEAKING)
(CHUCKLES)
(NORA SPEAKING)
(HAE SUNG SPEAKING)
(CAMERA SHUTTER CLICKING)
(NORA SPEAKING)
(CHUCKLES)
NORA: Hm.
(HAE SUNG SPEAKING)
(CHUCKLES SOFTLY)
(NORA LAUGHS)
(NORA SPEAKING)
(LAUGHING)
(CARNIVAL MUSIC PLAYING
FAINTLY ON CAROUSEL)
Hmm?
Hmm.
(IN ENGLISH) Hi. Hi, my love.
(SIGHS) How was it?
You were right.
I was?
Yeah.
He came here to see me.
(OBJECT THUDS)
(SIGHS)
It's so crazy to see
him be this grown-up man
with a normal job and a normal life.
He's so Korean.
He still lives with his
parents which is really Korean.
And he has all these really Korean views
about everything.
And I feel so not Korean when I'm with him.
But also,
in some way, more Korean?
(SCOFFS) It's so weird.
I mean, I have Korean friends,
but he's not, like, Korean-American.
He's Korean-Korean.
Is he attractive?
I think so.
He's really masculine in this way
that I think is so Korean.
Are you attracted to him?
I don't think so.
I don't know, I mean...
He was just this kid in my head
for such a long time.
And then he was just
this image on my laptop.
And now he's a physical person.
It's really intense,
but I don't think that that's attraction,
I think I just missed him a lot.
I think I miss Seoul.
Did he miss you?
I think he missed the 12-year-old crybaby
he knew a long time ago.
You were a crybaby?
Yeah.
Most of the time, he'd have to
just stand there and watch me.
When is he leaving, again?
The morning after tomorrow. Mm-hmm.
Are you mad?
No.
It feels like you are.
(SCOFFS) I don't have a right to be mad.
What do you mean? Of course you do.
No, I...
That guy flew 13 hours to be here.
I'm not gonna tell you
that you can't see him or something.
He's your childhood sweetheart.
And it's not like you're
gonna run away with him.
Are you?
Definitely. I'm gonna
throw away my life here
- and run away with him to Seoul.
- (CHUCKLES)
Do you even know me?
I'm not gonna miss my
rehearsals for some dude.
I know.
I know you.
(INDISTINCT CHATTER OVER TV)
(PHONE CLATTERS)
(TV TURNS OFF)
(CHUCKLING SOFTLY)
What?
I was just thinking about
what a good story this is.
The story of Hae Sung and me? Yeah.
I just can't compete.
What do you mean?
Childhood sweethearts who
reconnect 20 years later
only to realize they were
meant for each other.
We're not meant for each other.
I know.
In the story,
I would be the evil white American husband
standing in the way of destiny.
(LAUGHS)
Shut up.
What do you not like about it?
Our story's just so boring.
We met at an artists' residency.
Slept together because we
both happened to be single.
We realize we both live in New York, so
we move in together to save money on rent.
We got married so you could
get a green card. So...
Oh, you make it sound so romantic.
Right, that's what I'm saying.
I'm the guy you leave in the story
when your ex-lover comes to take you away.
He's not my ex-lover.
What if you met somebody else
at that residency?
What if there was another
writer from New York
who had also read all
the same books you had,
and watched all the same movies,
could give you useful notes on your plays,
and listen to you complain
about your rehearsals?
NORA: That's not how life works. I know.
Yeah.
But wouldn't you be laying here with him?
This is my life, and
I'm living it with you.
Are you happy with it?
Is this what you imagined for yourself
when you left Seoul?
When I was a 12-year-old?
Yeah. Is this what you
pictured for yourself?
Laying in bed in some
tiny apartment in the East Village
with some Jewish guy who writes books?
Is that what your parents wanted for you?
You're asking me if you, Arthur Zaturansky,
are the answer to my
family's immigrant dream?
Yeah. Wow.
(SIGHS)
This is where we ended up.
This is where I'm supposed to be.
ARTHUR: Okay.
NORA: What?
It's just that you make
my life so much bigger.
And I'm wondering if I do
the same thing for you.
NORA: You do.
(SOFT PIANO MUSIC PLAYING)
I'm just a girl from Korea, you know?
(CHUCKLES SOFTLY) Okay.
And you're forgetting the
part where I love you.
I don't forget that.
I have trouble believing it sometimes.
Do you know you only speak in Korean
when you talk in your sleep?
I do? Yeah.
You never sleep talk in English.
You only dream in Korean.
I didn't know that.
Yeah.
You never told me that.
Well, sometimes I think it's cute.
Sometimes, I don't know,
I guess I get scared.
Scared of what?
(SIGHS)
You dream in a language
that I can't understand.
It's like there's this whole place
inside of you where I can't go.
I think that's why I've
been trying to learn Korean,
even though I know it's annoying for you.
You want to understand
me when I'm dreaming?
Yeah.
I'm sure I'm just saying gibberish.
(SHIP HORN BLARING)
(NORA SPEAKING KOREAN)
(HAE SUNG SPEAKING)
(NORA SPEAKING)
(HAE SUNG DISMISSES)
(HAE SUNG SPEAKING)
(NORA SPEAKING)
NORA: Hm?
(HAE SUNG SPEAKING)
(NORA SPEAKING)
(HAE SUNG LAUGHING)
(HAE SUNG SPEAKING)
(NORA SPEAKING)
(LAUGHS)
(HAE SUNG SPEAKING)
(CHUCKLES)
(NORA SPEAKING)
(HAE SUNG SPEAKING)
(DOOR OPENS)
(DOOR CLOSES)
(NORA SPEAKING)
(INHALES AND CHUCKLES)
Um...
(CHUCKLES)
(IN ENGLISH) Uh, hi.
Nice to meet you, also.
(CHUCKLES)
(IN KOREAN)
(HAE SUNG CHUCKLES)
Uh...
(IN ENGLISH) Are you hungry?
Hm? Oh...
(IN KOREAN)
(IN ENGLISH) Ah, oh. Yes.
(ARTHUR SPEAKING KOREAN)
Uh...
Pasta?
(LAUGHS) Pasta? Yeah. You like pasta?
Yes. (CHUCKLES)
Okay. Okay.
Let's get pasta. Pasta.
What did you two do today?
Uh...
The Statue of Liberty.
You took the ferry.
Yes. Yeah.
It's, um, nice.
I've never been.
What? Really?
Yeah, I've never actually been there.
(IN KOREAN)
(IN ENGLISH) Have we seriously
never been there together?
(CHUCKLES) No.
HAE SUNG: When I was 24 year,
I, uh... Um...
Oh.
(IN KOREAN)
(IN ENGLISH) Yes. (CHUCKLES)
Oh, military service.
Right.
You know how Korean men
have mandatory military service?
Yeah, your dad talks about it. How was it?
You like it?
(IN KOREAN)
(IN ENGLISH) No. (LAUGHS)
Uh, but military and work, same.
Same?
(IN KOREAN)
(IN ENGLISH) Uh, you have, um...
You have a boss.
NORA: Hm.
(IN KOREAN)
(IN ENGLISH) There's no
overtime pay in Korea.
(IN KOREAN)
(BOTH CHUCKLE)
HAE SUNG (IN ENGLISH): It's, uh, very hard.
Hmm. Uh, work. Work is hard.
Hard physically or mentally?
(IN KOREAN)
(IN ENGLISH) Uh, yes. Uh, both.
Physical, very hard.
Uh, and, um... Hm. Mentally.
Mentally, I'm strong.
Mm! (ARTHUR CHUCKLES)
(IN KOREAN)
(HAE SUNG SPEAKING)
(CHUCKLES SOFTLY)
NORA: Mm.
Hm.
(CHUCKLES)
(NORA SPEAKING)
Hm.
(SCOFFS)
(SIGHS)
(CHUCKLING)
(NORA SPEAKING)
(BOTH LAUGHING SOFTLY)
(IN ENGLISH) He's talking about you.
(HAE SUNG SPEAKING KOREAN)
(NORA SPEAKING)
(BOTH CHUCKLE)
(LAUGHS)
(ALTERNATIVE MUSIC PLAYING
SOFTLY OVER SPEAKERS)
(HAE SUNG INHALES AND CHUCKLES)
(IN ENGLISH) I'm sorry we speak alone.
Uh, we will stop.
It's okay.
You haven't seen each other in a long time.
(ARTHUR CHUCKLES AND SIGHS)
I never thought I'd be a
part of something like this.
Hm?
Sitting here with you.
Do you know what in-yun?
Yeah. Nora told me about
it when we first met.
(CHUCKLES)
You and me.
(LAUGHS) Yeah. Yeah, you
and I are in-yun too.
(CHUCKLES) Right?
I'm really glad you came here.
It was the right thing to do.
(DOOR OPENS)
Mm. I'm gonna walk him to his Uber.
Okay.
Uh, nice to meet you.
Nice to meet you, too.
Uh, come visit me in Korea.
Definitely.
(WHISPERS) I'll be right back.
Okay.
(SIREN BLARING)
(IN KOREAN)
HAE SUNG: Hm.
(CAR APPROACHING)
Hm?
(CHUCKLES SOFTLY)
(MELANCHOLIC MUSIC PLAYING)
(SOBBING)
(CONTINUES SOBBING)