That was a long one. I don't suppose you can tell me how
it looks, can you? Unfortunately, I'm just the technician.
Your doctor will have results tomorrow. Would you like
some help too? Thank you very much. You're very good.
Yes, why do you call it? Does anyone else? Henry
Kessler? Please. Stage 4, kind of grey. Come on. That's
what they tell me anyway. What else like this to me
at? How much time do I have? Do you? Months. At best.
I still have a lot of work that needs to be
done. My advice? Retire? You know, at this stage,
everyone always searches for, only out. But sometimes
those who accept their fate have an easier time.
How is your time? What? Dying.
So your advice to me is to die easy.
Help! Hey! Help! Help!
I'd like to play a game.
Brown's a number of
dresses, clothes,
sticky fingers of yours.
I've had my eyes on you, and I do not like
what I see. Your job as a custodian is a
number one, sanitizing and sterilizing the
hospital, helping patients with white sickness.
There is a sin inside you that
needs to be inside. You have
the ability to not only save
your soul today, but your sight.
All you have to do is hook
the dial across the fire positions,
and you will live to see another
day. You have 60 seconds.
Help me!
I can't! I can't!
I can't! I can't! I can't!
Not you!
Hey!
Can I get a blueberry scone, please?
Thank you.
Henry, we were on the same cancer
support group. John Kramer, I remember you.
Hey, good to see you.
And you as well.
You look marvelous.
Thank you. I feel great.
Correct me if I'm wrong, but
you were in stage four pancreatic.
But now, four months later,
I mean complete remission.
It's a long story. I'd love to hear it.
You got a minute to tell me.
Sure. Sure.
So, I read about a
doctor, a specialist, a
doctor, a skin Peterson.
He offered a treatment.
It is a groundbreaking drug cocktail
combined with surgery. It's my wound.
I know it looks bad,
but it was totally worth it.
Yeah.
Is it available here?
No. No, no. The treatment's not available.
In the states, the medication
isn't approved by the FDA.
Tell it, it isn't approved by anybody.
I haven't seen them since
my treatment in Norway.
But this link is still good.
Hey, John.
Good luck, man. Okay?
I am. I'm rooting for you.
Thank you.
Take care.
Doctor, what exactly is the procedure?
Well, I'm the device circumstances,
and I'm a stimuli. Genus can be turned off.
Turned off. Make a note switch.
And you're targeting the cancer cells.
Exactly. What you managed to do
is to create a new cutting-edge drug
cocktail, along with virtually to
teach the malignant cells. Switch off.
My father, Dr. Finn Peterson,
was forced into hiding by
corrupt governments and their
relationship to big fun. Why?
Because my father was
on the cusp of curing dozens
of diseases, which means
no more need for life.
From medication, can you
imagine what that implies?
Well, the big drug
company certainly can. And
I'm here to say that
this just cannot stand.
So why do my father continues to
make further improvements to his formula?
I'm taking his treatment
on the road for more
trials to save as many
lives as humanly possible.
How is this?
This is Celia Peterson.
This is John Kramer.
Yes, it is.
Good. We received the
email with your medical
records, Mr. Kramer.
Thank you for reaching out.
I'm sick to three potential
candidates for our program.
So I'm pulling you now
because we have stopped
opening the treatment
in about three months.
Mr. Kramer?
Uh, he has a leader.
You don't have three months, do you?
Okay, listen. I am
currently working in
Mexico, also has
become too difficult for us.
But we have a team of specialists here who
share our belief in the Peterson method,
and I've gathered a group of eligible
patients who start treatment a week from now.
I think I could add one more
spot, if you are interested.
Yes, I'm interested.
Henry Kessler, referring me to you.
Henry, he's doing well. I'm so pleased.
I wonder if you could tell me a
little more about the treatment?
Of course. It's a
two-pronged treatment that
uses my father's
sexual phenol cocktail,
and in your case it would be combined
with a cranial surgery to clear the tumor.
When both are used together,
the results have been stunning.
Or a 90% success rate.
I know it's an old trip.
Mr. Kramer, especially in your condition.
But I want you to know
that we've found a very
beautiful location for our
clinic outside Mexico City.
It's in a well-of-the-grid
area in the
countryside where you
can have safety and privacy.
Also, of course, it's the range for
a trusted driver that you're arriving.
What date did you have in mind?
Fifth, right after next.
I think I could make that.
Yes? Yes.
Welcome to Mexico. Please. This way.
Take a look at that.
That's a much holy can cathedral.
That's too better from
a wish home memorial.
That's the angel of independence.
Take a look at that.
It's really beautiful.
So, hey, hey, that's my friend.
That's the old Aztec statue of flowers.
That's where the priests
chomped the hearts out
of their subjects and
pulled them downstairs.
Every day a tourist wants
me to take them here.
There he is.
Hey, Jay.
Okay?
You're listening to me.I
can't. I can't. My name. Tell.
your name? John Kramer.
Like to me again. I
left you this chamber in
July. I'm not lying, my
name is John Kramer.
You're fine. You're safe. Come with me.
Come, come. Here. Welcome. Watch your head.
You're room. Here. Come.
Sit here. Good luck.
See?
I am John Kramer.
Come. There you go.
Hi, Gabriela.
There you go.
Meet my family.
Come.
Hello.
I came back in here.
Doctor Cecilia Peterson.
I came.
She saved life.
My life.
I came. I came now.
Mr. Kramer.
Welcome.
That was quite a reception.
Did I go out on the way out here?
Oh, well, welcome.
I know. I'm sorry, but
we've had to beef up
the security where we go.
The big drug companies
are always one step behind.
So, we must keep our location
secret from everyone, leaving you.
Come. I want you to meet the team.
Hello.
Yes?
That's Carlos.
Our local football star.
His father, he's a kid, take it.
Love it.
Really?
This used to be a chemical
factory up in the day.
Hello, Doctor.
Is this Joe Kramer?
Very nice to meet you, Mr. Kramer,
and welcome to our clinic.
You're a very good hat for us.
I tell you, it isn't anesthesiologist
at hospital after Prado.
He is a residency at Tom's Health Kingston.
That's where you'll look with my father.
Yes.
We'll be helping out with
your surgery tomorrow.
Thank you.
I'll be right here, being here.
This is Valentina, one of our nurses.
She will be taking some
scans and drawing some blood.
All in preparation for that
injection therapy later today.
Mr. Sierz, we're good.
It's good for release.
Dr. Silly?
John Kramer?
Thorough cancer, advanced in brain.
You win.
Sorry, I'm here.
Call me home yesterday.
I took out a tumor the size of my dog.
I just had to stop the hotel.
You did it in natural killer cells.
There were a type of cytotoxic
lymphocytes developed by my father.
Good luck, John.
Thank you.
John, where are you?
Please don't worry.
So, Mr. Kramer, what do you do?
Like for a living?
John.
Please call me John.
And what do you do, John?
I've done a civil engineer at an architect.
Most of my life.
Now I have a few hobbies.
Let me get it.
Classic drug renovation.
No?
No.
I hope people will
overcome inner obstacles.
Help them make positive
changes in their lives.
Like life coach, yes?
Something like that.
Sounds not.
I don't think of anything more
important than helping others.
Yeah.
Thank you.
Very good, though.
Thank you, Gabriel.
No.
It's a local favorite.
You can't drink another,
not people's surgery.
My son says to rise again.
Yeah.
Your son is rising again, John.
We will make sure of it.
You speak English, Carlos?
Yeah?
That's about as good as my Spanish.
How do you say it, Paul?
Paul, Paul, Paul.
Hello.
Excellent.
Thank you.
I hope it forms the surgery.
Dr. Ruben Cortes, also a doctor of Prado.
He's the best you research in 2000 miles.
He's the doctor I have to use if
my own family was on the table.
Now, we'll be performing
an awake traniotomy.
This means that you'll
be floating in and out of
consciousness, so that
we can function like this.
It allows us to monitor your abilities, so
that we don't touch any part of your brain.
You did great.
Where are we?
We're two blocks away
from a Theo's hospital.
In case you need a transfusion.
That you have not worked.
Even though global is normal.
It all looks good, John.
It all looks good.
Now, drink two day.
One in the morning and one at night.
Okay.
In addition to my father's treatment,
it contains a painkiller you'll
need for the next seven days.
After that, what happens then?
You're a live puppet, isn't it?
I don't know, Ches, but I've got real life.
Where are you the oldest?
I'll send them your best.
Don't get your head wet.
The advantage is hand type by two.
It will stay out in place.
An antenna will swing by
to keep an eye on it for you.
There's some rest in our job.
All right.
Dr. Fusen, just so you know her.
I'll wear her the second half.
I have it to one more.
Thank you, John.
Have a good night, John.
A long, good night.
It's for a friend.
Hello?
Good night.
Okay, so, here we are,
this is the flow of statue,
okay, hello, what an
entrance, all in the house.
Out in the air, no.
I'd like to play a
game, attached to your
arms or two explosive
devices, pipe the bombs.
Cancer, a malignancy
that must be cut out for
you to survive, the
blades cannot cut through
the galvanized cable,
with the Cannon spliced
through the flesh and muscle allowing
you to cut the cancer away with or die.
A tweeze.
Cramer.
I can use your assistance in locating some
people that are in need of our services.
No, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no,
no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no,
no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no.
no, no, no, no, no, no,
no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no,
no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no
You said those medical records
in and we'll have a look, alright?
Perfect. See you soon Margaret.
See you soon. Oh, get it gone.
This is my sensory show, Amanda.
Celia.
you're going to fucking me.
who are you?
please.
please please
please please please.
why don't you try to help him.
that game is over.
Valentina.
didn't let blood ever make into the lab.
or.
could you just suck it out and
flush it down the drain somewhere.
we have nothing to do
with this we get her own, it's
going on and we'll solve her
She's glad the whole thing.
No, Taylor.
I don't even know if that's your real name.
It is my real name.
It is.
Oh.
I say you've never heard of you.
That's a hostel.
She told me to say that I
worked there for tonight.
Wait.
Mr. Kramer.
I meant them hard.
I would really like to believe you.
Gabrielle.
You'll have a chance to prove yourself.
The kid of your freedom is inside that box.
It's a jelly saw.
I thought you said there was a kid.
He was speaking metaphorically.
He does that a lot.
When I get out of here,
I'm going to kill both of them.
You want to fuck them?
That's a good plan.
You're going to want
to really listen carefully
to the rules in
order to pull that off.
Fuck you.
Go ahead.
The wire saw inside that box was invented
by an Italian physician, Leonardo, Julie.
It creates an extraordinarily
clean cut along.
The dotted line on your leg marks the spot.
Are you fucking Christian?
What means you think I
fucking get off my own leg?
Well, because if you don't,
the wire saw that's
wrapped around your neck.
will first cut into your
skin and your verbal
ligaments and finally
it'll sever your spinal cord.
A cleft-on's version?
You're right.
It's true.
We won't.
The Valentina, Mike.
All of you.
We promise dying people.
Dying people!
You could save their lives
and then doing so of you took
advantage of the only
thing that they still possess.
Oh.
No, don't.
We've worked to heal people.
Your case was...
different.
Then still you lie.
My associate Amanda here has
titled Look at your bank records.
Pickle up.
Who are those 34 people to you?
John's case was different.
Did you heal any of those 34 people?
Do they have children,
but they're now orphaned?
Even though this Larsen stands now
for more than the years, eight years.
That's one eight million dollars.
There's a lot of pain.
to inflict on others for
your own enrichment.
There was no healing going on their beds.
They're all underground.
I checked.
We know everything.
We have everything.
Including the cash from your house.
We have it upstairs.
Please.
Please don't do this.
Please, please kill me.
That's exactly what
we are doing, Valentina.
This is not retribution.
It's a real awakening.
Valentina, follow my
instructions if you want to live.
There are more than
five pounds of marrow in
the human body or you
need it's four ounces.
There's more than enough in your femur.
Just suction it out.
When they transfer to
that device right there.
And then deactivate
the fall around your neck.
Don't hesitate.
You should find this prescribed.
No.
Now refusing to play the game.
is not an option.
If you refuse,
you'll remain in this room.
Go around.
Let's stop right.
Please, please, please.
John!
Don't get me.
You have to do this.
No!
Don't do it.
Okay.
No, no, no, no, no, no, no, no.
Stop it down your leg.
Don't!
What?
Sometimes we get sucked into things that.
our kids are in nature
drugs are as vicious.
as they are powerful.
We all have free will.
We all have their own free will.
And if you can't handle this,
I'll be mad to the rest of our work.
And not to be.
Why don't we use the clues
to assign them your senses?
Yes, yes, yes, yes.
We need a vote.
Yes.
The pain.
It just comes in the waves.
Listen, I'm not ready
to do this without you.
You're ready.
You are ready.
And you can.
Listen again.
Don't touch her.
Don't touch me.
Right now I'm under these
people deserve to be tested.
That lady doctor deserves nothing.
Everyone deserves a chance.
And I'll pretend they ever do themselves.
You should know that boy or anyone.
What the fuck is that?
What are you doing?
What?
No?
Yeah.
Oh.
Find an egg.
Egg will get up by two.
But my father, Don, is real to you.
And you know that?
He can save you.
Is that you concern?
To you and me?
He can heal you.
I swear to God.
That's who I was trying to call.
Let me talk to him.
Let me tell him where
we are and he will come.
He will come to help you.
To save my life.
They won't help trust
me and I'm the first to try.
Sweet.
It's so cute.
John.
We have a visitor.
My friend is fucking gone.
It's hard to fear.
I'm coming here.
Hey.
You saved me.
What is this?
Walk in with a gun and
get treated like a criminal.
Who are you?
I was going to ask you the same question.
I know you.
I know.
Brain cancer, right?
What are you doing here, Barbara?
I can't give my money back.
These people are just crooks.
Look at this.
Yeah.
Is that me?
I'm a material.
Gabriella, Valentina,
and Diego was in arm too.
You're all calm artists.
And we.
We were just suckers.
Pinch.
I gave everything.
All the money I had.
That was for my family, that money.
It's very good with my
kids when I was gone.
Let me stand you treated into magic beings.
More time.
The shop of life.
What your life really mean to you, Parker?
Have you ever thought about that?
Because if you find
the meaning of your life.
What you found is your soul.
But when we have your money,
you can be assured of that.
But before I let you confront Cecilia,
there is a game that she has
to play out to its conclusion.
Wait a minute.
Oh God.
You killed Valentina.
We don't kill.
You've jumped a fucking head off!
Valentina died because she
didn't have the wealth to live.
She failed her test.
John?
He found us here.
Others might too.
And soon we're wasting time.
I'm just trying to give this to Sears.
A chance to make his choice.
A choice.
I don't have a choice but he
needs to fucking talk me about.
I'm going to give you an opportunity
to do something super delicate.
With your life.
Right now.
I miss me.
But first I'm going to have to insist.
No cons.
Rules are rules.
Consquence is for
grating and we'll be dire.
Understood.
Let's do me now.
John.
I promise you I'm in to one way or another.
So I'm going to work out a coordinate plan.
Why don't you go and prepare,
and get real enough of the next game.
You won't be into it.
No.
But the anesthesiologist is next.
Can you please talk to me?
Please talk to me.
You fucking bitch!
You fucking god!
Help me.
Please don't. I just did. You were next.
He's the monster. He's going to kill you.
He's going to kill you.
He's going to kill you all the best.
You don't know John.
You like it.
That's how to shoot that thief in the face.
First we must do seers.
In short order.
Show wish the new era.
Hold on.
No.
What is it?
I don't know what the
fuck all these things are.
What do you think?
And there's a fucking bone cutter.
The crayons.
I don't care what the
fucking thing is called.
That's Elliot.
They're just playing me.
I'm not going to talk to him.
What the fuck?
Hello, Mateo.
It's time to play the game.
The rules are simple.
Place a big enough piece of
yours so you can teach you.
Into the glass inside tank.
And you, yeah.
A piece of what?
Great matter.
What does that mean?
A piece of the brain.
This is insane.
Crazy.
If you complete your task
in less than three minutes,
the enzymes will dissolve
the tissue to close a circuit.
This will save you life.
But know this.
The brain is a remarkably resilient organ.
There are an accounts of people undergoing
complete anatomical lamispyrectomies,
as the brain remote,
only to have it rewire itself so
that the patient not only survives,
but thrives.
I don't know how to do this.
The only thing I have not
provided is your anaesthetic.
But trust me,
you will want to remain alert.
And if you fail to act,
the consequences will not go well for you.
Do not waste time.
Little time.
The choice is yours.
Okay, take it, take it, take it.
Damn.
What do we do? What do we do?
What do we do?
You have to use the radiator.
Not going to fucking happen.
You have to cut it to your skull.
No.
I can't do it.
Do you want to live?
Or wind up like that?
Okay.
Is there a cable?
Is there a seat?
Sure.
Yes.
You guys are fucking sick.
We're sick.
These people will kill with force.
Oh.
What if there is something
her father can do to help you?
Amanda, you know, as well as I do.
People will say almost anything.
Save their own life.
Yeah, but her father is real.
We both know that.
Amanda, the reality is...
I'm dying.
I am dying.
You have to face that.
But I'm worse not than I had.
I'm trusting.
Trusting.
You.
The area.
It's almost morning.
We got a job to do.
We're running out of time.
I want you to go and free.
Mr. Sears.
I can see you don't play by the rules.
Mmm.
No.
Don't be a... You have to take.
I'll never get out of here otherwise.
Hello, Gabriel.
I want to play a game.
No, no, stop it.
Stop it.
I'm afraid that's not going to work.
You are going to have to play the game.
No.
Most of you all pretended
to cure my cancer.
I have spent years in treatment.
Immunotherapy, immunotherapy,
radiation machines are not.
I'm afraid to be trifled with the
following instructions carefully, Gabriel.
The only way out is to free your
hand and ankle from the shackles.
Use the tool above you.
No.
You can't.
Broken bones heal.
Flesh can be grafted.
It will not be easy.
Like life.
Ever is.
Let's wake up on the way.
I did it, Gabby.
Gabby!
Okay, play tons of it.
If guns were against the
rules, fuck your rules, John.
The keys to the city has changed.
Don't need the keys.
She's not going anywhere.
Come on.
Move.
Don't you have a gun about me?
Not a chance.
You know, I die for you, baby.
I'm Locker.
No!
I'm one who should do that.
Come on, old man.
Lock yourself in.
Come on, move!
Move!
New game.
It's called We Live.
You die.
Fuck you.
Simply enough.
I told you Parker would break the rules.
Filled your test asshole.
We need to get her to our hospital.
She don't want her getting,
and she deserves to live.
Oh, actually now.
Her injury is named medical treatment.
Do you think?
Tell me.
Don't think about it.
Unfortunately.
The keys.
Fuck yourself in.
Don't tell me, John.
You've been doing
this for a very long time.
How would you?
How would I stop you?
Am I just that good?
Don't flatter yourself.
How'd you say who works in charge of them?
That's all.
Yeah, I agree.
For a guy as smart as you are, John.
You're kind of a little page
around everyone you say.
You didn't give a shit though.
All your friends are dead because of you.
Not friends.
They were loose bands, as we taught.
Nothing but loose ends.
If you want to know what I thought.
I watched them each die.
One less person just picked them anyway.
So thank you.
You did me a favor.
You're going to have to
get the money back from me.
Before you took the split.
I think we're getting money back.
Substairs.
You know she's eventually
going to kill you too, right?
Fuck off, Amanda.
Amanda's all right.
She's going to burn you.
You just can't see it yet.
Is that really all you've got left, John?
When I realized who you really were.
Jake fucking saw.
I got a bit worried.
I got a sonist.
And now the great John Kramer is
going to die in one of his own traps.
There's something we get irony.
And the craziest thing is that
you could have just walked away.
A knowledge that you've got beat.
You've got to count.
But now.
You're just trying to
come back and continue.
Why don't we put this bitch on the
other side of that thing and press play?
You know this fucking
asshole is dead in two months.
But I want him to suffer.
Like he made me suffer.
I want this last memory to be
watching someone innocent die.
If you think I'm innocent.
You.
Not for a second.
I don't think we're here or no, son.
Jake, are you kidding?
It's an terrible one for
seeing God's wants.
Please don't judge this.
The boy says.
Exactly.
If you let him die, it's all on you.
And we get this thing started.
It's activated by the subject.
Of course.
Because you wouldn't be responsible
for killing anyone, would you?
How can he have got hurt?
Well, you might want to tell
the kid the rules before we start.
He's not a player.
In any of this.
Oh, come on John.
Get the scary boys.
I don't want to play, game.
No.
You really want the boy to
play without airing the rules.
I don't think it's gonna fit well.
John, I will cut his throat.
It's not right.
I'm really.
Electron moral decency.
From you.
You've got 10 seconds.
We're here to deliver myself.
And I don't have a
silly moral code like you.
Trust me.
Of course.
Don't let him.
Confronting.
Turn it on, Parker.
Let's go.
Hold on.
Once I heard your voice over
that speaker, then you'll be fine.
John would be a bit full of the
whole dancing, whole line and singer.
But if you were the
last player, who was
supposed to be on the
side of that play with you?
There's the money.
You.
A warrior.
Are you okay?
No, exactly.
Yes, we're planted.
But.
Parker!
He knows.
He wasn't in.
He's a handler.
He's fucking silly too.
I was able to find the
man who has four hands.
Ah.
Good.
But Dr. Hughes.
You'll have to find another way.
Do you have a visitor?
Parker, Sears.
You've each been working a great play role.
Work.
Never realizing that you lost a game.
But two of you.
Now you'll work against each other.
Only one can survive.
Do we kill you too, right?
Fuck off of them.
Donna!
Where's your skull?
Henry?
Thank you, Detective.
For locating my fellow cancer patient.
Out of all the mentorship.
You pick John Kramer?
I mean.
I call that.
Epic bad luck.
Please.
John, please.
Please don't kill me.
That's the last thing you
should be worried about.
No.
I want to play a game.
Please don't kill me.
Go.
You're just gonna die.
Kr Easy.
Go.
But you're not gonna die.
Have you seen any of this fun game?