13 meters. You should see it.
Okay, take her up and over the bow rail.
Mir 2, we're going over the bow.
Stay with us.
Okay, quiet. We're rolling.
Seeing her coming out of the
darkness like a ghost ship
still gets me every time.
To see the sad ruin
of the great ship sitting here
where she landed at 2:30 in the morning
of April 15, 1912
after her long fall
from the world above.
You are so full of shit, boss.
Dive 6. Here we are again
on the deck of Titanic.
Two and a half miles down. 3,821 meters.
The pressure outside is
three and a half tons per square inch.
These windows are nine inches thick.
If they go, it's sayonara
in two microseconds.
All right, enough of that bullshit.
Just put her down on the roof of
the officers' quarters like yesterday.
Mir 2, we're landing right over the
Grand Staircase. You guys set to launch?
Yeah, Brock. Launching Dunkin now.
Go, Charlie.
-All right, tether out.
-Tether out.
Okay, Brock, we're dropping
down along the hull.
Yeah, roger that. Okay, drop down and go
into the first class gangway door.
I want you guys working the D deck
reception area and the dining saloon.
Copy that.
-Tether out. Okay, now left. Left, left.
-Okay, coming left.
Snoop Dog is on the move.
We're headed down the stairwell.
Okay, Lewis, drop down to B deck.
-Okay, A deck.
-Give me some rope, Captain.
B deck. Get in there. Get in there.
Watch the door frame.
-Watch it, watch it.
-I see it. I got it.
-We good? Bring her down.
-We're good. Just chill, boss.
Okay, make your turn.
-Cable out, Captain.
-Make your turn. Watch the wall.
Yeah Brock, we're at the piano. You copy?
Okay, copy that.
Okay, right there. Right there.
Okay, that's it, that's it.
That's the bedroom door.
I see it. I see it.
We're in!
We're in, baby. We're there.
That's Hockley's bed.
That's where the son of a bitch slept.
Oops. Somebody left the water running.
Hold it. Hold it just a second.
Go back to the right.
That wardrobe door. Get closer.
You smelling something, boss?
-I want to see what's under it.
-Give me my hands, man.
All right.
-Take it easy. It might come apart.
-Okay.
Go, go, go. Flip it over.
Flip it over. Go.
Turn her over. Keep going.
Go, go, go.
Okay, drop it.
Oh, baby, baby. Are you seeing this, boss?
It's payday, boys.
Cha-ching!
-We did it, Bobby.
-We brought it back, Baby.
Oh, yeah! Who's the best?
Who's the best, baby?
Say it. Say it. Say it.
You are, Lewis.
-Bobby, my cigar.
-Right here.
Okay, crack her open.
Shit.
No diamond.
You know, boss, this same thing happened
to Geraldo and his career never recovered.
Turn the camera off.
Brock, the partners would like
to know how it's going.
Hey, Dave, Barry, hi. Look, I it wasn't
in the safe. But hey, hey...
Don't worry about it. There's still
plenty of places it could be. Hell, yes.
The floor debris in the suite,
the mother's room,
the purser's safe on C deck.
Jimmy Hoffa's briefcase.
A dozen other places. Guys, look,
you're just going to have to
trust my instincts. I know we're close.
We've just got to go through a little
process of elimination.
Hang on a second.
-Let me see that.
-We may have something here, guys.
Where's the photograph of the necklace?
We'll call you right back.
I'll be goddamned.
Treasure hunter Brock Lovett
is best known for finding Spanish gold...
It's okay. I'll feed you in a minute.
Now he has chartered Russian subs to reach
the most famous shipwreck of all,
the Titanic.
He is with us live via satellite
from the research ship Keldysh
in the North Atlantic. Hello, Brock.
Hello, Tracy. Of course, everyone knows
the familiar stories of Titanic.
You know, the nobility of the band playing
to the very end and all that.
But what I'm interested in
are the untold stories.
The secrets locked deep inside
the hull of Titanic.
And we're out here using robot
technology to go further into the wreck
than anybody has ever done before.
Your expedition is at the center
of a storm of controversy
over salvage rights and even ethics.
Many are calling you a graverobber.
Well, nobody ever called the
recovery of the artifacts...
What is it?
Turn that up, dear.
I have museum-trained experts
sent out here making sure
that these relics are preserved
and cataloged properly.
Take a look at this drawing
that we found just today.
A piece of paper that's been underwater
for 84 years.
And my team are able to
preserve it intact.
Should this have remained unseen
at the bottom of the ocean for eternity
when we can see and enjoy it now?
I'll be goddamned.
Brock!
There's a satellite call for you.
Bobby, we're launching. You see
these submersibles going in the water?
Trust me, buddy.
You want to take this call.
This better be good.
Now, you gotta speak up.
She's kind of old.
Great.
This is Brock Lovett.
How can I help you, Mrs...
Calvert. Rose Calvert.
Mrs. Calvert.
I was just wondering if you had found
the "Heart of the Ocean" yet, Mr. Lovett.
Told you you wanted to take the call.
All right, you have my attention, Rose.
Can you tell us who the woman
in the picture is?
Oh, yes. The woman in the picture is me.
She's a goddamn liar!
Some nutcase seeking money or publicity.
God only knows why.
Like that Russian babe, Anesthesia.
They're inbound!
Rose DeWitt Bukater died on the
Titanic when she was 17, right?
That's right.
If she had lived,
she'd be over 100 by now.
101 next month.
Okay, so she's a very old goddamn liar.
Look, I've already done
the background on this woman
all the way back to the '20s,
when she was working as an actress.
An actress.
There's your first clue, Sherlock.
Her name was Rose Dawson back then.
Then she marries this guy named Calvert.
They move to Cedar Rapids
and she punches out a couple of kids.
Now Calvert's dead and,
from what I hear, Cedar Rapids is dead.
And everybody who knows about
the diamond is supposed to be dead
or on this boat, but she knows.
Doesn't exactly travel light, does she?
Hurry up, give him a hand.
Mrs. Calvert, I'm Brock Lovett.
Welcome to the Keldysh.
Okay, let's get her inside there.
Hi, Miss Calvert.
-Hi.
-Welcome to the Keldysh.
Thanks.
Hey!
-Yes?
-Are your staterooms all right?
Oh, yes. Very nice.
Have you met my granddaughter, Lizzy?
She takes care of me.
We met just a few minutes ago.
Remember, Nana? Up on deck?
Oh, yes.
There. That's nice.
Have to have my pictures when I travel.
Can I get you anything?
Is there anything you'd like?
Yes.
I would like to see my drawing.
Louis XVI wore a fabulous stone that was
called the Blue Diamond of the Crown
which disappeared in 1792
about the same time old Louis lost
everything from the neck up.
The theory goes that the crown diamond
was chopped, too.
Recut into a heart-like shape that
became known as the Heart of the Ocean.
Today it would be worth
more than the Hope diamond.
It was a dreadful, heavy thing.
I only wore it this once.
You actually think this is you, Nana?
It is me, dear.
Wasn't I a dish?
I tracked it down
through insurance records.
An old claim that was settled
under terms of absolute secrecy.
Can you tell me
who the claimant was, Rose?
I should imagine someone named Hockley.
Nathan Hockley, that's right.
Pittsburgh steel tycoon.
The claim was for a diamond necklace
his son Caledon, bought his fiancée.
You.
A week before he sailed on Titanic.
And it was filed right after the sinking.
So the diamond had to have
gone down with the ship.
You see the date?
April 14, 1912.
Which means if your grandmother
is who she says she is
she was wearing the diamond
the day the Titanic sank.
And that makes you my new best friend.
These are some of the things
we recovered from your stateroom.
This was mine.
How extraordinary.
And it looks the same as it
did the last time I saw it.
The reflection has changed a bit.
Are you ready to go back to Titanic?
Okay, here we go.
She hits the berg on
the starboard side, right?
She kind of bumps along
punching holes like Morse Code,
"Dit, dit, dit," along the side
below the water line.
Then the forward compartments
start to flood.
Now, as the water level rises
it spills over the watertight bulkheads
which, unfortunately, don't go
any higher than E deck.
So now as the bow goes down
the stern rises up, slow at first,
then faster and faster
until finally, she's got her whole
ass sticking up in the air.
And that's a big ass.
We're talking 20, 30,000 tons. Okay?
And the hull's not designed
to deal with that pressure.
So, what happens?
She splits, right down to the keel.
And the stern falls back level.
Then as the bow sinks,
it pulls the stern vertical
and then finally detaches.
Now the stern section just kind of bobs
there like a cork for a couple of minutes,
floods, and finally goes under
about 2:20 a.m.
Two hours and forty minutes
after the collision.
The bow section planes away,
landing about a half a mile away
going 20, 30 knots when
it hits the ocean floor.
Pretty cool, huh?
Thank you for that fine
forensic analysis, Mr. Bodine.
Of course, the experience of it was
somewhat different.
Will you share it with us?
I'm taking her to rest.
No.
Come on, Nana.
No!
Give me the tape recorder.
Tell us, Rose.
It's been 84 years...
It's okay. Just try to remember anything,
anything at all.
Do you want to hear this
or not, Mr. Lovett?
It's been 84 years,
and I can still smell the fresh paint.
The china had never been used.
The sheets had never been slept in.
Titanic was called the ship of dreams.
And it was.
It really was.
All third-class passengers
with a forward berth,
this way please! This queue!
It's a big boat, huh?
Daddy, it's a ship.
You're right.
I don't see what all the fuss is about.
It doesn't look any bigger
than the Mauretania.
You can be blasé about some things, Rose,
but not about Titanic.
It's over 100 feet longer than Mauretania
and far more luxurious.
Your daughter is far too
difficult to impress, Ruth.
So this is the ship
they say is unsinkable.
It is unsinkable.
God Himself could not sink this ship...
What?
You have to check your baggage
through the main terminal.
It's round that way, sir.
I put my faith in you good sir.
Now kindly see my man.
Yes, sir. It's my pleasure, sir.
If I can do anything at all...
Yes, right.
All the trunks from that car there.
12 from here.
And the safe, to the parlor suite,
rooms B-52, 54, 56.
Ladies, we better hurry.
Come along.
-My coat?
-I have it, miss.
All third-class passengers
queue here for health inspection.
-Welcome aboard, ma'am.
-Welcome to Titanic.
It was the ship of dreams
to everyone else.
To me, it was a slave ship
taking me back to America in chains.
Outwardly, I was everything
a well brought up girl should be.
Inside, I was screaming.
Jack, you are pazzo.
You bet everything we have.
When you got nothing,
you got nothing to lose.
You moron. I can't believe
you bet our tickets.
Sven?
All right, moment of truth.
Someone's life is about to change.
Fabrizio?
Olaf?
Nothing.
Sven?
Two pair.
I'm sorry, Fabrizio.
I'm sorry,
you're not gonna see your mom again
for a long time
'cause we're going to America.
Full house, boys!
Come on.
I'm going home!
I'm going home.
I go to America!
No, mate.
Titanic go to America,
in five minutes.
Shit. Fabri. Come on.
Come on, here. Here.
We're riding in high style now!
We're a couple of regular swells.
We're practically goddamn royalty,
ragazzo mio.
You see? Is my destino.
Like I told you,
I go to America to be millionaire.
You are pazzo.
Maybe, but I've got the tickets.
Come on, I thought you were fast.
Whoa. Wait! Wait!
Hey, wait!
We're passengers!
Have you been through
the inspection queue?
Of course. Anyway, we don't have any lice.
We're Americans. Both of us.
Right. Come aboard.
We're the luckiest sons
of bitches in the world.
You know that?
Good-bye!
You know somebody?
Of course not. That's not the point.
Good-bye! I'll miss you!
Good-bye!
I will never forget you!
Come with me, darling. Let's go.
G-60.
G-60. G-60.
Excuse me, ma'am.
G-60.
Right here.
Hey, how you doing?
Jack. Nice to meet you.
Jack Dawson. Nice to meet you.
How you doing?
Who says you get top bunk, huh?
Where's Sven?
This is your private promenade deck, sir.
Will you be requiring anything?
Excuse me.
-This one?
-No.
It had a lot of faces on it.
This is the one.
Would you like all of them out, miss?
Yes. We need a little color in this room.
Put it in there. In the wardrobe.
God, not those finger paintings again.
They certainly were a waste of money.
The difference between
Cal's taste in art and mine
is that I have some.
They're fascinating.
Like being inside a dream or something.
There's truth but no logic.
-What's the artist's name?
-Something Picasso.
Something Picasso.
He won't amount to a thing.
He won't, trust me.
-Let's put the Degas in the bedroom.
-At least they were cheap.
Put it in the wardrobe.
At Cherbourg, a woman came aboard
named Margaret Brown.
We all called her Molly.
History would call her
the Unsinkable Molly Brown.
Well, I wasn't about to
wait all day for you, sonny.
Here, if you think you can manage.
Her husband had struck gold
someplace out west.
And she was what Mother
called "new money."
By the next afternoon,
we were steaming west
from the coast of Ireland
with nothing out ahead of us but ocean.
Take her to sea, Mr. Murdoch.
Let's stretch her legs.
Yes, sir.
All ahead full, Mr. Moody.
Very good, sir.
All ahead full.
All ahead full!
Come on lads, step lively!
All right! Let's stoke her right up!
We go full ahead!
Come on, put your backs into it!
21 knots, sir.
Hey, look, look, look!
See it?
There's another one! See him?
Look at that one! Look at him jump!
I can see the Statue of Liberty already.
Very small, of course.
I'm the king of the world!
She is the largest moving object
ever made by the hand of man
in all history.
And our master shipbuilder,
Mr. Andrews here
designed her from the keel plates up.
I may have knocked her together,
but the idea was Mr. Ismay's.
He envisioned a steamer so grand in scale
and so luxurious in its appointments
that its supremacy
would never be challenged.
And here she is.
-Willed into solid reality.
-Hear, hear.
I'll have the salmon.
You know I don't like that, Rose.
She knows.
We'll both have the lamb.
Rare, with very little mint sauce.
You like lamb, right sweet pea?
You gonna cut her meat
for her too there, Cal?
Hey, who thought of the name Titanic?
Was it you, Bruce?
Yes, actually.
I wanted to convey sheer size.
And size means stability,
luxury, and above all, strength.
Do you know of Dr. Freud, Mr. Ismay?
His ideas about
the male preoccupation with size
might be of particular interest to you.
What's gotten into you?
Excuse me.
I do apologize.
She's a pistol, Cal.
Hope you can handle her.
Well, I may have to start minding what she
reads from now on, won't I, Mrs. Brown?
Freud? Who is he? Is he a passenger?
The ship is nice, huh?
Yeah. It's an Irish ship.
Is English, no?
No, it was built in Ireland.
15,000 Irishmen built this ship.
Solid as a rock. Big Irish hands.
That's typical.
First-class dogs
come down here to take a shite.
Lets us know where we rank
in the scheme of things.
Like we could forget?
I'm Tommy Ryan.
-Jack Dawson.
-Fabrizio.
Do you make any money with your drawings?
Forget it, boyo.
You'd as like have angels
fly out of your arse
as get next to the likes of her.
I saw my whole life
as if I'd already lived it.
An endless parade
of parties and cotillions,
yachts and polo matches.
Always the same narrow people,
the same mindless chatter.
I felt like I was standing
at a great precipice
with no one to pull me back.
No one who cared
or even noticed.
Don't do it.
Stay back.
Don't come any closer.
Come on.
Just give me your hand.
I'll pull you back over.
No! Stay where you are.
I mean it.
I'll let go.
No, you won't.
What do you mean, no I won't?
Don't presume to tell me
what I will and will not do.
You don't know me.
Well, you would have done it already.
You're distracting me. Go away.
I can't.
I'm involved now.
You let go, and I'm going to have
to jump in there after you.
Don't be absurd.
-You'll be killed.
-I'm a good swimmer.
The fall alone will kill you.
It would hurt. I'm not saying it wouldn't.
Tell you the truth,
I'm a lot more concerned
about that water being so cold.
How cold?
Freezing. Maybe a couple degrees over.
You ever been to Wisconsin?
What?
Well, they have some of
the coldest winters around.
I grew up there, near Chippewa Falls.
I remember when I was a kid,
me and my father, we went ice fishing
out on Lake Wissota.
-Ice fishing is, you know, where you...
-I know what ice fishing is!
Sorry.
You just seem like, you know,
kind of an indoor girl.
Anyway, I...
I fell through some thin ice.
And I'm telling you,
water that cold,
like right down there,
it hits you like 1,000 knives
stabbing you all over your body.
You can't breathe. You can't think.
Least not about anything but the pain.
Which is why I'm not looking
forward to jumping in there after you.
Like I said,
I don't have a choice.
I guess I'm kind of hoping you'll
come back over the rail,
and get me off the hook here.
You're crazy.
That's what everybody says but,
with all due respect, miss,
I'm not the one hanging off
the back of a ship here.
Come on.
Come on, give me your hand.
You don't want to do this.
I'm Jack Dawson.
Rose DeWitt Bukater.
I'll have to get you to
write that one down.
Come on.
I got you. Come on.
Help, please!
Help!
-Please, help me!
-Listen. Listen to me.
Listen. Listen to me.
I've got you. I won't let go.
Now pull yourself up. Come on!
Come on. That's right.
You can do it.
I got you.
What's all this?
You stand back and don't move an inch!
Fetch the Master at Arms.
This is completely unacceptable!
What made you think that you could
put your hands on my fiancée?
Look at me, you filth!
-Cal.
-What do you think you were doing?
Cal, stop. It was an accident.
An accident?
It was.
Stupid, really.
I was leaning over and I slipped.
I was leaning far over to see the...
The...
-Propellers?
-Propellers, and I slipped.
And I would have gone overboard
but Mr. Dawson here saved me.
And almost went over himself.
You wanted to see the...
She wanted to see the propellers.
Like I said,
women and machinery do not mix.
Was that the way of it?
Yeah. Yeah, that was pretty much it.
Well, the boy's a hero then.
Good for you, son. Well done.
So, it's all's well
and back to our brandy, eh?
Look at you. You must be freezing.
Let's get you inside.
Perhaps a little something for the boy?
Of course.
Mr. Lovejoy, I think a 20 should do it.
Is that the going rate
for saving the woman you love?
Rose is displeased.
What to do?
I know.
Perhaps you could join us for
dinner tomorrow evening
to regale our group with your heroic tale.
Sure. Count me in.
Good. It's settled then.
This should be interesting.
Can I bum a smoke?
You'll want to tie those.
It's interesting,
the young lady slipped so suddenly,
and you still had time to remove
your jacket and your shoes.
I know you've been melancholy.
I don't pretend to know why.
I intended to save this
until the engagement gala next week,
but, I thought
tonight.
Good gracious.
Perhaps as a reminder
of my feelings for you.
-Is it a...
-Diamond. Yes.
56 carats to be exact.
It was worn by Louis XVI.
And they called it Le Coeur de la Mer.
-The Heart of the Ocean.
-The Heart of the Ocean. Yes.
It's overwhelming.
Well, it's for royalty.
We are royalty, Rose.
You know, there's
nothing I couldn't give you.
There's nothing I'd deny you
if you would not deny me.
Open your heart to me, Rose.
Well, I've been on my own since
I was 15, since my folks died.
And I had no brothers or sisters or
close kin in that part of the country,
so I lit on out of there
and I haven't been back since.
You could just call me a
tumbleweed blowing in the wind.
Well, Rose, we've walked about a mile
around this boat deck and
chewed over how great the weather's
been and how I grew up
but I reckon that's not why
you came to talk to me, is it?
-Mr. Dawson, I...
-Jack.
Jack.
I want to thank you for what you did.
Not just for pulling me back,
but for your discretion.
You're welcome.
Look.
I know what you must be thinking.
Poor little rich girl.
What does she know about misery?
No.
No, that's not what I was thinking.
What I was thinking was
what could have happened to this girl
to make her think she had no way out?
Well I...
It was everything.
It was my whole world and
all the people in it.
And the inertia of my life,
plunging ahead and me,
powerless to stop it.
God, look at that thing.
You would have gone
straight to the bottom.
500 invitations have gone out.
All of Philadelphia society will be there.
And all the while I feel I'm
standing in the middle of a crowded room
screaming at the top of my lungs
and no one even looks up.
Do you love him?
Pardon me?
You're being very rude.
You shouldn't be asking me this.
Well, it's a simple question.
Do you love the guy or not?
This is not a suitable conversation.
Why can't you just answer the question?
This is absurd.
You don't know me and I don't know you,
and we are not having this
conversation at all. You are rude
and uncouth and presumptuous
and I am leaving now.
Jack. Mr. Dawson. It's been a pleasure.
I sought you out to thank you,
and now I have thanked you.
And you've insulted me.
Well, you deserved it.
-Right.
I thought you were leaving.
I am.
You are so annoying.
Wait.
I don't have to leave.
This is my part of the ship. You leave.
Well, well, well. Now who's being rude?
What is this stupid thing
you're carrying around?
So, what are you, an artist or something?
These are rather good.
They're very good, actually.
Jack, this is exquisite work.
They didn't think too
much of them in old Paree.
Paris?
You do get around for a...
-Well, a person of limited means.
-Go on.
A poor guy. You can say it.
Well, well, well.
And these were drawn from life?
Well, that's one of the good things
about Paris.
Lots of girls are willing
to take their clothes off.
You liked this woman.
You used her several times.
Well.
She had beautiful hands, you see?
I think you must have
had a love affair with her.
No, no, no. Just with her hands.
She was a one-legged prostitute.
See?
She had a good sense of humor though.
Oh, and this lady.
She used to sit at this bar every night
wearing every piece of jewelry she owned
just waiting for her long, lost love.
We called her Madame Bijoux.
See, her clothes are all moth-eaten.
Well, you have a gift, Jack.
You do.
You see people.
I see you.
And?
You wouldn't have jumped.
But the purpose of university
is to find a suitable husband.
Rose has already done that.
Look, here comes that vulgar Brown woman.
Quickly, get up before she sits with us.
Hello, girls. I was hoping
I'd catch you at tea.
We're awfully sorry, you missed it.
The Countess and I were just
off to take the air on the boat deck.
What a lovely idea.
I need to catch up on my gossip.
Countess.
So, you've not yet lit the
last four boilers?
No, I don't see the need.
We are making excellent time.
The press knows the size of Titanic.
Now, I want them to marvel at her speed.
We must give them something new to print.
This maiden voyage of Titanic must
make headlines.
Mr. Ismay, I would prefer
not to push the engines
until they've been properly run in.
Of course, I'm just a passenger.
I leave it to your good offices
to decide what's best.
But what a glorious end
to your final crossing
if we were to get into New York
on Tuesday night
and surprise them all.
Make the morning papers.
Retire with a bang, eh, E.J.?
Good man.
After that, I worked
on a squid boat in Monterey,
then I went to Los Angeles to the pier
in Santa Monica
and started doing portraits
for 10 cents a piece.
Why can't I be like you, Jack?
Just head out for the horizon
whenever I feel like it.
Say we'll go there sometime, to that pier,
even if we only ever just talk about it.
No, we'll do it. We'll drink cheap beer.
Ride on the roller coaster
till we throw up.
Then we'll ride horses on the beach,
right in the surf.
But you have to do it like a real cowboy.
None of that sidesaddle stuff.
-You mean with one leg on each side?
-Yeah.
Can you show me?
Sure, if you like.
Teach me to ride like a man.
Chew tobacco like a man.
And spit like a man.
They didn't teach you that
in finishing school?
No.
Come on, I'll show you. Let's do it.
I'll show you how.
Jack! No, Jack, no. Wait.
No, Jack. I couldn't possibly, Jack.
Watch closely.
That's disgusting.
Your turn.
That was pitiful.
You really have to hawk it back.
Get some leverage.
Use your arms. Arc your neck.
You see the range on that thing?
Okay, go.
That was better. You have to work on it.
Really try to hawk it up.
Mother.
May I introduce Jack Dawson?
Charmed, I'm sure.
The others were gracious and curious
about the man who'd saved my life.
But my mother looked at him
like an insect.
A dangerous insect
which must be squashed quickly.
Sounds like you're a good man
to have around in a sticky spot.
Why do they always insist on announcing
dinner like a damn cavalry charge?
Shall we go dress, Mother?
See you at dinner, Jack.
Son?
Son!
Do you have the slightest comprehension
what you're doing?
Not really.
You're about to go into the snake pit.
What are you planning to wear?
I figured. Come on.
I was right. You and my son
are just about the same size.
Pretty close.
You shine up like a new penny.
Good evening, sir.
Thousands of tons of Hockley steel
are in this ship.
-Which part?
-All the right ones.
Then you're accountable
if there's a problem. Where's my daughter?
She'll be along.
There is the Countess. Hello, my dear.
I saw that in a nickelodeon once
and always wanted to do it.
Darling,
surely you remember Mr. Dawson.
Dawson.
It's amazing.
You could almost pass for a gentleman.
Almost.
This is extraordinary.
This is a remarkable voyage.
-Mad.
-Completely lunatic.
There's the Countess of Rothes.
That's John Jacob Astor,
the richest man on the ship.
His little wifey there, Madeleine,
is my age and in a delicate condition.
See how she's trying to hide it.
Quite the scandal.
Benjamin Guggenheim and his mistress,
Madame Aubert.
Mrs. Guggenheim is at home with
the children, of course.
And over here, Sir Cosmo
and Lucile, Lady Duff Gordon.
She designs naughty lingerie,
among her many talents.
Very popular with the royals.
Congratulations, Hockley. She's splendid.
Why, thank you.
Care to escort a lady to dinner?
Certainly.
Sweet pea, sweet pea.
Ain't nothing to it. Is there, Jack?
They love money. Pretend like you own
a gold mine and you're in the club.
Hey, Astor.
Hello, Molly. Nice to see you.
J.J., Madeleine,
I'd like you to meet Jack Dawson.
-How do you do?
-Pleasure.
Well, Jack,
are you of the Boston Dawsons?
No, the Chippewa Falls Dawsons, actually.
Oh, yes.
He must have been nervous,
but he never faltered.
They assumed he was one of them.
Heir to a railroad fortune, perhaps.
New money, obviously,
but still a member of the club.
Mother, of course,
could always be counted upon.
Tell us of the accommodations in steerage,
Mr. Dawson. I hear they're quite good.
The best I've seen, ma'am.
Hardly any rats.
Mr. Dawson is joining us from third class.
He was of help to my fiancée last night.
It happens Mr. Dawson
is quite a fine artist.
He showed me some of his work today.
Rose and I differ somewhat in
our definition of fine art.
Not to impugn your work, sir.
Are all these mine?
Start from the outside
and work your way in.
He knows every rivet in her.
Don't you, Thomas?
Your ship is a wonder, Mr. Andrews. Truly.
Thank you, Rose.
How do you take your caviar, sir?
No caviar for me, thanks.
Never did like it much.
Where exactly do you live, Mr. Dawson?
Right now, my address is the RMS Titanic.
After that, I'm on God's good humor.
How do you have means to travel?
I work my way from place to place.
Tramp steamers and such.
I won my ticket on Titanic
at a lucky hand at poker.
A very lucky hand.
All life is a game of luck.
A real man makes his own luck, Archie.
Right, Dawson?
And you find that sort of
rootless existence appealing, do you?
Yes, ma'am, I do.
I've got everything I need
right here with me.
I have air in my lungs
and a few blank sheets of paper.
I love waking up in the morning, not
knowing what's gonna happen
or who I'll meet.
Where I'll wind up.
Just the other night,
I was sleeping under a bridge,
now here I am
on the grandest ship in the world,
having champagne with you fine people.
I'll take some more of that.
I figure life's a gift.
I don't intend on wasting it.
You never know what hand
you're gonna get dealt next.
You learn to take life as it comes at you.
Here, Cal.
To make each day count.
Well said, Jack.
Hear, hear.
To making it count.
Bravo.
But Mr. Brown had no idea
I'd hidden the money in the stove.
He comes home drunk as a pig celebrating
and he lights a fire.
Next, it'll be brandy in the smoking room.
Join me in a brandy, gentlemen?
Now they retreat into a cloud of smoke
and congratulate each other on being
masters of the universe.
Ladies, thank you for your company.
May I escort you to the cabin?
No, I'll stay here.
Here you go, Molly.
Joining us, Dawson?
You don't want to stay with the women.
No, thanks. I have to head back.
That's best.
It'll be all business and politics.
Wouldn't interest you.
But Dawson, good of you to come.
Must you go?
Time for me to row with the other slaves.
Good night, Rose.
So, you want to go to a real party?
Is okay I put my hand here?
I can't understand you.
I'm going to dance with her now.
Come on.
Come on. Come with me.
Jack. Jack, wait.
I can't do this.
We'll have to get a bit closer.
Like this.
You're still my best girl, Cora.
-I don't know the steps.
-Me, either. Just go with it.
Don't think.
Wait! Jack! Wait! Stop, Jack!
What? Wait!
Jack, no.
...beyond the jurisdiction
of the Sherman Act.
That's what Rockefeller said...
Supreme Court didn't swallow it.
What? You think
a first-class girl can't drink?
Get out of here.
Are you all right?
I'm fine.
Two out of three.
So,
you think you're big tough men?
Let's see you do this.
Hold this for me, Jack. Hold it up.
Jesus!
You okay?
I haven't done that in years.
Come on, lads.
Give it all you got. Let's go.
Coffee, sir?
I had hoped you would
come to me last night.
I was tired.
Your exertions below deck
were no doubt exhausting.
I see you had
that undertaker of a manservant follow me.
You will never behave like that again.
I'm not one of your mill foremen
who you can command.
I'm your fiancée.
My fiancée. My fiancée!
Yes, you are! And my wife!
My wife in practice,
if not yet by law, so you will honor me!
You will honor me the way
a wife honors her husband.
Because I will not be made a fool of.
Is this in any way unclear?
No.
Good. Excuse me.
Oh, Miss Rose.
We had a little accident.
-That's all right.
-I'm sorry, Trudy.
Let me help you.
It's all right, miss.
Tea, Trudy.
Yes, ma'am.
You're not to see that boy again.
Do you understand me?
Rose, I forbid it.
Stop it, Mother.
You'll give yourself a nosebleed.
This is not a game.
Our situation is precarious.
You know the money's gone.
Of course I know it's gone.
You remind me every day.
Your father left us nothing but a legacy
of bad debts hidden by a good name.
That name is the only card
we have to play.
I don't understand you.
It is a fine match with Hockley.
It will ensure our survival.
How can you put this on me?
Why are you being so selfish?
I'm being selfish?
Do you want to see me
working as a seamstress?
Is that what you want?
To see our fine things sold at auction?
Our memories scattered?
It's so unfair.
Of course it's unfair.
We're women.
Our choices are never easy.
Protect them by thy guiding hand
From every peril on the land
O, spirit whom the father sent
To spread abroad the firmament
O, wind of heaven, by thy might
Save all who dare the eagle's flight
And keep them by thy watchful care
-Hello, Mr. Andrews.
-Hello, Jack.
I need to talk to someone.
You're not supposed to be in here.
I was here last night, remember?
No. Now please turn around.
He'll tell you. I just need to talk...
Mr. Hockley and Mrs. DeWitt Bukater
are still appreciative of your assistance.
They asked me
to give you this in gratitude...
I don't want your money.
Also to remind you that
you hold a third class ticket
and that your presence here
is no longer appropriate.
Let me speak to Rose.
Gentlemen, please see Mr. Dawson
returns to where he belongs
and that he stays there?
Yes, sir.
Come along, you.
Hear us when we cry to thee
For those in peril on the sea
Why are there two steering wheels?
We use this one near shore.
Excuse me, sir.
Another ice warning, from the Noordam.
Thank you, Sparks.
Not to worry.
Quite normal for this time of year.
In fact, we're speeding up.
I've ordered the last boilers lit.
Okay, son, wind it up tight
like I showed you. That's right.
Okay, now let it go.
-It was good, wasn't it?
-Quite nice. That's excellent.
Mr. Andrews... Forgive me.
I did the sum in my head,
and with the number of lifeboats
times the capacity you mentioned...
Forgive me, but it seems that there are
not enough for everyone aboard.
About half, actually.
Rose, you miss nothing, do you?
In fact, I put in these new type davits
which can take an extra row
of boats inside this one.
But it was thought, by some
the deck would look too cluttered.
So, I was overruled.
It's a waste of deck space
as it is on an unsinkable ship.
Sleep soundly, young Rose.
I have built you a good ship,
strong and true.
She's all the lifeboat you need.
Just keep heading aft. The next
stop will be the engine room.
Jack, this is impossible. I can't see you.
-I need to talk to you.
-No, Jack. No.
Jack. I'm engaged.
I'm marrying Cal.
I love Cal.
Rose,
you're no picnic. All right?
You're a spoiled little brat even.
But under that, you're the
most amazingly, astounding
wonderful girl,
woman, that I've ever known.
Jack, I...
No, let me try and get this out. You're...
I'm not an idiot.
I know how the world works.
I've got ten bucks in my pocket.
I have nothing to offer
you and I know that.
I understand.
But I'm too involved now.
You jump, I jump. Remember?
I can't turn away without
knowing you'll be all right.
That's all that I want.
Well, I'm fine.
I'll be fine. Really.
Really?
I don't think so.
They've got you trapped, Rose.
And you're gonna die if you
don't break free.
Maybe not right away
because you're strong,
but sooner or later that
fire that I love about you, Rose,
that fire is gonna burn out.
It's not up to you to save me, Jack.
You're right.
Only you can do that.
I'm going back.
Leave me alone.
Tell Lucile about the disaster
you had with the stationers.
Well, of course the invitations
had to be sent back, twice.
Oh, my dear.
And the dreadful bridesmaids' gowns.
Let me tell you what an
odyssey that has been.
Rose decided she wanted lavender.
She knows I detest the color.
So, she did it only to spite me.
If only you'd come to me sooner.
Ruth saw some of my designs in
La Mode Illustrée.
They were for the trousseau of the Duchess
of Marlborough's youngest daughter.
They were quite charming.
But, I think you'll agree,
my dear, that together
we've created something
of a phoenix from the ashes.
Hello, Jack.
I changed my mind.
They said you might be up here.
Give me your hand.
Now close your eyes.
Go on.
Now, step up.
Now, hold onto the railing.
Keep your eyes closed. Don't peek.
I'm not.
Now, step up onto the rail.
Hold on. Hold on.
Keep your eyes closed.
Do you trust me?
I trust you.
All right,
open your eyes.
I'm flying.
Jack.
Come, Josephine, in my flying machine
Going up she goes
Up she goes
That was the last time
Titanic ever saw daylight.
We're up to dusk the night of the sinking.
Six hours to go.
Incredible. There's Smith
and he's standing there,
and he's got the iceberg warning
in his fucking hand,
excuse me, his hand,
and he's ordering more speed.
26 years of experience
working against him.
He figures anything big
enough to sink the ship
they're gonna see in time to turn.
But the ship's too big
with too small a rudder.
Doesn't corner worth a damn.
Everything he knows is wrong.
It's quite proper, I assure you.
This is the sitting room.
-Will this light do?
-What?
Don't artists need good light?
That is true, but I'm not used to
working in such horrible conditions.
Monet!
-Do you know his work?
-Of course.
Look at his use of color here.
Isn't he great?
I know. It's extraordinary.
Cal insists on carting
this hideous thing everywhere.
Should we be expecting him any time soon?
Not as long as the cigars
and brandy hold out.
That's nice.
What is it, a sapphire?
A diamond. A very rare diamond.
Jack, I want you to draw me
like one of your French girls.
Wearing this.
All right.
Wearing only this.
The last thing I need is another picture
of me looking like a porcelain doll.
As a paying customer
I expect to get what I want.
Over on the bed, the couch.
Come. Lie down.
-Tell me when it looks right.
-Keep that.
Put your arm back the way it was.
Put that other arm up,
that hand right by your face there.
Right.
Now, head down.
Eyes to me. Keep them on me.
And try to stay still.
So serious.
I believe you are blushing,
Mr. Big Artiste.
I can't imagine Monsieur Monet blushing.
He does landscapes.
-Just relax your face.
-Sorry.
No laughing.
My heart was pounding the whole time.
It was the most erotic moment of my life,
up until then, at least.
So what happened next?
You mean, did we do it?
Sorry to disappoint you, Mr. Bodine.
Jack was very professional.
Thank you.
What are you doing?
Will you put this back in the safe for me?
Gentlemen, would you excuse me.
None of the stewards have seen her.
This is absurd. It's a ship.
There's only so many places she could be.
Lovejoy, find her.
-Clear.
-Yes.
I don't think I've ever
seen such a flat calm.
Like a mill pond.
Not a breath of wind.
It will make the bergs harder to see
with no breaking water at the base.
Well, I'm off.
Maintain speed
and heading, Mr. Lightoller.
Yes, sir.
It's getting cold. You look nice.
Miss Rose?
My drawings!
Come on!
Wait, wait, wait!
-Go. Go. Down, down.
-Take us down, quickly. Quickly!
Bye.
Sorry.
-Keep going.
-Thank you, I've got it.
Pretty tough for a valet, this fella.
Seems more like a cop.
I think he was.
-Oh, shit.
-Go!
No, over here!
Quick!
Now what?
What?
More coal for number one, mate.
Hold up? What are you two doing down here?
You shouldn't be down here.
It could be dangerous!
Carry on!
Don't mind us. You're doing a great job!
Keep up the good work!
Look at what we have here, huh?
Thank you.
Where to, miss?
To the stars.
You nervous?
No.
Put your hands on me, Jack.
It's bloody cold.
You know, I can smell ice, you know.
When it's near.
Bollocks!
Well, I can, all right?
Did you ever find those
binoculars for the lookouts?
Haven't seen them since Southampton.
Well, I'll be on my rounds.
Cheerio.
You're trembling.
Don't worry.
I'll be all right.
-They ran down there.
-Right.
Anything missing?
I have a better idea.
Got you!
Did you see those guys' faces?
Did you see them?
When the ship docks,
I'm getting off with you.
This is crazy.
I know. It doesn't make any sense.
That's why I trust it.
Here, look at this.
Look at that, would you?
They're warmer than we are.
If that's what it takes for us
to get warm, I'd rather not.
Bugger me!
Pick up, you bastards!
Is anyone there?
What do you see?
Iceberg, right ahead!
Thank you.
Iceberg ahead!
Hard a' starboard!
Turn! Turn! Smartly!
Full astern!
Hard over.
Helm's hard over, sir.
Go, lads, go!
Bring that steam down! Bring it down!
Shut all the dampers! Shut them!
Hold it.
Hold it!
Now! Engage reversing engine!
Why ain't they turning?
Is it hard over?
It is, sir. Hard over.
Come on, come on, come on. Turn.
Yes.
It's going to hit!
Jesus Christ!
Jesus!
Hard to port!
Get back!
Come on. Let's go!
They're closing the doors! Get out!
Get out the door! Go!
Go! Come on, lads! Go, lads, go!
Go! Go!
Out! Out!
Oh, my God.
That was a close shave.
Smell ice, can you? Bleedin' Christ!
Note the time. Enter it in the log.
What was that, Mr. Murdoch?
An iceberg, sir.
I put her hard to starboard,
but it was too close.
I tried to port round it, but...
-Close the watertight doors.
-They're closed, sir.
-All stop.
-Aye, sir.
Have the carpenter sound the ship.
Come on, let's get the hell out of here!
Why have the engines stopped?
I felt a shudder.
Not to worry. We threw a propeller blade.
That's the shudder you felt.
Do you need anything?
No, thank you.
There's talk of an iceberg.
I don't see anything. Do you?
If this is the direction the rats are
going, that's good enough for me
-You, there.
-There is no emergency.
-There is. I've been robbed.
-Get the Master at Arms.
-Now, you moron!
-Yes, sir.
Did I miss the fun?
-Did you see what happened?
-No. I missed it
Apparently, it hit over there.
Boiler room six is flooded eight feet
and the mail hold is worse.
-Can you shore up?
-Not unless the pumps get ahead.
-Have you seen the mail hold?
-It's already underwater.
This is bad.
We should tell Mother and Cal.
I think they're very good, sir.
Don't touch anything.
I want the entire room photographed.
We've been looking for you, miss.
Here we go.
Something serious has happened.
Yes, it has.
Indeed. Two things dear to me
have disappeared this evening.
Now that one is back, I know
where to find the other. Search him.
-Take your coat off, son.
-Now what?
Cal, what are you doing?
We're in the middle of an emergency.
-Is this it?
-That's it.
This is horseshit!
Don't you believe it, Rose.
-He couldn't have.
-Easy enough for a professional.
I was with him the whole time.
This is absurd.
Perhaps he did it while you were putting
your clothes back on, dear.
Real slick, Cal.
Rose, they put it in my pocket.
-Shut up.
-It isn't even your pocket.
"Property of A.L. Ryerson."
That was reported stolen today.
I just borrowed it.
I was going to return it.
We have an honest thief.
You know I didn't do this, Rose.
Don't you believe them, Rose. You know it.
Let's go, son. Come on.
You know I didn't do it, Rose!
There's a good lad. Come on, son.
You know I didn't do it! You know me!
This is most unfortunate, Captain.
Water 14 feet above the keel
in ten minutes
in the forepeak,
all three holds and boiler room six.
That's right, sir.
When can we get underway? Damn it.
That's five compartments.
She can float with four compartments
breached, but not five.
Not five. As she goes down by the head,
the water will spill
over the tops of the bulkheads at E deck,
from one to the next
back and back. There's no stopping it.
The pumps.
The pumps buy you time, but minutes only.
From this moment, no matter what we do,
Titanic will founder.
But this ship can't sink.
She's made of iron. I assure you, she can.
And she will.
It's a mathematical certainty.
How much time?
An hour. Two, at most.
How many aboard, Mr. Murdoch?
Two thousand, two hundred souls, sir.
Well, I believe you may
get your headlines, Mr. Ismay.
It is a little slut, isn't it?
Look at me when I'm talking to you!
-Mr. Hockley?
-Not now. We're busy.
You've been asked to put on lifebelts
and go to the boat deck.
I said, not now.
I'm sorry, Mr. Hockley,
but it's Captain's orders. Dress warmly.
It's quite cold out tonight.
May I suggest topcoats and hats?
This is ridiculous.
Not to worry, miss.
I'm sure it's just a precaution.
Everybody up! Lifebelts on!
What's he on about?
-Everybody up. Put your lifebelts on!
-What's the ruckus?
Just put your lifebelts on.
CQD?
Sir?
That's right, CQD. The distress call.
That's our position.
Tell whoever responds we're going down
by the head and need immediate assistance.
Blimey.
Keep lowering!
Steady! Make it taut! And winch out!
Uncover this boat!
Uncover all the boats aft!
Release those ties!
Roll back that cover! Smartly now!
Where are the passengers?
They went inside.
Too cold and noisy for them.
You there! Get down here
and help with these lines!
Care for a drink, sir?
Sonny, what's doing?
You get us all trussed up
and now we're cooling our heels.
Sorry, ma'am. Let me go find out.
Nobody knows what's going on.
Just like the damn English,
everything by the book.
No need for language, Mr. Hockley.
Go back and turn the heaters on
in our rooms.
I'd like a cup of tea when I return.
-Yes, ma'am.
Mr. Andrews.
I saw the iceberg.
And I see it in your eyes.
Please tell me the truth.
The ship will sink.
-You're certain?
-Yes.
In an hour or so, all this
will be at the bottom of the Atlantic.
What?
Please, tell only who you must. I don't
want to be responsible for a panic.
And get to a boat. Quickly. Don't wait.
You remember what I told you
about the boats?
Yes.
I understand.
Over here, son.
Sir, they need you up in
the Second Class Purser's office.
-There's a big mob up there.
-Go on. I'll keep an eye on him.
Aye. Right.
Sir, Carpathia says they're
making 17 knots. Full steam for them, sir.
She's the only one responding?
The only one close, sir.
She says they can be here in four hours.
Four hours?
Thank you, Bride.
My God.
We are swung out and ready, sir.
Hadn't we better get the women
and children into the boats, sir?
Yes.
Sir?
Women and children first, yes.
Yes, sir.
Ladies and gentlemen,
your attention, please!
Step this way, please. That's right.
Come towards me. Thank you.
Good.
For the time being,
I require only women and children.
Right here.
All right, boys, like the Captain said,
nice and cheery, so there's no panic.
"Wedding Dance."
Lifebelts on. Put your lifebelts on.
Put your lifebelts on. Lifebelt on.
Here, put that lifebelt on.
Turn it around.
It isn't time to go to the boats yet!
Please, stay calm.
Make sure you have your lifebelts on.
Allow the women and children
through to the front.
What are we doing, Mommy?
Waiting, dear. When they finish putting
first-class people in the boats,
they'll be starting with us, and we want
to be all ready. Won't we?
Pushing won't get you out any faster.
Go get help.
Lower it away,
left and right together! Steady.
Both sides together! Steady!
Steady!
Stop, stop, stop!
Hold the left!
Right side only! Right side only!
Right side only!
Hold the left side! Right side down!
Lower away together!
Steady, lads!
You know, I do believe this ship may sink.
I've been asked to give you
this small token of our appreciation.
Compliments of Mr. Caledon Hockley.
Come on, sister, you heard
the man. Into the boat.
Any room for a gentleman, gentlemen?
Only women at this time, sir.
Will the lifeboats be
seated according to class?
I hope they're not too crowded.
Mother, shut up!
Don't you understand?
The water is freezing
and there aren't enough boats.
Not enough by half.
Half the people on this
ship are going to die.
Not the better half.
Come on, Ruth, get in the boat.
First class seats are right up here.
You know, it's a pity I didn't
keep that drawing.
It'll be worth a lot more by morning.
You unimaginable bastard.
Come on, Rose darling.
There's plenty of room for you.
Come on, Rose.
You're next, darling.
Come into the boat, Rose.
Come.
Rose.
Get into the boat!
Good-bye, Mother.
Rose? Rose, come back here.
Where are you going?
To him?
To be a whore to a gutter rat?
I'd rather be his whore than your wife.
No!
I said, no!
Rose! Please, stop!
-And, lower away!
-Rose!
No, Wait!
Lower away!
-Rose!
-Lower together!
Hold the left side!
Help!
Can anybody hear me?
Hello! Help me!
Help me!
Can you hear me?
Can anybody hear me? Somebody help me!
Mr. Andrews?
-Steward, check the starboard corridor.
-Yes, Mr. Andrews,
Madam, please put on a lifebelt.
Get to the boat deck immediately.
Lucy, for God's sake put on your
lifebelt and set a good example.
Yes, sir.
-Anyone in here?
-Mr. Andrews!
Mr. Andrews! Thank God!
Where would the Master at Arms
take someone under arrest?
What? You have to get
to a boat right away.
No! I'm doing this
with or without your help, sir.
But without will take longer.
Take the elevator to the very bottom.
Go to the left down the crewmen's passage.
Then go right
and left again at the stairs.
You'll come to a long corridor.
This could be bad.
Oh, shit! Oh, shit!
Excuse me. Thank you.
-Lifts are closed.
-I do not care what you think, sir.
Lifts are...
I'm sorry, miss, but the lifts are closed.
I'm through being polite, god damn it!
Now take me down!
E deck.
Come on.
Come on, come on.
I'm going back up.
No! No! No!
Come back! I'm going back up!
I'm going back up!
Crew passage.
Jack!
Rose!
Rose, I'm in here!
-I'm in here!
-Jack.
-I'm in here! Rose!
-Jack!
Jack! I'm sorry.
I'm sorry. I'm so sorry.
That guy Lovejoy put it in my pocket.
I know, I know, I know.
Listen, Rose,
you're gonna have to find
a spare key, all right?
Look in that cabinet right there.
It's a little silver one, Rose.
These are all brass ones!
Check right here, Rose.
Rose.
How did you find out I didn't do it?
I didn't.
I just realized I already knew.
Keep looking.
No key.
There's no key!
All right, Rose, listen.
You're gonna have to go find some help.
It'll be all right.
I'll be right back.
I'll just wait here!
Hello? Is there anyone here?
Hello?
Is there anybody down here?
We need help! Hello?
Damn it!
Can anybody hear me, please? Hello? Hello?
Oh, thank God.
Wait, please, I need your help.
There's a man back here, and he's...
Wait!
Hello?
Miss, you shouldn't be here now.
-I need your help.
-This way, quickly.
There is a man down
here and he is trapped.
-This way, yes. All right.
-Please!
-There's no need to panic.
-No, I'm not panicking!
You're going the wrong way!
Let go of me! Listen!
To hell with you.
Oh, my God.
Will this work?
I guess we'll find out.
Come on.
Wait, wait, wait.
Try a couple practice swings over there.
Good.
Now try and hit the same mark
again, Rose. You can do it.
Okay, that's enough practice.
Come on, Rose.
You can do it.
Listen, just hit it really hard
and really fast.
Come on. Wait.
Open your hands up a little more.
-Like that?
-Right.
Listen, Rose, I trust you.
Go.
You did it!
Come on. Let's go.
Oh shit, this is cold!
Oh, shit! Shit! Shit!
This is the way out.
We have to find another way. Come on.
Pull.
Put your backs into it.
Pull!
Now, there's something
you don't see every day.
What's this luggage doing here?
Get rid of it. Get rid of it.
We need the room. Get rid of that. Out.
This way. Let go, sir. Get back.
Keep calm!
Lovejoy!
She's not on the starboard side either.
We're running out of time. This strutting
martinet isn't letting any men on at all.
There's one on the other side
letting men on.
Well then, that's our play.
We'll need some insurance first. Come on.
This way, please. All the way down here.
Here!
What do you think you're doing?
You'll have to pay for that, you know.
That's White Star Line property.
-Shut up!
Will you hold the boat a moment?
I just have to run back to my room...
Sit down!
She's the last.
-Prepare to lower.
-Mr. Lightoller.
Why are the boats being
launched half full?
Not now, Mr. Andrews.
There, look. 20 or so
in a boat built for 65?
And I saw one boat with only 12. 12!
Well, we weren't sure of
the weight, Mr. Andrews.
These boats may buckle.
Rubbish!
They were tested in Belfast
with the weight of 70 men.
Now, fill these boats, Mr. Lightoller.
For God's sake man!
Please, I need more women
and children, please!
Get back in there!
This is not an exit. This is not an exit.
You can't keep us locked in here.
Like animals. The ship's bloody sinking.
Bring forward the women!
Unlock the gates.
Women only!
No men!
Get back!
Lock the gates!
Get them back from those gates!
Don't touch the gates!
For God's sake, man,
there are women and children down here!
Let us up so we can have a chance!
Get back!
Tommy!
-Can we get out?
-It's hopeless that way.
Whatever we do, we've got to do it fast.
Jack!
Fabrizio!
The boats are all going.
This whole place is flooding.
We've gotta get out of here.
-There is niente this way.
-All right.
Let's go this way, all right? Come on!
I make my own luck.
So do I.
Come on!
No, come on, let's go this way.
This way!
Just go back to the main stairwell.
And everything will be sorted out there.
It will all get sorted out back there.
Go back to the main stairwell.
-Open the gate!
-Go back down the main stairwell.
Open the gate right now!
Go back down the main
stairwell, like I told you.
God damn it! Son of a bitch!
Stop that!
Open the damn gate!
Open it!
-Fabri, Tommy, give me a hand here.
-Move aside. Move aside!
Come on, pull!
Pull!
Move aside. Quickly, move aside!
Put that down!
-Move aside!
-Put that down!
-One! Two!
-Stop that!
Three!
Again!
Now, let's go!
Let's go, Rose.
You can't go up there! You can't do this!
Keep order! Keep order here!
Back! Back! Back!
Hold on to her!
Pull her in!
Get back, I say,
or I'll shoot you all like dogs!
Keep order here!
Keep order, I say.
Mr. Lowe, man this boat.
Right. Is everybody all right?
Nobody panic.
Stay back.
We're too late.
There are more boats down the front.
Stay with this one. Murdoch.
He seems to be quite practical.
Don't lower it!
Cut the falls!
Sit down!
Stay back, you lot!
Just stay back, the lot of you! Stay back!
It's starting to fall apart.
We don't have much time.
Mr. Murdoch?
Mr. Hockley. You two, with me, now!
I'm a businessman, as you know,
and I have a business proposition for you.
Come on, Rose.
The boats are gone!
Colonel, are there any boats on that side?
No, miss, but there are a couple
of boats all the way forward.
This way, I'll lead you.
What's the use?
Nobody's listening to us anyway.
Well, they don't listen to us
at dinner, either.
Come on, let's play.
Keep us warm.
"Orpheus."
Music to drown by.
Now I know I'm in first class.
-Where is everyone?
-They're all still aft, sir.
We have an understanding
then, Mr. Murdoch.
Will the men please hold back!
Hold back, I say!
Women and children only!
Get back!
Come through, madam.
This way. Step back, sir!
You better check the other side. Go!
I found her, on the other side.
Waiting for a boat.
With him.
-Any more women and children?
-They're all aboard, Mr. Murdoch.
Anyone else then?
-Anyone else?
-Do hurry. Hurry along.
God damn it all to hell.
Shit.
Fire!
Sir, sir, you can't go through here.
That's it. Splendid. Right.
Prepare to lower.
Ready on the left.
Take them down.
Keep it steady.
Both sides together.
Steady. Keep it steady.
-Give her to me.
-Daddy.
It'll be fine, darling. Don't you worry.
Daddy, get in the boat.
It's good-bye for a little
while. Only for a little while.
There'll be another boat for the daddies.
This boat is for the
mummies and the children.
You hold Mummy's hand
and be a good little girl.
I'm not going without you.
No, you have to go, now.
No, Jack.
Get in the boat, Rose.
-No, Jack.
-Yes.
Get on the boat!
Yes, get on the boat, Rose.
Oh, my God, look at you.
You look a fright.
Here.
Put this on. Come.
Go on. I'll get the next one.
No, not without you.
I'll be all right. Listen, I'll be fine.
I'm a survivor, all right?
Don't worry about me.
Now, go on. Get on.
I have an arrangement with an
officer on the other side of the ship.
Jack and I can get off safely.
Both of us.
See?
I got my own boat to catch.
Go on, hurry.
They're almost full.
-Step aboard, miss.
-Go. Go.
Step aboard, please.
You're daddy's good girl, all right?
You're my little sailor.
Keep back. Keep back, I say.
Clear the rail, please.
And, lower away!
You're a good liar.
Almost as good as you.
There's no arrangement, is there?
No, there is.
Not that you'll benefit much from it.
I always win, Jack.
One way or another.
Rose!
-Stop her! Stop her!
-Rose, what are you doing?
No!
Rose!
You're so stupid! Why did you do that?
You're so stupid, Rose.
Why did you do that? Why?
You jump, I jump, right?
Right.
Oh God. I couldn't go.
I couldn't go, Jack.
It's all right. We'll think of something.
-At least I'm with you.
-We'll think of something.
Come on! Move!
Come on! Move.
Come on!
Move!
Come on! Come on, Rose.
Rose, come on!
Move Rose!
Go!
I hope you enjoy your time together!
What could possibly be funny?
I put the diamond in the coat.
And I put the coat on her!
Come on!
Dada!
We can't leave him.
All right, come on!
Dada!
Go back!
It's the wrong way! Come back!
No, not that way! Come back! Stop!
Go!
Go! Run!
This way!
Give me your hand!
Oh, God!/
Help!
Wait, sir! Sir, open the gate, please!
Help us, please!
Help us!
-Please!
Bloody hell!
-Come on, come on!
-Come on!
-Go, go!
-Jesus.
-Please!
-Come on!
Hurry!
Come on!
I'm sorry, I dropped the keys.
-Wait, please!
-Wait!
Don't leave! Please, send for help!
I got it! Which one is it, Rose?
The short one. Try the short one.
Hurry, Jack.
Oh no! It won't go in.
It's stuck! It's stuck!
-Come on!
-Hurry, Jack!
I got it! I got it! Go! Go, Rose!
Go! Go!
Jack! Come on!
Move, move.
-Get those oars in place.
-Get an oar under it.
Hold it! Hold it!
Hold it!
Get these davits cranked in!
Let's get the falls hooked up!
Mommy!
Keep going up!
Stop pushing!
Stay back!
Will you give us a chance
to live, you limey bastard!
I'll shoot any man who tries
to get past me! Get back!
Bastard!
Get back!
We had a deal, damn you!
Your money can't save you
any more than it could save me.
Get back!
Women and children only!
No, Tommy!
No, Will!
Now stand back, damn you!
Gently, gently. Hold it. Hold it.
I have a child!
-I have a child!
-Clear a path here!
Please, I have a child!
Please. I'm all she has in the world.
Go on.
Step back!
-Please?
-Here, give her to me.
You're all right, dearie.
Give her here.
There, there.
Wait, wait, wait! Mr. Andrews!
Oh, Rose.
Won't you even make a try for it?
I'm sorry that I didn't build you
a stronger ship, young Rose.
It's going fast. We have to move.
Wait.
Good luck to you, Rose.
And to you.
Mr. Guggenheim?
These are for you, Mr. Guggenheim.
No, thank you.
We are dressed in our best and are
prepared to go down as gentlemen.
But we would like a brandy.
Get the falls over here now!
Let them drop. Then we'll right it.
Where should I go? Please.
Captain. Captain. Sir.
Right. That's it, then.
Good-bye, Wally. Good luck.
-Good-bye, Wallace.
-So long, old chap.
And so they lived happily
together for 300 years
in the land of Tir na nog.
Land of eternal youth and beauty.
There's no time!
Cut those falls!
Cut them! Cut them if you have to!
I need a knife!
Cut the falls now!
Cut them loose!
Cut those bloody falls!
Gentlemen,
it has been a privilege
playing with you tonight.
We have to stay on the ship
as long as possible.
Come on!
This way. Through the rail.
Come on, Rose.
Jump.
Come on.
I got you. Jump.
I've got you, miss.
-Jack!
-Rose.
Back!
No! You'll swamp us!
Yea, though I walk through the
valley of the shadow of death...
You wanna walk a little faster
through that valley there?
Holy Mary, mother of God,
pray for us sinners now
and at the hour of our death. Amen.
Hail Mary, full of grace...
This way.
Come on!
And I saw a new heaven and a new earth
for the first heaven and the first earth
had passed away,
and there was no more sea.
It'll be over soon.
It'll all be over soon.
And he shall dwell with them.
And they shall be his people
and God himself shall be with them
and be their God.
Jack,
this is where we first met.
And God shall wipe away
all the tears from their eyes,
and there shall be no more death.
Neither shall there be sorrow or crying.
Neither shall there be any more pain
for the former world has passed away.
Bloody pull faster! And pull!
Hang on, Miss Trudy!
Hold on real tight.
God Almighty.
Keep those breakers in! Keep them in!
We have to move!
-Give me your hand. I'll pull you over.
-I can't.
Come on! Give me your hand.
I've got you. I won't let go.
Come on, I've got you.
-What's happening, Jack?
-I don't know. I don't know.
Hold on.
This is it!
Oh, my God, Jack! Oh, God. Oh, God.
Hold on!
The ship is gonna suck us down.
Take a deep breath when I say.
Kick for the surface and keep kicking.
Do not let go of my hand.
We're going to make it, Rose.
Trust me.
I trust you.
Ready! Ready!
Now!
Jack! Jack!
Jack!
Rose!
Get off her! Get off her!
-Rose!
-Jack!
Swim, Rose! I need you to swim!
Keep swimming.
It's so cold.
Swim, Rose!
Come on. Here.
Keep swimming.
Come on.
Here,
get on it.
Get on top.
Come on, Rose.
Stay on it. Stay on, Rose.
It'll be all right now.
Return the boats!
The boats are coming back for us Rose.
Hold on just a little bit longer.
They had to row away for the suction,
but now they'll be coming back.
For God's sake!
Please, help us!
You don't understand.
If we go back, they'll swamp the boat.
They'll pull us right down,
I'm telling you.
Knock it off. You're scaring me.
Come on, girls, grab an oar. Let's go.
Are you out of your mind?
We're in the middle of the North Atlantic.
Now, do you people want to live
or do you want to die?
I don't understand a one of you.
What's the matter with you?
It's your men out there!
There's plenty of room for more.
And there'll be one less on this boat
if you don't shut that hole in your face!
Now, bring in your oars over there.
And tie these two boats together as well.
Now, make sure that's
tied up nice and tight.
Right, listen to me, men.
We have to go back.
I want to transfer all the women
from this boat into that boat right now,
as quick as you can, please.
Let's create some space over there.
Move forward and aft.
It's getting quiet.
It's just going to take
a couple of minutes
to get the boats organized.
I don't know about you but
I intend to write a strongly worded letter
to the White Star Line about all this.
I love you, Jack.
Don't you do that.
Don't you say your good-byes. Not yet.
Do you understand me?
I'm so cold.
Listen, Rose,
you're gonna get out of here.
You're gonna go on,
and you're gonna make lots of babies.
And you're gonna watch them grow.
You're gonna die an old...
An old lady.
Warm in her bed.
Not here.
Not this night. Not like this.
Do you understand me?
I can't feel my body.
Winning that ticket, Rose,
was the best thing that
ever happened to me.
It brought me to you.
And I'm thankful for that, Rose.
I'm thankful.
You must...
You must do me this honor.
You must promise me that you'll survive.
That you won't give up,
no matter what happens.
No matter how hopeless.
Promise me now, Rose.
And never let go of that promise.
I promise.
Never let go.
I'll never let go, Jack.
I'll never let go.
Right ahead, sir.
Oars!
Do you see any moving?
No, sir. None moving, sir.
Check them.
Bring that oar up here.
Check them. Make sure.
These are dead, sir.
Now, give way.
Ahead easy.
Careful with your oars.
Don't hit them.
Is there anyone alive out there?
Can anyone hear me?
We waited too long.
Well, keep checking them!
Keep looking!
Is there anyone alive out there?
Can anyone hear me?
Come, Josephine
In my flying machine
And it's up she goes
Up she goes
Come, Josephine
In my flying
Jack.
There's a boat.
There's a boat, Jack.
Jack.
Come back.
Come back. Come back!
Hello!
Can anyone hear me?
There's nothing here, sir.
Come back.
I'll never let go.
I promise.
Come about!
Fifteen hundred people went into the sea
when Titanic sank from under us.
There were twenty boats floating nearby,
and only one came back.
One.
Six were saved from the water,
myself included.
Six,
out of fifteen hundred.
Afterward,
the seven hundred people in the boats
had nothing to do but wait.
Wait to die.
Wait to live.
Wait for an absolution
that would never come.
Sir, I don't think you'll find any
of your people down here.
It's all steerage.
His hair is reddish brown,
reddish brown, reddish brown.
White beard.
Isn't there another passenger list?
There is no other list.
Perhaps he's on another ship.
We're doing all we can, ma'am.
I'm so sorry.
That's the last time I ever saw him.
He married, of course,
and inherited his millions.
But the Crash of '29
hit his interests hard,
and he put a pistol in
his mouth that year.
Or so I read.
Can I take your name please, love?
Dawson.
Rose Dawson.
Thank you.
We never found anything on Jack.
There's no record of him at all.
No, there wouldn't be, would there?
And I've never spoken of him until now.
Not to anyone.
Not even your grandfather.
A woman's heart is a
deep ocean of secrets.
But now you know there was
a man named Jack Dawson,
and that he saved me
in every way that a person can be saved.
I don't even have a picture of him.
He exists now only in my memory.
Keldysh, Mir 2 on our way to the surface.
I was saving this for when
I found the diamond.
I'm sorry.
Three years
I've thought of nothing except Titanic.
But I never got it.
I never let it in.