1
00:01:09,027 --> 00:01:11,020
- Up yours!
- Get out of the way!

2
00:02:30,116 --> 00:02:31,527
Fine time piece, brother?

3
00:02:33,412 --> 00:02:34,527
Goodbye.

4
00:03:24,677 --> 00:03:28,675
<i>Who's the black private dick
that's a sex machine to all the chicks?</i>

5
00:03:29,432 --> 00:03:30,463
<i>Shaft</i>

6
00:03:31,018 --> 00:03:32,346
<i>Damn right</i>

7
00:03:40,444 --> 00:03:44,858
<i>Who is the man that would risk
his neck for his brother man?</i>

8
00:03:45,490 --> 00:03:46,523
<i>Shaft</i>

9
00:03:47,202 --> 00:03:48,612
<i>Can you dig it?</i>

10
00:03:56,462 --> 00:04:00,461
<i>Who's the cat that won't cop out
when there's danger all about?</i>

11
00:04:01,468 --> 00:04:02,547
<i>Shaft</i>

12
00:04:02,928 --> 00:04:04,090
<i>Right on</i>

13
00:04:05,263 --> 00:04:07,505
<i>They say this cat is a bad mother-</i>

14
00:04:07,599 --> 00:04:08,678
<i>Shut your mouth</i>

15
00:04:08,767 --> 00:04:10,143
<i>I'm talking about Shaft</i>

16
00:04:10,228 --> 00:04:11,888
<i>Then we can dig it</i>

17
00:04:12,020 --> 00:04:14,061
<i>He's a complicated man</i>

18
00:04:14,148 --> 00:04:15,144
<i>No one understands him</i>

19
00:04:15,900 --> 00:04:17,892
<i>But his woman</i>

20
00:04:17,985 --> 00:04:19,396
<i>John Shaft</i>

21
00:04:19,738 --> 00:04:21,363
What's happening, Marty?

22
00:04:21,448 --> 00:04:23,904
Same old sixes and sevens, Shaft.

23
00:04:23,992 --> 00:04:28,120
Two guys were looking for you
like 10 minutes ago.

24
00:04:28,247 --> 00:04:29,576
Harlem cats?

25
00:04:29,958 --> 00:04:34,454
How the hell should I know?
Everybody looks the same to me.

26
00:04:36,422 --> 00:04:37,881
Take it easy, Marty.

27
00:04:38,299 --> 00:04:39,711
Take care, Shaft.

28
00:05:21,180 --> 00:05:22,556
Thanks, brother.

29
00:05:28,187 --> 00:05:30,146
Too much sugar this morning.

30
00:05:31,025 --> 00:05:32,483
Then don't drink it, baby.

31
00:05:34,695 --> 00:05:37,447
A couple of dudes from uptown
looking for you.

32
00:05:38,867 --> 00:05:39,981
Know them?

33
00:05:41,077 --> 00:05:42,275
Not by name.

34
00:05:42,829 --> 00:05:46,328
Seen them around uptown.
Come in here when I was opening up.

35
00:05:47,042 --> 00:05:49,119
Asked where they could find you.

36
00:05:49,712 --> 00:05:51,254
What did they look like?

37
00:05:51,339 --> 00:05:54,589
One was wearing a funky plaid coat.
Other one was sharp.

38
00:05:55,676 --> 00:05:59,296
$50 shoes. Black coat, gray flares.

39
00:06:01,516 --> 00:06:03,758
- Is that all?
- They had heat on them.

40
00:06:04,060 --> 00:06:07,180
The one in the plaid coat
had his hands in his pocket.

41
00:06:07,357 --> 00:06:09,396
Pulled his coat tight, you dig?

42
00:06:10,985 --> 00:06:13,061
Had some heavy iron in his belt.

43
00:06:13,488 --> 00:06:16,193
You got a scuff on the
toe of this left shoe.

44
00:06:22,915 --> 00:06:24,623
What time you got, Tom?

45
00:06:25,250 --> 00:06:26,199
8:16.

46
00:06:30,507 --> 00:06:34,635
Pull over in front of that shoe-shine
parlor. He usually hangs out there.

47
00:06:34,928 --> 00:06:35,841
Okay.

48
00:06:41,227 --> 00:06:43,682
- You want me to go in?
- No. We'll wait.

49
00:06:48,068 --> 00:06:52,481
Got yourself a nice shine. You can go out
and make something of yourself, man.

50
00:06:54,616 --> 00:06:58,615
Go out and get rich and fat like you?
We're straight, baby.

51
00:07:03,626 --> 00:07:05,120
Got a minute, Shaft?

52
00:07:05,253 --> 00:07:09,252
Got no use for no dirty postcards, Vic.
Get off my back.

53
00:07:09,633 --> 00:07:11,341
I just want to talk to you.

54
00:07:11,427 --> 00:07:13,799
Call me up. You know my number.

55
00:07:16,308 --> 00:07:20,008
Come on, I'll buy you a cup of coffee.
Go sit in the park a minute?

56
00:07:20,103 --> 00:07:23,270
Hell, no. Just tell me
what you got to say right here!

57
00:07:24,399 --> 00:07:27,686
Tom, go get us two cigars.
What kind do you smoke?

58
00:07:27,904 --> 00:07:29,980
Just say what you've got to say.

59
00:07:31,908 --> 00:07:34,280
Get us a couple of El Garcia's.

60
00:07:38,457 --> 00:07:39,916
Look, I'm late.

61
00:07:40,876 --> 00:07:43,034
What are you trying to lay on me?

62
00:07:43,128 --> 00:07:45,834
Just love, Shaft.
Nothing but love and sympathy.

63
00:07:45,924 --> 00:07:49,090
Then we're even. Go on, get on with it.

64
00:07:49,594 --> 00:07:52,263
I thought you might know something
I want to know.

65
00:07:52,388 --> 00:07:55,639
Seems there's been a lot of low,
quiet rumbles going on uptown.

66
00:07:55,726 --> 00:07:59,593
Our people have been able to pick up
the sounds of it, but not words.

67
00:07:59,688 --> 00:08:02,892
That's 'cause us black folk
talk mush mouth, Lieutenant.

68
00:08:04,778 --> 00:08:06,320
I thought we'd get to it.

69
00:08:06,404 --> 00:08:10,188
We did. But, you want me to pigeon.
I just said, "Up yours, baby."

70
00:08:12,494 --> 00:08:15,864
How come two cats from Harlem
came downtown this morning...

71
00:08:15,957 --> 00:08:17,748
...looking for John Shaft?

72
00:08:19,377 --> 00:08:23,077
They're soul brothers. They came down
so I could teach them the handshake.

73
00:08:24,883 --> 00:08:26,128
They find you?

74
00:08:26,218 --> 00:08:28,045
Of course, I wasn't hiding.

75
00:08:29,388 --> 00:08:32,970
If you find out anything, give me a call.
I'm still at the 38th Precinct.

76
00:08:34,060 --> 00:08:35,223
Right on.

77
00:08:36,563 --> 00:08:38,520
Where the hell are you going?

78
00:08:39,732 --> 00:08:42,354
To get laid. Where the hell are you going?

79
00:08:47,825 --> 00:08:50,150
That boy's got a lot of mouth on him.

80
00:08:54,583 --> 00:08:57,074
The boy's man enough to back it up, too.

81
00:08:58,460 --> 00:09:00,086
What did he tell you?

82
00:09:00,547 --> 00:09:01,578
Nothing.

83
00:09:02,090 --> 00:09:03,834
Got to lean on that kind.

84
00:09:04,802 --> 00:09:06,711
You don't lean on that kind.

85
00:09:10,390 --> 00:09:12,134
Give me a package of gum.

86
00:09:52,020 --> 00:09:54,097
Make a noise, I'll cut you. Back up.

87
00:09:54,190 --> 00:09:56,859
- Something wrong, Mr. Shaft?
- Sick friend here.

88
00:09:56,943 --> 00:09:58,900
Jim, can you get us a car up?

89
00:10:03,867 --> 00:10:05,409
I'll take that.

90
00:10:07,162 --> 00:10:08,621
Now, be cool, man.

91
00:10:20,134 --> 00:10:21,795
Where is your partner?

92
00:10:31,188 --> 00:10:32,434
Open the door.

93
00:11:17,990 --> 00:11:22,202
You've got about a half a minute
to tell me what the hell you want with me.

94
00:11:22,287 --> 00:11:26,237
The police will ask why you threw
that son of a bitch out the window.

95
00:11:27,167 --> 00:11:30,786
They can find you dead or alive.
Now, what's your goddamn story?

96
00:11:31,797 --> 00:11:32,877
Bumpy...

97
00:11:33,925 --> 00:11:36,498
Bumpy says to bring you uptown.

98
00:11:37,010 --> 00:11:39,004
Did he tell you to mess me up?

99
00:11:41,683 --> 00:11:43,177
I was to bring you.

100
00:11:48,190 --> 00:11:49,650
It doesn't make sense.

101
00:11:49,734 --> 00:11:52,735
You arrive at your office.
You have a sick friend with you.

102
00:11:52,820 --> 00:11:56,106
Suddenly, another man you don't know
rushes up and a fight starts.

103
00:11:56,240 --> 00:11:59,325
Your sick friend goes out the window.
Why, Mr. Shaft?

104
00:12:00,412 --> 00:12:03,283
Ask the man who started the fight,
Mr. Leibowitz.

105
00:12:03,457 --> 00:12:06,162
Your friend, the only name
you know him by is "Tex"?

106
00:12:06,293 --> 00:12:08,202
- No last name?
- That's right.

107
00:12:08,295 --> 00:12:09,672
I don't buy that, Shaft.

108
00:12:09,756 --> 00:12:13,670
I think you know more than that.
Why the fight started, for instance.

109
00:12:13,760 --> 00:12:16,844
What you think and what you can prove
are two different bags.

110
00:12:20,393 --> 00:12:23,228
All your friends walk around
with weapons like that?

111
00:12:24,480 --> 00:12:25,761
That depends.

112
00:12:25,856 --> 00:12:28,942
My Negro friends don't walk around
with rabbits' feet no more.

113
00:12:29,194 --> 00:12:32,230
Don't get wise with me.
There's a simple way for me to go.

114
00:12:32,364 --> 00:12:36,148
- I'll put your goddamn ass in! - I'll
sue your goddamn ass for false arrest.

115
00:12:36,243 --> 00:12:39,328
You want me to believe the man fell out
the way you said he did?

116
00:12:39,414 --> 00:12:43,494
- What do I look like? Some kind of klutz?
- Don't ask, and I won't tell you.

117
00:12:43,585 --> 00:12:45,910
You're licensed by the city and the state.

118
00:12:46,045 --> 00:12:49,747
No one licensed can afford to be a wise ass
where a felony case is involved.

119
00:12:50,134 --> 00:12:52,007
Are you suggesting I'd lose my license?

120
00:12:52,094 --> 00:12:55,261
You are damn right I am!
You better believe it and level with me!

121
00:12:56,180 --> 00:12:59,302
Threatening my livelihood is a violation
of my rights, isn't it?

122
00:13:03,940 --> 00:13:05,055
Byron...

123
00:13:08,613 --> 00:13:11,104
Let me have a talk with him in private.

124
00:13:12,742 --> 00:13:14,983
You got an assailant to interview.

125
00:13:15,119 --> 00:13:17,444
Start that and I'll join after we talk.

126
00:13:17,538 --> 00:13:21,240
I think you are b.s.-ing me, too.
This thing stinks.

127
00:13:39,020 --> 00:13:41,938
Maybe he didn't like the handshake
you taught him.

128
00:13:43,692 --> 00:13:46,777
You know you can get your rump
in a sling for this mess?

129
00:13:46,862 --> 00:13:49,781
- Static, a lot of hassle.
- You'll save me, Vic.

130
00:13:50,700 --> 00:13:52,194
Well, I can try.

131
00:13:52,452 --> 00:13:53,282
If?

132
00:13:54,370 --> 00:13:56,197
One hand washes the other.

133
00:13:56,999 --> 00:14:00,997
All the hassle in the world wouldn't
make me sing a song to the police.

134
00:14:01,963 --> 00:14:02,958
No way, baby.

135
00:14:04,799 --> 00:14:07,884
That cat you threw out the window
was a flunky for Bumpy Jonas.

136
00:14:09,054 --> 00:14:11,343
I didn't throw no cat
out no window, Lieutenant.

137
00:14:11,430 --> 00:14:13,258
Bumpy isn't gonna like it.

138
00:14:13,767 --> 00:14:17,054
I don't care what he likes!
What the hell are you pumping me for?

139
00:14:17,146 --> 00:14:19,388
Two weeks ago
we started picking up rumbles.

140
00:14:20,900 --> 00:14:23,984
- You already said that.
- We know it's not the Panthers.

141
00:14:25,113 --> 00:14:28,031
Or the Young Lords.
But, something's on the boil.

142
00:14:29,285 --> 00:14:30,945
I want to know what it is...

143
00:14:31,078 --> 00:14:34,328
...before we need an adding machine
to count the bodies.

144
00:14:34,415 --> 00:14:36,492
Bumpy wants you for something.

145
00:14:36,626 --> 00:14:39,912
He knows what's going on.
And that's what I want to know.

146
00:14:40,505 --> 00:14:42,047
Not who, just what.

147
00:14:43,340 --> 00:14:47,422
It warms my black heart to see you
so concerned about us minority folks.

148
00:14:49,640 --> 00:14:52,048
Come on, Shaft.
What is it with this black shit?

149
00:14:55,229 --> 00:14:56,772
You ain't so black.

150
00:14:58,567 --> 00:15:00,809
And you ain't so white, baby.

151
00:15:03,780 --> 00:15:04,812
All right.

152
00:15:05,950 --> 00:15:08,737
You want to play
your super heavy black number.

153
00:15:10,622 --> 00:15:12,246
I'm gonna play mine.

154
00:15:13,499 --> 00:15:17,747
We can nail your tail for manslaughter
with what we've got on you right now!

155
00:15:18,380 --> 00:15:22,460
You can waltz Leibowitz, but you
know the law. You could be charged.

156
00:15:23,177 --> 00:15:24,719
Charged, Lieutenant.

157
00:15:24,804 --> 00:15:27,212
Yeah, but your license'll be suspended.

158
00:15:27,557 --> 00:15:30,095
You'll be out of business for six months.

159
00:15:31,144 --> 00:15:33,433
You want to be out of business
for six months?

160
00:15:34,397 --> 00:15:35,857
Out on the street.

161
00:15:35,942 --> 00:15:38,349
No gun permit. Six months!

162
00:15:39,320 --> 00:15:42,985
With Bumpy looking for you
when all hell's about to break loose?

163
00:15:43,074 --> 00:15:44,450
You want it, you got it.

164
00:15:46,244 --> 00:15:48,036
You scare me to death, Lieutenant.

165
00:15:48,120 --> 00:15:52,036
You're buying trouble not only for
yourself, but a blood bath up in Harlem.

166
00:15:52,125 --> 00:15:53,074
You want that?

167
00:15:55,630 --> 00:15:58,797
All I'm asking you is to let me know
what's going on!

168
00:15:59,217 --> 00:16:01,340
No names, no places, just what!

169
00:16:04,473 --> 00:16:06,549
I'm not asking you to sell out.

170
00:16:08,852 --> 00:16:11,343
Tell me the name of the game,
so I know the rules.

171
00:16:27,373 --> 00:16:28,915
I'll think about it.

172
00:16:31,210 --> 00:16:33,167
All right, I'll settle for that now.

173
00:16:34,089 --> 00:16:37,707
That buys you 48 hours on the street,
and then we're gonna talk again.

174
00:16:38,760 --> 00:16:41,547
You got the number
of Bumpy's private phone?

175
00:16:44,017 --> 00:16:45,048
All right.

176
00:16:45,935 --> 00:16:48,177
Take off. I'll see to Leibowitz.

177
00:16:50,523 --> 00:16:51,686
Right on.

178
00:16:53,652 --> 00:16:54,897
I'll see you.

179
00:17:04,414 --> 00:17:05,659
Look at that.

180
00:17:43,499 --> 00:17:46,619
- Wrong number.
- Don't bull me, I got the right number.

181
00:17:46,710 --> 00:17:47,908
This is Shaft.

182
00:17:48,003 --> 00:17:49,877
How did you get this number?

183
00:17:49,964 --> 00:17:52,634
Off a bathroom wall
in the goddamn subway.

184
00:17:53,093 --> 00:17:54,717
I'm looking for you.

185
00:17:55,136 --> 00:17:56,631
I've got an office.

186
00:18:08,985 --> 00:18:10,265
Here you are.

187
00:18:10,653 --> 00:18:11,685
Thanks.

188
00:18:11,863 --> 00:18:14,568
Bag of chestnuts, please.
Cold as hell today, huh?

189
00:18:14,866 --> 00:18:17,536
Yeah, yeah. Good chestnuts.

190
00:18:19,579 --> 00:18:20,694
How much?

191
00:18:20,789 --> 00:18:21,953
Two bits.

192
00:18:22,040 --> 00:18:23,998
- Here you go. Take it easy.
- Thanks.

193
00:18:24,085 --> 00:18:25,248
Hey, taxi!

194
00:18:30,634 --> 00:18:32,342
What the hell is this?

195
00:18:33,262 --> 00:18:34,673
You white mother!

196
00:18:37,266 --> 00:18:38,464
Taxi! Taxi!

197
00:19:23,692 --> 00:19:26,314
Cat say he gonna be here,
he should be here.

198
00:19:26,445 --> 00:19:27,608
Open it up.

199
00:19:56,520 --> 00:19:58,347
Cat say he gonna be here...

200
00:20:00,066 --> 00:20:01,477
...and he ain't.

201
00:20:03,653 --> 00:20:05,811
It ain't right, Boss.

202
00:20:07,448 --> 00:20:08,778
We'll wait.

203
00:20:12,037 --> 00:20:13,864
You take crap off of him...

204
00:20:14,290 --> 00:20:16,199
...he'll give you more crap.

205
00:20:17,584 --> 00:20:18,748
We'll wait.

206
00:20:19,796 --> 00:20:21,539
That's some cold shit...

207
00:20:23,090 --> 00:20:25,629
...throwing my man, Leroy,
out the window.

208
00:20:26,803 --> 00:20:30,671
Just picked my man up, and threw him
out the goddamned window.

209
00:20:32,435 --> 00:20:35,886
Got us standing around and waiting
to say thank you.

210
00:20:41,820 --> 00:20:43,896
Glad you let yourself in, Bumpy.

211
00:20:45,699 --> 00:20:48,487
Give me a bad name,
have you hanging around in the hall.

212
00:20:51,456 --> 00:20:53,662
If the man ever comes down here...

213
00:20:54,375 --> 00:20:56,083
...again to see you...

214
00:20:56,794 --> 00:20:58,954
...you make sure you be here.

215
00:21:00,090 --> 00:21:01,122
Waiting.

216
00:21:02,092 --> 00:21:03,587
You're in my chair.

217
00:21:22,030 --> 00:21:23,276
Wait outside.

218
00:21:32,376 --> 00:21:34,783
Sims and Leroy tried to muscle you, Shaft?

219
00:21:38,800 --> 00:21:40,958
Well, I got no grudge about Leroy.

220
00:21:41,427 --> 00:21:42,838
I couldn't give a damn.

221
00:21:43,179 --> 00:21:44,424
I got a job for you.

222
00:21:45,640 --> 00:21:47,349
I'm not on the hustle, Bumpy.

223
00:21:47,643 --> 00:21:48,722
A detective job.

224
00:21:51,020 --> 00:21:53,180
- What kind?
- Your kind. You take it.

225
00:21:54,942 --> 00:21:57,268
Don't jive me. What are you talking about?

226
00:21:57,362 --> 00:21:59,734
Somebody kidnapped my daughter, Marcy.

227
00:21:59,948 --> 00:22:01,775
Done in a couple of people.

228
00:22:01,866 --> 00:22:05,235
Didn't leave no ransom note or nothing.
Nobody saw nothing.

229
00:22:06,038 --> 00:22:08,825
I want you to find her.
That's the fucking job.

230
00:22:11,252 --> 00:22:13,161
The police do that for free.

231
00:22:13,629 --> 00:22:16,300
Not for me. You know I can't go
to the cops.

232
00:22:17,426 --> 00:22:18,836
And you want me?

233
00:22:19,803 --> 00:22:21,048
The spade detective.

234
00:22:21,430 --> 00:22:24,384
Yeah, I want you 'cause
you're a black spade detective.

235
00:22:24,474 --> 00:22:29,137
I want you 'cause you got your other foot
in whitey's trough! She can be anywhere.

236
00:22:32,025 --> 00:22:33,649
Got any idea who grabbed her?

237
00:22:36,030 --> 00:22:37,903
A lot of cats hate my guts.

238
00:22:39,408 --> 00:22:42,195
A sweet, loving dude like you?

239
00:22:43,662 --> 00:22:45,371
Sweet talking a man's lady...

240
00:22:45,498 --> 00:22:49,081
...as you beat her man out of his paycheck
in the back room of a horse parlor?

241
00:22:49,169 --> 00:22:51,375
Feeding his kid shit to shoot in his arm?

242
00:22:53,965 --> 00:22:55,793
Who could hate you, Bumpy?

243
00:22:56,552 --> 00:23:00,597
My baby never sold nothing to nobody.
Never took nothing from nobody.

244
00:23:01,766 --> 00:23:04,518
She's a straight kid.
She's going to college.

245
00:23:07,189 --> 00:23:09,894
Whoever grabbed her, got her to get at me.

246
00:23:11,234 --> 00:23:14,604
They have a beef with me,
they should come to me.

247
00:23:16,115 --> 00:23:18,689
So you got a rule
that somebody else don't.

248
00:23:24,458 --> 00:23:26,083
Is that all you know?

249
00:23:26,168 --> 00:23:30,296
There's a piece of Harlem I can't get at.
The one them militants got their arm on.

250
00:23:31,173 --> 00:23:34,625
They could have my baby.
She's been into some of that stuff.

251
00:23:35,428 --> 00:23:38,215
Bunch calls themselves the "La Mumba's."

252
00:23:38,974 --> 00:23:40,468
Ben Buford's thing.

253
00:23:41,600 --> 00:23:43,642
I could send my people to ask them.

254
00:23:44,855 --> 00:23:45,851
Shit.

255
00:23:46,774 --> 00:23:51,103
It'd come to a shootout and when
it's all over, a bunch of dead cats.

256
00:23:52,863 --> 00:23:54,442
And maybe they'd kill Marcy.

257
00:23:57,619 --> 00:23:59,659
Yeah, you're Papa pimp to them.

258
00:24:01,039 --> 00:24:04,456
They want to see you burn
as bad as they want to see the police burn.

259
00:24:04,960 --> 00:24:07,416
But kidnapping sisters,
that ain't their thing.

260
00:24:07,547 --> 00:24:10,464
The only reason anybody grabs
anybody for is money.

261
00:24:10,590 --> 00:24:14,804
What other bunch in Harlem needs money
bad enough to grab my baby?

262
00:24:14,888 --> 00:24:18,838
If you believe that, what's all this
about me having a foot in whitey's trough?

263
00:24:18,934 --> 00:24:22,101
I said I think they had her.
I didn't say they had her in Harlem.

264
00:24:22,187 --> 00:24:24,893
They ain't dumb enough
to take her someplace uptown.

265
00:24:26,860 --> 00:24:28,105
It don't lay right.

266
00:24:28,236 --> 00:24:31,272
What the hell you think I need you for
if I knew who had her?

267
00:24:33,700 --> 00:24:34,981
I'm guessing.

268
00:24:36,203 --> 00:24:38,529
If they don't have her, all right.

269
00:24:38,830 --> 00:24:40,622
Maybe they know something.

270
00:24:41,709 --> 00:24:43,121
I got nothing.

271
00:24:43,962 --> 00:24:45,587
That's the job, Shaft.

272
00:24:48,175 --> 00:24:49,550
Will you take it, or no?

273
00:24:54,098 --> 00:24:55,758
I get $50 an hour.

274
00:24:57,018 --> 00:24:58,263
Plus expenses.

275
00:25:00,355 --> 00:25:02,597
And no questions asked
about how I spend it.

276
00:25:04,026 --> 00:25:05,188
You got it.

277
00:25:05,402 --> 00:25:07,940
I get a free hand to move any way I want.

278
00:25:12,452 --> 00:25:14,112
You find my baby.

279
00:25:17,290 --> 00:25:18,749
That's all I want.

280
00:25:21,920 --> 00:25:23,166
I got money.

281
00:25:25,466 --> 00:25:26,711
You spend it.

282
00:25:28,928 --> 00:25:30,339
And you find her.

283
00:25:43,695 --> 00:25:45,403
That'll get you started.

284
00:26:04,342 --> 00:26:06,134
When will I hear from you?

285
00:26:10,307 --> 00:26:12,217
When I got something to say.

286
00:26:14,770 --> 00:26:16,264
One more thing:

287
00:26:19,358 --> 00:26:23,986
You send another cat after me with a gun,
I'll kill him and I'll come looking for you!

288
00:26:25,198 --> 00:26:26,990
And I'll get you, Bumpy.

289
00:26:27,200 --> 00:26:28,481
You believe it.

290
00:26:51,353 --> 00:26:52,598
Fake mother.

291
00:27:01,405 --> 00:27:04,774
<i>Black man born free</i>

292
00:27:04,909 --> 00:27:06,700
You seen Ben Buford around?

293
00:27:06,827 --> 00:27:09,319
<i>The way it's supposed to be</i>

294
00:27:09,414 --> 00:27:13,032
<i>Chains that bind him are hard to see</i>

295
00:27:13,710 --> 00:27:17,044
<i>Unless you take this walk with me</i>

296
00:27:18,048 --> 00:27:20,540
<i>The place where he lives</i>

297
00:27:21,636 --> 00:27:25,634
<i>It's got plenty of names</i>
<i>Slums</i>

298
00:27:26,474 --> 00:27:29,476
Ben Buford used to live here.
He live here anymore?

299
00:27:30,354 --> 00:27:31,385
No, why?

300
00:27:32,189 --> 00:27:33,767
I'm looking for him.

301
00:27:33,857 --> 00:27:36,431
I am, too. He owes me six months' rent.

302
00:27:38,112 --> 00:27:39,523
Take it easy.

303
00:27:42,534 --> 00:27:45,700
<i>Any kind of job is hard to find</i>

304
00:27:46,037 --> 00:27:49,205
<i>And that means an increase in the welfare line</i>

305
00:27:50,084 --> 00:27:53,085
<i>Crime rate is rising too</i>

306
00:27:54,296 --> 00:27:57,297
<i>If you are hungry, what would you do?</i>

307
00:27:58,468 --> 00:28:01,469
<i>Rent is two months past due</i>

308
00:28:02,430 --> 00:28:05,467
<i>And the building is falling apart</i>

309
00:28:06,727 --> 00:28:09,894
<i>Little boy who needs a pair of shoes</i>

310
00:28:14,986 --> 00:28:18,403
Hello, ma'am. I'm looking for a guy
named Ben Buford. You know him?

311
00:28:18,490 --> 00:28:19,866
Yeah, I know him.

312
00:28:19,950 --> 00:28:22,785
- Seen him around here lately?
- Not in a long while.

313
00:28:22,870 --> 00:28:26,036
<i>Some of the brothers got plenty of cash</i>

314
00:28:26,957 --> 00:28:30,125
<i>Chicks on the corner gonna see to that</i>

315
00:28:30,879 --> 00:28:34,045
<i>Some like to smoke, some like to blow</i>

316
00:28:35,008 --> 00:28:38,176
<i>Some even strung out on a $50 jones</i>

317
00:28:39,764 --> 00:28:42,599
<i>Some are trying to ditch reality</i>

318
00:28:43,934 --> 00:28:46,604
<i>By getting so, so high</i>

319
00:28:47,898 --> 00:28:53,058
<i>Only to find out that you can never touch the sky</i>

320
00:28:53,195 --> 00:28:55,768
I'm looking for Ben Buford.
You seen him around?

321
00:28:55,906 --> 00:28:57,698
No, I ain't seen him.

322
00:28:58,659 --> 00:28:59,691
Thanks.

323
00:29:00,745 --> 00:29:03,034
Know what the number was today?

324
00:29:03,706 --> 00:29:06,281
<i>Every Sunday morning</i>

325
00:29:06,585 --> 00:29:09,871
<i>I can hear the old sisters say</i>

326
00:29:10,422 --> 00:29:14,337
<i>Hallelujah, hallelujah</i>

327
00:29:14,468 --> 00:29:16,343
<i>Trust in the Lord</i>

328
00:29:16,429 --> 00:29:18,422
<i>He'll make a way</i>

329
00:29:20,140 --> 00:29:22,976
<i>I hope that he hears their prayers</i>

330
00:29:24,270 --> 00:29:26,941
<i>'Cause deep in their souls they believe</i>

331
00:29:28,943 --> 00:29:31,101
<i>Someday he'll put an end</i>

332
00:29:31,862 --> 00:29:34,021
<i>To all this misery</i>

333
00:29:34,949 --> 00:29:37,108
- <i>That's in</i>
- Soulsville

334
00:29:43,500 --> 00:29:45,160
<i>Soulsville</i>

335
00:30:04,314 --> 00:30:06,557
- What's happening?
- Man, how's it going?

336
00:30:06,650 --> 00:30:07,730
Seen Ben?

337
00:30:08,987 --> 00:30:10,398
Ben? Ben who?

338
00:30:11,072 --> 00:30:12,899
Ben Buford. You know who I mean.

339
00:30:13,783 --> 00:30:16,536
Look, man, I don't know no Ben Buford.

340
00:30:18,289 --> 00:30:19,154
$20.

341
00:30:20,499 --> 00:30:22,207
That Ben Buford.

342
00:30:22,710 --> 00:30:25,878
He's holed up on a place
on Amsterdam, 710.

343
00:30:27,007 --> 00:30:28,881
What apartment and what time?

344
00:30:29,259 --> 00:30:32,593
Third floor. There's a meeting at 9:00.

345
00:30:33,555 --> 00:30:35,134
I can't guarantee it.

346
00:30:35,933 --> 00:30:38,389
I just heard some cat tell another cat.

347
00:30:39,479 --> 00:30:41,555
They're both in the movement with Ben.

348
00:30:43,983 --> 00:30:45,941
Yeah, well, stay loose, baby.

349
00:31:16,728 --> 00:31:18,104
You all right?

350
00:31:19,106 --> 00:31:20,814
Baby, are you all right?

351
00:31:22,275 --> 00:31:26,025
I got to feeling like a machine.
That's no way to feel.

352
00:31:30,243 --> 00:31:31,785
Come here, baby.

353
00:32:45,200 --> 00:32:47,822
Had a visitor from uptown this afternoon.

354
00:32:49,330 --> 00:32:50,575
What're you having?

355
00:32:50,706 --> 00:32:52,499
A dog with mustard and onions.

356
00:32:53,502 --> 00:32:54,367
No.

357
00:32:54,460 --> 00:32:55,836
Hold the onions.

358
00:32:59,508 --> 00:33:00,503
Cold, huh?

359
00:33:05,640 --> 00:33:07,383
Well, John, what did you get?

360
00:33:14,440 --> 00:33:15,770
I got laid.

361
00:33:36,090 --> 00:33:39,673
Uptown, brother. Amsterdam Avenue.
Take your time. I'm early.

362
00:34:31,902 --> 00:34:33,277
Champ, you lost?

363
00:34:33,487 --> 00:34:34,317
No.

364
00:34:35,405 --> 00:34:36,947
You live around here?

365
00:34:37,032 --> 00:34:37,981
Yeah.

366
00:34:39,452 --> 00:34:40,697
You look cold.

367
00:34:46,542 --> 00:34:48,120
Get something to eat.

368
00:34:49,296 --> 00:34:50,838
Gee, thanks, mister.

369
00:34:51,173 --> 00:34:52,501
Okay, champ.

370
00:36:11,928 --> 00:36:13,838
- Who is it?
- John Shaft, Ben.

371
00:36:33,202 --> 00:36:36,987
Unless you want more visitors,
better split up that pair out front.

372
00:36:39,209 --> 00:36:41,248
Put somebody on the basement door.

373
00:36:42,295 --> 00:36:43,623
How did you find me?

374
00:36:43,713 --> 00:36:46,252
Wasn't hard. You got a big mouth.

375
00:36:48,344 --> 00:36:50,751
- Cool it, man.
- You cool it, boy.

376
00:36:54,183 --> 00:36:56,889
Don't let your mouth
get your ass in trouble.

377
00:36:59,439 --> 00:37:02,109
- I got nothing to say to you.
- Don't jive me.

378
00:37:04,360 --> 00:37:08,360
- We've put in a lot of street time
together. - That was a long time back.

379
00:37:08,740 --> 00:37:10,533
I don't know you no more.

380
00:37:10,660 --> 00:37:13,945
A lot of hard years, man.
The kind you don't forget.

381
00:37:17,960 --> 00:37:21,827
Now, I'm gonna give you one minute
to say what you came here to say.

382
00:37:23,048 --> 00:37:26,798
Then you go back out that door
you came in or I'll throw you out.

383
00:37:29,139 --> 00:37:30,681
You know Marcy Jonas?

384
00:37:30,765 --> 00:37:32,888
- Yeah, why?
- You know where she is?

385
00:37:33,393 --> 00:37:35,766
- What do you mean?
- Somebody grabbed her.

386
00:37:37,148 --> 00:37:39,140
Bumpy thinks maybe it was you.

387
00:37:42,194 --> 00:37:44,234
We don't do that kind of thing.

388
00:37:44,405 --> 00:37:46,280
You know anything about it?

389
00:37:47,993 --> 00:37:50,235
Tom, you used up your minute. Get out!

390
00:37:50,328 --> 00:37:51,823
Don't "Tom" me, man!

391
00:37:52,497 --> 00:37:54,324
- Where are the guns?
- None here.

392
00:37:54,417 --> 00:37:55,911
I'll be goddamned!

393
00:37:59,672 --> 00:38:01,416
Sonny! Sonny!

394
00:38:01,758 --> 00:38:02,789
They're coming!

395
00:38:02,925 --> 00:38:04,634
- Up on the roof?
- Yeah. Go!

396
00:38:08,056 --> 00:38:09,052
He's dead.

397
00:38:09,140 --> 00:38:10,552
Come on, come on!

398
00:38:11,769 --> 00:38:13,560
Not the roof, this way!

399
00:38:22,322 --> 00:38:23,484
Stand back.

400
00:38:24,867 --> 00:38:27,109
- What is this?
- Everything will be fine.

401
00:38:27,244 --> 00:38:30,162
- What is this?
- Go over there and be quiet.

402
00:39:21,010 --> 00:39:23,800
Everything's okay, ma'am.
No need to worry.

403
00:39:25,559 --> 00:39:27,136
Sorry about your door.

404
00:39:27,560 --> 00:39:29,304
That'll take care of it.

405
00:39:31,314 --> 00:39:32,810
You set us up, man!

406
00:39:35,069 --> 00:39:36,694
Young man, please.

407
00:39:37,864 --> 00:39:39,144
Don't do that.

408
00:39:39,407 --> 00:39:44,319
Don't ever threaten me again!
And don't call me Judas!

409
00:40:26,167 --> 00:40:29,287
Come on. It's no time
to count your dead. Come on!

410
00:40:45,396 --> 00:40:46,345
Look.

411
00:40:53,656 --> 00:40:54,770
Come on!

412
00:41:00,622 --> 00:41:02,164
This way, this way!

413
00:41:06,336 --> 00:41:07,665
One of yours?

414
00:41:09,005 --> 00:41:10,833
- No.
- Probably a finger man.

415
00:41:27,150 --> 00:41:30,817
When you lead that revolution,
whitey better be standing still...

416
00:41:31,406 --> 00:41:33,612
...'cause you don't run
worth a damn no more!

417
00:41:33,740 --> 00:41:35,117
We're done running, man.

418
00:41:35,200 --> 00:41:37,573
What the hell do you call this, man?

419
00:41:57,976 --> 00:42:01,013
I got to find out if
they're after you or me.

420
00:42:11,909 --> 00:42:14,993
I'll leave you with some friends.
They're straight people.

421
00:42:15,329 --> 00:42:18,365
So don't you lay any of
that Uncle Tom jive on them.

422
00:42:24,839 --> 00:42:28,838
I don't know what's connected to what.
I can't piece them together.

423
00:42:28,928 --> 00:42:30,126
Answer that.

424
00:42:31,138 --> 00:42:35,634
It's only a half an hour since it happened.
How could I have something this soon?

425
00:42:36,685 --> 00:42:41,479
I'm not paid enough to worry about what
the Commissioner or the Mayor thinks!

426
00:42:41,817 --> 00:42:43,975
It's Shaft. You want to talk to him?

427
00:42:44,069 --> 00:42:46,690
I got a call. I might have something.
Hold on.

428
00:42:46,988 --> 00:42:48,947
No, better I call you back.

429
00:42:52,120 --> 00:42:53,744
I'm coming to see you.

430
00:42:54,455 --> 00:42:56,448
You've been holding out on me.

431
00:42:56,833 --> 00:43:00,285
I'll wait. Listen, several cats
were killed in Harlem.

432
00:43:00,379 --> 00:43:02,003
You know anything about it?

433
00:43:02,089 --> 00:43:03,880
I was there, Lieutenant.

434
00:43:13,768 --> 00:43:18,063
The Captain's at home. Call him back.
Tell him I left to chase down a lead.

435
00:43:18,232 --> 00:43:21,518
- Where are you going?
- Nowhere. Just get him off my back.

436
00:43:21,610 --> 00:43:24,232
A reporter from the News
wants an interview.

437
00:43:25,239 --> 00:43:28,691
Tell him to call the Captain.
Serves the old bastard right.

438
00:43:30,120 --> 00:43:32,611
This is that list
from the intelligence section.

439
00:43:32,914 --> 00:43:34,290
What about the pictures?

440
00:43:34,374 --> 00:43:37,661
They're getting them together now.
Said about five minutes.

441
00:43:37,753 --> 00:43:40,327
Shaft's coming down. Send him right in.

442
00:43:55,189 --> 00:43:58,475
Dina'll get you a bed made up.
Why don't you get some sleep, man?

443
00:44:00,570 --> 00:44:02,895
Got some dead brothers laying out there.

444
00:44:03,740 --> 00:44:05,649
And this ain't where I should be.

445
00:44:06,076 --> 00:44:09,576
Till we find out why they're dead,
this is the only place for you to be!

446
00:44:09,914 --> 00:44:11,491
You think like a white man!

447
00:44:11,582 --> 00:44:13,160
You don't think! You want to get wasted?

448
00:44:13,250 --> 00:44:14,792
If that's what it takes!

449
00:44:14,877 --> 00:44:16,835
Marvin's sleeping.

450
00:44:22,886 --> 00:44:25,758
I'll find out what I can and pick you up
in the morning.

451
00:44:26,849 --> 00:44:29,174
If you think I'll owe you for this,
you're wrong.

452
00:44:29,310 --> 00:44:30,888
You got nothing I want!

453
00:44:32,897 --> 00:44:34,724
You can have the girls' room.

454
00:44:39,320 --> 00:44:43,319
I got to go out. Got an extra key
so I don't wake you when I come back?

455
00:44:51,459 --> 00:44:53,867
This'll open the downstairs door, too.

456
00:44:55,548 --> 00:44:56,958
Watch your mouth.

457
00:44:57,090 --> 00:44:58,502
I'll say anything I want.

458
00:44:59,385 --> 00:45:02,006
Not in this house. Not here, you won't.

459
00:45:26,582 --> 00:45:27,577
Have a chair.

460
00:45:28,125 --> 00:45:29,702
I don't like your chair.

461
00:45:32,212 --> 00:45:34,253
You gave me nothing, Vic.

462
00:45:34,507 --> 00:45:38,719
You want to lock me up for manslaughter
'cause someone went out of my window...

463
00:45:39,804 --> 00:45:40,967
...go ahead.

464
00:45:41,389 --> 00:45:42,931
You got no deal.

465
00:45:44,935 --> 00:45:48,185
I have nothing else to give you, then.
That's straight.

466
00:45:49,023 --> 00:45:50,398
What do you got now?

467
00:45:50,483 --> 00:45:52,025
One question first.

468
00:45:52,109 --> 00:45:55,728
Anyone who could've identified those guys
with machine guns got wiped out!

469
00:45:55,822 --> 00:45:56,736
Yeah?

470
00:45:56,823 --> 00:46:00,607
Five of Ben Buford's people
and probably the guy that fingered you.

471
00:46:01,660 --> 00:46:04,200
Me? Are you sure it's me?

472
00:46:05,625 --> 00:46:08,542
I'd be sure if I knew if the guys
were black or white.

473
00:46:08,836 --> 00:46:10,793
I'd make it 80-20 they were after you.

474
00:46:10,880 --> 00:46:13,337
But Bumpy could probably tell you that
for sure.

475
00:46:13,425 --> 00:46:15,050
Just say what you got, man.

476
00:46:17,054 --> 00:46:18,714
A few things that may fit.

477
00:46:20,933 --> 00:46:24,599
Do you remember I told you that Bumpy
was doubling his crews up in Harlem?

478
00:46:24,687 --> 00:46:25,517
So?

479
00:46:25,605 --> 00:46:27,645
So, downtown we get some visitors.

480
00:46:28,274 --> 00:46:32,402
Three guys from LA, two from Phoenix,
a guy from Decatur, Illinois...

481
00:46:33,322 --> 00:46:36,773
...four guys from Philly.
Altogether about 15 that we're sure of.

482
00:46:37,618 --> 00:46:38,781
Special guys, huh?

483
00:46:38,869 --> 00:46:41,158
All suspected being guns for the Mafia.

484
00:46:41,330 --> 00:46:42,909
Just got into town.

485
00:46:43,250 --> 00:46:46,701
Most of them staying at a hotel
in the Village. Taking in the sights.

486
00:46:49,464 --> 00:46:50,460
Is that it?

487
00:46:50,549 --> 00:46:52,341
No, one thing more.

488
00:46:53,219 --> 00:46:56,552
A couple of dudes from Harlem
go across to Jersey.

489
00:46:57,306 --> 00:47:00,094
Try to kidnap some Mafia bigwig.
They blew it.

490
00:47:00,434 --> 00:47:02,095
They killed the guy's runner.

491
00:47:02,187 --> 00:47:05,307
But the man says his runner
was in Florida on a fishing trip.

492
00:47:08,569 --> 00:47:10,894
- Looks like war coming.
- It's a bad thing.

493
00:47:11,823 --> 00:47:14,859
Mafia against Bumpy.
It's hood against hood, on the inside.

494
00:47:14,993 --> 00:47:17,199
On the outside, it's black against white.

495
00:47:19,205 --> 00:47:23,156
We could have tanks and troops
on Broadway if this thing breaks open.

496
00:47:24,670 --> 00:47:26,544
Yeah, you got a point.

497
00:47:27,256 --> 00:47:29,925
This is what some of
our visitors look like.

498
00:47:31,470 --> 00:47:33,130
Be a good time for it.

499
00:47:33,220 --> 00:47:34,419
What? War?

500
00:47:35,140 --> 00:47:36,848
Fishing down in Florida.

501
00:47:37,434 --> 00:47:40,055
It might help if I knew
what Bumpy hired you for.

502
00:47:40,270 --> 00:47:42,098
- Never said he did.
- He did.

503
00:47:43,608 --> 00:47:46,099
It's against my ethics to say yes or no.

504
00:47:46,860 --> 00:47:49,269
- He put you on the spot, Shaft.
- He did?

505
00:47:50,865 --> 00:47:52,859
You're a very wise Caucasian, Vic.

506
00:47:54,160 --> 00:47:58,111
I'll be here. If I'm not, call me at home.

507
00:47:59,374 --> 00:48:00,834
That's a comfort.

508
00:48:11,388 --> 00:48:12,931
- Hello?
- Hello, baby.

509
00:48:13,974 --> 00:48:15,006
I waited up.

510
00:48:15,726 --> 00:48:18,015
- Sorry, I can't make it.
- Got problems?

511
00:48:19,605 --> 00:48:21,231
Yeah, I got a couple of them.

512
00:48:22,067 --> 00:48:25,767
I was born black and I was born poor.

513
00:48:27,948 --> 00:48:28,897
I love you.

514
00:48:30,785 --> 00:48:31,947
Yeah, I know.

515
00:48:32,995 --> 00:48:34,240
Take it easy.

516
00:48:49,012 --> 00:48:50,009
Get up.

517
00:48:50,932 --> 00:48:52,391
We've got a man to see.

518
00:49:10,996 --> 00:49:13,035
See who that is, will you?

519
00:49:23,926 --> 00:49:25,255
It's Shaft.

520
00:49:27,472 --> 00:49:28,801
Let him in.

521
00:49:40,820 --> 00:49:43,857
- I have an appointment with Bumpy.
- I know all about it.

522
00:49:46,242 --> 00:49:49,197
I've got to see if you're clean
before you can see the man.

523
00:49:50,456 --> 00:49:52,828
Better get yourself six more helpers then.

524
00:49:55,169 --> 00:49:56,628
That's how it's done.

525
00:49:57,046 --> 00:49:58,375
Who searches you?

526
00:49:58,632 --> 00:49:59,711
Nobody.

527
00:50:00,509 --> 00:50:02,964
Then get the same cat to search us.

528
00:50:06,765 --> 00:50:09,767
I've got to see if you got a gun on you
before you go in.

529
00:50:11,604 --> 00:50:14,060
Tell Bumpy we were here. Come on, Ben.

530
00:50:14,315 --> 00:50:16,058
You gonna let them walk now, Willy?

531
00:50:16,567 --> 00:50:18,312
Bumpy'll have your tail.

532
00:50:21,990 --> 00:50:24,197
Wait here, I'll call in to the man.

533
00:50:30,040 --> 00:50:31,784
What do you want, Willy?

534
00:50:32,335 --> 00:50:35,336
- Shaft's out here with some dude.
- Send them in.

535
00:50:35,713 --> 00:50:38,170
He won't let me see if they are clean.

536
00:50:38,592 --> 00:50:39,921
Let them in.

537
00:50:41,929 --> 00:50:43,423
Go on, you heard him.

538
00:50:46,809 --> 00:50:48,304
Listen, Snow White...

539
00:50:49,770 --> 00:50:51,894
...we're gonna tangle sooner or later.

540
00:50:54,150 --> 00:50:55,728
Did you hear what I said?

541
00:50:55,902 --> 00:50:58,311
Why don't you stop playing with yourself?

542
00:50:59,365 --> 00:51:01,073
You ain't gonna do shit!

543
00:51:31,108 --> 00:51:33,017
You're a cagey spook, Bumpy.

544
00:51:33,152 --> 00:51:35,643
You ride a tall horse, Mr. Shaft.

545
00:51:36,573 --> 00:51:41,199
This is Ben Buford. Your little caper
cost him five friends last night.

546
00:51:42,329 --> 00:51:45,781
- We'll take it out of your ass, pimp.
- You're pushing me a little far.

547
00:51:46,834 --> 00:51:48,827
I found out some things, Bumpy.

548
00:51:49,920 --> 00:51:53,918
You knew who grabbed your daughter,
and that it wasn't Ben or his people...

549
00:51:54,175 --> 00:51:56,548
...when you laid all that jive on me
in my office.

550
00:51:56,637 --> 00:52:00,136
I told you, there was no note.
I still don't know who has her.

551
00:52:00,474 --> 00:52:01,754
You're lying, man!

552
00:52:01,934 --> 00:52:04,888
Now, deal them up straight,
or don't deal them at all!

553
00:52:05,020 --> 00:52:07,594
You grabbed the dope hustle up here
from the Mafia.

554
00:52:08,024 --> 00:52:09,851
Made yourself some big bread.

555
00:52:09,984 --> 00:52:12,191
Now the Mafia wants to move in on you.

556
00:52:19,995 --> 00:52:20,909
So what?

557
00:52:21,038 --> 00:52:22,912
So, the Mafia grabbed your daughter.

558
00:52:23,457 --> 00:52:24,453
You knew it.

559
00:52:25,000 --> 00:52:26,661
You knew it when you hired me.

560
00:52:30,257 --> 00:52:31,003
Yeah.

561
00:52:31,883 --> 00:52:34,125
You tried to snatch one for a trade.

562
00:52:34,720 --> 00:52:36,927
But your flunky friends out there blew it.

563
00:52:37,515 --> 00:52:41,678
They burned some kid. Missed the man
we wanted to grab for a trade.

564
00:52:43,729 --> 00:52:45,604
Then you wanted to hustle old Shaft.

565
00:52:45,732 --> 00:52:49,066
I hired you for a job. I conned you,
but I never lied to you.

566
00:52:49,736 --> 00:52:51,147
My baby was grabbed.

567
00:52:51,738 --> 00:52:55,191
You'll get her back. You bought that deal.
You're gonna live with it.

568
00:52:57,912 --> 00:52:59,704
Not at these prices, baby.

569
00:53:06,839 --> 00:53:09,591
I told you what it costs, it costs.

570
00:53:13,429 --> 00:53:16,965
A lot of hyped-up black people give you
that money you're spending, pimp!

571
00:53:22,063 --> 00:53:25,647
Don't you try to bullshit me, boy.
We're all on the hustle.

572
00:53:26,819 --> 00:53:29,026
I sell broads and dope and numbers.

573
00:53:29,322 --> 00:53:32,073
You sell crap and blue sky.
It's all the same game.

574
00:53:35,870 --> 00:53:38,788
You knew the Mafia cats would come
after me, didn't you?

575
00:53:39,416 --> 00:53:41,243
But it doesn't shake me up.

576
00:53:41,710 --> 00:53:44,202
They made a good move
to take out my front man.

577
00:53:44,380 --> 00:53:46,669
They'll probably try again. I would.

578
00:53:47,926 --> 00:53:50,499
You been using me, Bumpy. Suckered me.

579
00:53:52,639 --> 00:53:55,309
That's okay. We stood face to face.

580
00:53:56,852 --> 00:53:59,972
But, I want to know why you wanted me
to hook up with Ben.

581
00:54:05,737 --> 00:54:08,738
'Cause you're gonna need an army
to get my baby back.

582
00:54:09,740 --> 00:54:10,737
Ben's got one.

583
00:54:11,034 --> 00:54:13,360
My people ain't worth a damn
outside of Harlem.

584
00:54:13,620 --> 00:54:16,492
If you think I'd risk
some of the brothers...

585
00:54:16,582 --> 00:54:19,951
...just 'cause your daughter's black,
you're wrong, man.

586
00:54:22,046 --> 00:54:23,245
We need money.

587
00:54:25,259 --> 00:54:27,500
I got a lot of brothers
and sisters in jail.

588
00:54:27,886 --> 00:54:28,835
Set a price.

589
00:54:34,102 --> 00:54:35,430
$10,000 a head.

590
00:54:38,106 --> 00:54:41,605
That's what the honky government
pays a cat in the Army for insurance.

591
00:54:42,653 --> 00:54:44,028
$10,000 a man.

592
00:54:46,240 --> 00:54:47,520
That's our price.

593
00:54:51,830 --> 00:54:52,826
All right.

594
00:54:57,710 --> 00:55:01,162
You telling me you're willing to lay out
that kind of bread for Marcy?

595
00:55:02,884 --> 00:55:04,294
Don't jive me, man.

596
00:55:05,303 --> 00:55:07,011
I can always get more money.

597
00:55:08,639 --> 00:55:09,920
I only got one baby.

598
00:55:10,933 --> 00:55:14,635
That means you already owe him $50,000
for the men he lost last night.

599
00:55:15,939 --> 00:55:16,971
All right.

600
00:55:19,400 --> 00:55:22,486
We can get a lot of brothers and sisters
out of jail with that.

601
00:55:22,572 --> 00:55:24,150
How many of his you'll need?

602
00:55:25,240 --> 00:55:27,649
Depends on whether
the Mafia will take a ransom.

603
00:55:28,286 --> 00:55:32,154
- They want Harlem, nothing less.
- It ain't yours to give. Not anymore.

604
00:55:32,290 --> 00:55:34,284
Mine or not, it's not gonna be theirs.

605
00:55:34,418 --> 00:55:37,834
All I gotta do is find out
where they've got her and bring her home.

606
00:55:38,464 --> 00:55:39,329
That's it.

607
00:55:39,798 --> 00:55:42,373
If he's worth $10,000, I'm worth $20,000.

608
00:55:44,346 --> 00:55:45,840
You got it, COD.

609
00:55:46,430 --> 00:55:48,388
Half now, half when I bring her home.

610
00:55:48,475 --> 00:55:49,305
All!

611
00:55:50,310 --> 00:55:51,224
Right now!

612
00:55:51,354 --> 00:55:54,058
Half, that's the best I'll do.

613
00:55:55,733 --> 00:55:57,441
You just been hustled, Bumpy.

614
00:55:58,152 --> 00:55:59,694
Deliver the money tonight.

615
00:56:00,780 --> 00:56:03,070
I'll have my boys drop it off.

616
00:56:03,700 --> 00:56:07,912
At these prices, you blow it, Shaft,
I'm not gonna like it.

617
00:56:08,120 --> 00:56:09,782
Not even a little bit.

618
00:56:10,040 --> 00:56:14,086
I thought the money didn't matter to you.
Just getting your baby back.

619
00:56:17,130 --> 00:56:18,923
Money always matters.

620
00:56:32,482 --> 00:56:34,391
This is where I get off, man.

621
00:56:35,150 --> 00:56:39,399
One thing we got to get straight.
If it comes to a fight, we do it my way.

622
00:56:40,490 --> 00:56:42,780
For that kind of bread,
the brothers'll play.

623
00:56:42,869 --> 00:56:45,027
As long as you remember
we owe them five.

624
00:56:45,120 --> 00:56:46,283
I said, my way!

625
00:56:48,876 --> 00:56:50,038
I'll call you.

626
00:57:23,205 --> 00:57:25,363
- Hey, man!
- Hey, Billy? Come here.

627
00:57:26,625 --> 00:57:28,120
- Do me a favor.
- Sure.

628
00:57:28,252 --> 00:57:32,380
- Go up to my place and turn on the...
- Hey, no, man. I've already turned on.

629
00:57:32,715 --> 00:57:34,458
No, Billy, turn on the lights.

630
00:57:34,592 --> 00:57:35,457
Lights.

631
00:57:35,550 --> 00:57:37,508
- About two minutes, okay?
- Got it.

632
00:58:32,530 --> 00:58:34,239
How are we doing, love?

633
00:58:35,576 --> 00:58:37,653
That's nice. Don't make any trouble.

634
00:58:38,705 --> 00:58:40,947
- Johnny!
- What do you say, Rollie?

635
00:58:41,374 --> 00:58:43,165
Gorgeous coat!

636
00:58:45,545 --> 00:58:48,547
How about letting me
take over the bar for a while?

637
00:58:48,632 --> 00:58:51,206
There's nothing I wouldn't do for $20.

638
00:58:56,933 --> 00:58:58,178
Have funzies.

639
00:59:24,087 --> 00:59:25,202
You look ready.

640
00:59:25,798 --> 00:59:28,206
Yeah, okay. Scotch and water, both.

641
00:59:33,598 --> 00:59:35,009
On the house, gents.

642
00:59:40,689 --> 00:59:43,476
And since the house is buying,
I'll have one.

643
00:59:51,493 --> 00:59:53,948
To the big-hearted owner
of the No Name Bar.

644
00:59:54,037 --> 00:59:56,244
Whether he knows he's generous or not.

645
01:00:02,672 --> 01:00:03,786
That's all booze!

646
01:00:03,923 --> 01:00:04,920
Right on.

647
01:00:05,425 --> 01:00:08,130
All booze. One zillion percent.

648
01:00:20,525 --> 01:00:21,687
Hold on.

649
01:00:25,447 --> 01:00:26,562
Hold on.

650
01:00:31,036 --> 01:00:33,278
No, he ain't here. Right.

651
01:00:36,668 --> 01:00:38,328
Ho there, innkeeper?

652
01:00:41,089 --> 01:00:44,625
Two gin and tonics, and a Virgin Mary...

653
01:00:45,136 --> 01:00:46,381
...for moi.

654
01:00:47,054 --> 01:00:48,928
I'm thirsty. Parched.

655
01:00:49,724 --> 01:00:51,551
There's a girl over there...

656
01:00:51,684 --> 01:00:54,258
...with the dark hair
and the groovy boobs...

657
01:00:55,439 --> 01:00:58,559
You really turn her on,
if you're interested.

658
01:01:00,027 --> 01:01:01,272
I ain't dead.

659
01:01:02,779 --> 01:01:06,612
Her friend, Valerie, says she's hot
for my body. I told her I was gay.

660
01:01:06,700 --> 01:01:09,785
You know what she said?
She'd straighten me out.

661
01:01:10,914 --> 01:01:12,538
That's what she said.

662
01:01:13,375 --> 01:01:17,325
It's not enough that I'm lovely,
she wants me to play character parts.

663
01:01:17,880 --> 01:01:22,625
The one with the titillating boobs
is named Linda.

664
01:01:36,192 --> 01:01:38,019
Man can't walk on one leg.

665
01:01:44,868 --> 01:01:46,446
Hate drinking alone.

666
01:02:17,237 --> 01:02:19,064
Vic, private line.

667
01:02:22,994 --> 01:02:24,108
Hey, sweet baby?

668
01:02:24,245 --> 01:02:25,822
This is your lover man.

669
01:02:26,914 --> 01:02:28,539
Who the hell is this?

670
01:02:29,375 --> 01:02:30,869
Two sweet guesses.

671
01:02:33,005 --> 01:02:34,250
That you, Shaft?

672
01:02:34,339 --> 01:02:38,752
You bet your lovely self it is.
And I'm ready. Can you dig it?

673
01:02:40,387 --> 01:02:41,384
Got troubles?

674
01:02:43,016 --> 01:02:45,174
- I got what you want.
- Where are you?

675
01:02:45,268 --> 01:02:47,011
No Name Bar in the Village.

676
01:02:47,312 --> 01:02:48,806
On Jane Street.

677
01:02:50,648 --> 01:02:53,935
- What do you want me to do?
- Haul your beautiful self down here.

678
01:02:54,069 --> 01:02:55,267
How many are there?

679
01:02:56,280 --> 01:02:57,478
About two.

680
01:02:58,782 --> 01:03:01,274
I'll close up and we'll go over to my pad.

681
01:03:02,120 --> 01:03:04,789
You walk in that front door,
I'll close up right now.

682
01:03:07,042 --> 01:03:10,910
- I'll have a car there in a few seconds.
- That's what I want to hear.

683
01:03:19,680 --> 01:03:21,508
A lot of loose stuff around here?

684
01:03:24,978 --> 01:03:26,971
All a man can handle, deacon.

685
01:03:31,986 --> 01:03:33,611
What are you looking at?

686
01:03:38,200 --> 01:03:39,363
Get lost.

687
01:03:42,706 --> 01:03:44,165
Go do something.

688
01:03:46,000 --> 01:03:47,543
Where are my manners?

689
01:03:48,379 --> 01:03:50,835
I didn't even introduce myself
to you gentlemen.

690
01:03:52,509 --> 01:03:54,964
My name is John Shaft.

691
01:03:55,887 --> 01:03:56,918
Freeze!

692
01:04:14,324 --> 01:04:15,783
Throw me a towel.

693
01:04:16,660 --> 01:04:19,496
There's two of them.
We're generous around here.

694
01:04:30,509 --> 01:04:31,884
It's not so bad.

695
01:04:37,016 --> 01:04:39,009
It's a nice pad you got here.

696
01:04:39,895 --> 01:04:42,895
I'm going upstairs to take a shower.
I'll be right back.

697
01:04:51,574 --> 01:04:53,365
I just couldn't wait.

698
01:05:21,065 --> 01:05:23,141
- What do you say, Vic?
- 'Morning.

699
01:05:24,318 --> 01:05:27,320
Both of them had guns,
licenses to carry them.

700
01:05:28,030 --> 01:05:30,604
"Jewelry couriers," the licenses say.

701
01:05:31,243 --> 01:05:32,737
Detroit people.

702
01:05:35,120 --> 01:05:37,364
- Will you turn them loose?
- I have no choice.

703
01:05:38,459 --> 01:05:40,202
They'll leave town.

704
01:05:40,294 --> 01:05:43,129
You'll have strangers looking for you,
not them.

705
01:05:44,090 --> 01:05:45,963
Can I have a private talk with them?

706
01:05:47,094 --> 01:05:50,095
What you'll do to poor Carmen now?
Give him cancer?

707
01:05:51,390 --> 01:05:53,347
You busted his head, settle.

708
01:05:55,185 --> 01:05:57,891
I want to find out his views
on urban renewal.

709
01:06:01,776 --> 01:06:02,891
All right.

710
01:06:28,848 --> 01:06:30,840
I'm speaking for Bumpy Jonas.

711
01:06:30,933 --> 01:06:33,471
He wants to be sure his daughter's okay.

712
01:06:33,894 --> 01:06:38,557
My word is all he'll take.
No phone calls and no letters from her.

713
01:06:39,443 --> 01:06:41,020
I've got to see her.

714
01:06:42,905 --> 01:06:44,529
Then maybe he'll deal.

715
01:06:46,284 --> 01:06:48,691
Nothing I want to say in this rat hole.

716
01:06:49,287 --> 01:06:52,822
- People might be listening.
- That's a risk we'll have to take.

717
01:06:53,040 --> 01:06:56,458
Now give me a number
so I can let you know where I'll be.

718
01:06:57,463 --> 01:07:00,001
I'll call you at 12:30 sharp!

719
01:07:01,050 --> 01:07:03,801
And meet you at 12:45
somewhere in the Village.

720
01:07:58,780 --> 01:08:00,025
Hey, baby?

721
01:08:01,490 --> 01:08:03,484
- Come here.
- Party's over.

722
01:08:03,744 --> 01:08:05,203
You got to split.

723
01:08:06,247 --> 01:08:08,952
Some other time.
Same feeling, same place.

724
01:08:09,083 --> 01:08:11,954
Right now I've got to take care
of some business.

725
01:08:34,945 --> 01:08:36,108
Put Ben on.

726
01:08:36,196 --> 01:08:38,319
He's asleep, who wants him?

727
01:08:38,699 --> 01:08:40,905
Wake him up, it's John Shaft.

728
01:08:41,744 --> 01:08:44,662
You're really great in the sack, but...

729
01:08:45,916 --> 01:08:48,074
...you're pretty shitty afterwards.

730
01:08:52,005 --> 01:08:54,378
I'm trying to take care of some business.

731
01:08:56,636 --> 01:08:57,667
Come on!

732
01:08:59,680 --> 01:09:01,887
I need two good men. Are you ready?

733
01:09:01,974 --> 01:09:02,889
Yeah.

734
01:09:02,976 --> 01:09:04,720
They'd better be tough.

735
01:09:07,022 --> 01:09:08,931
Baby, please close the door.

736
01:09:11,026 --> 01:09:12,818
Close it yourself, Shitty.

737
01:09:16,532 --> 01:09:19,736
- Tell me where and when.
- At Café Reggio in the Village.

738
01:09:19,827 --> 01:09:21,619
- Know where it is?
- I'll find it.

739
01:09:21,870 --> 01:09:24,161
12:30. Five minutes late would be too late.

740
01:09:24,249 --> 01:09:26,076
I'll be there. 'Bye.

741
01:10:08,673 --> 01:10:10,333
It's Vic Androzzi.

742
01:10:15,680 --> 01:10:17,508
What the hell are you doing here?

743
01:10:22,147 --> 01:10:23,855
I got no time for chats.

744
01:10:36,037 --> 01:10:40,034
You had time for a chat with Carmen
and Patsy in my office this morning.

745
01:10:46,214 --> 01:10:48,540
You got me in one hell of a mess.

746
01:10:51,304 --> 01:10:54,091
- Did you have the room bugged?
- No, not me.

747
01:10:54,557 --> 01:10:57,013
Me? I could turn the other way.

748
01:10:57,936 --> 01:10:59,810
Not hear what I heard.

749
01:11:01,940 --> 01:11:04,977
It's that big-eared Captain I got
who was listening.

750
01:11:08,155 --> 01:11:10,908
He thinks he heard you discussing
a kidnapping.

751
01:11:13,119 --> 01:11:15,159
He thinks the Mafia's involved.

752
01:11:18,249 --> 01:11:20,373
And he knows Bumpy Jonas is involved.

753
01:11:20,710 --> 01:11:22,205
Tell him to ask Bumpy then.

754
01:11:22,964 --> 01:11:23,995
Yeah, I did.

755
01:11:24,757 --> 01:11:26,382
But he wants to ask you.

756
01:11:26,592 --> 01:11:28,384
Now. At the station.

757
01:11:30,514 --> 01:11:32,091
Lousy timing, right?

758
01:11:32,516 --> 01:11:33,927
Gonna take me in?

759
01:11:35,894 --> 01:11:37,175
I will if I find you.

760
01:11:39,065 --> 01:11:40,096
Are you home?

761
01:11:40,608 --> 01:11:41,771
Hell, no.

762
01:11:43,695 --> 01:11:45,189
That's too bad.

763
01:11:52,162 --> 01:11:53,657
Call me when you get home.

764
01:11:54,957 --> 01:11:55,703
I will.

765
01:12:01,464 --> 01:12:03,504
"Close it yourself, Shitty."

766
01:12:29,162 --> 01:12:31,949
This is Shaft. Now get this straight!

767
01:12:33,166 --> 01:12:36,617
I'll be at Café Reggio
on McDougall street at 12:45.

768
01:12:38,422 --> 01:12:40,664
- Got it?
- Reggio, 12:45.

769
01:12:40,758 --> 01:12:41,623
Right.

770
01:13:39,739 --> 01:13:40,735
Menu?

771
01:13:41,616 --> 01:13:42,612
Espresso.

772
01:13:44,035 --> 01:13:46,788
Don't you want a sandwich
or something with it?

773
01:13:47,748 --> 01:13:49,159
Just espresso.

774
01:14:08,688 --> 01:14:10,977
I hope you don't like lemon peel.

775
01:14:12,358 --> 01:14:13,556
Let it go.

776
01:14:14,610 --> 01:14:17,233
I think you like it. I'll go get you some.

777
01:14:18,449 --> 01:14:20,572
I always forget the lemon peel.

778
01:14:53,278 --> 01:14:55,521
I'm looking for a nigger named John Shaft.

779
01:14:57,909 --> 01:14:59,783
You just found him, wop!

780
01:15:02,455 --> 01:15:03,534
Sit down.

781
01:15:04,040 --> 01:15:06,413
I have to take you to visit a lady.
Come on.

782
01:15:09,546 --> 01:15:11,456
I haven't finished my espresso.

783
01:15:12,758 --> 01:15:14,467
Why don't you have some?

784
01:15:16,972 --> 01:15:19,889
Maybe they'll put a little garlic in it,
if you're nice.

785
01:15:24,230 --> 01:15:26,899
No, thanks. But you go ahead.

786
01:15:30,360 --> 01:15:33,362
We've even got time for you
to have your soul food.

787
01:15:37,202 --> 01:15:38,365
Espresso?

788
01:15:39,663 --> 01:15:40,991
No, thanks.

789
01:15:44,377 --> 01:15:45,540
Keep it.

790
01:15:46,462 --> 01:15:47,838
Thanks, baby.

791
01:16:01,687 --> 01:16:02,766
Let's go.

792
01:17:40,045 --> 01:17:41,209
Come on.

793
01:18:13,958 --> 01:18:15,239
After you, man.

794
01:18:58,507 --> 01:18:59,753
You stay here.

795
01:18:59,842 --> 01:19:04,255
You get around the back, keep an eye
on the alley door. Stay out of sight.

796
01:19:04,597 --> 01:19:06,341
What if they come out our way?

797
01:19:06,432 --> 01:19:10,098
You follow them. Remmy,
you come back for me. Now move it!

798
01:19:24,369 --> 01:19:26,575
No noise. Now, answer me straight.

799
01:19:28,249 --> 01:19:29,791
No lies and no con.

800
01:19:30,835 --> 01:19:33,041
How many men you got in there with her?

801
01:19:33,170 --> 01:19:34,119
Two.

802
01:19:35,798 --> 01:19:36,794
Okay.

803
01:19:37,049 --> 01:19:41,463
When I tell you, you open that door like
this gun was about to blow your head off.

804
01:19:42,806 --> 01:19:44,882
No signal or you're gone. Got it?

805
01:19:46,059 --> 01:19:47,008
Yeah.

806
01:19:50,565 --> 01:19:51,181
Gin!

807
01:19:51,274 --> 01:19:52,388
Open it.

808
01:20:00,409 --> 01:20:02,200
Turn her loose or he goes.

809
01:20:04,246 --> 01:20:06,654
- Tell them to turn her loose.
- He won't.

810
01:20:08,043 --> 01:20:10,201
He won't shoot, Marcy, come here.

811
01:20:10,879 --> 01:20:13,037
There's nothing you can do, Shaft.

812
01:20:13,423 --> 01:20:16,839
Except go back to Harlem
and tell Bumpy his little girl is fine.

813
01:20:16,968 --> 01:20:19,923
- When I leave, she leaves with me.
- No way, Shaft.

814
01:20:20,139 --> 01:20:22,844
She's our ace. You never give up your ace.

815
01:20:23,309 --> 01:20:24,803
Maybe you're right.

816
01:20:25,144 --> 01:20:28,181
I should take you uptown
and turn you over to Bumpy.

817
01:20:29,190 --> 01:20:31,860
Change your mind, you can walk right now.

818
01:20:33,070 --> 01:20:36,024
You try to take the girl or me along,
you're dead.

819
01:20:36,323 --> 01:20:39,408
You trying to tell me they'd blow you away
to get me?

820
01:20:39,702 --> 01:20:40,947
That's right.

821
01:20:46,543 --> 01:20:50,375
I halfway believe you. But, you're my ace,
so I got to call you.

822
01:21:04,145 --> 01:21:07,432
The only thing that's keeping you alive
right now is...

823
01:21:07,566 --> 01:21:10,852
...you got to be fit enough
to go tell that black punk in Harlem...

824
01:21:10,945 --> 01:21:14,444
...that he's got 24 hours to deal
or he's got a dead daughter!

825
01:21:14,532 --> 01:21:15,646
And a war!

826
01:21:16,159 --> 01:21:17,357
You hear me?

827
01:21:20,580 --> 01:21:22,158
Come on, let's go!

828
01:21:23,250 --> 01:21:24,329
Let's go!

829
01:21:31,718 --> 01:21:32,963
Back door.

830
01:22:09,217 --> 01:22:10,332
Come on.

831
01:22:13,430 --> 01:22:14,461
Come on!

832
01:22:25,069 --> 01:22:26,777
You all right? Come on.

833
01:22:27,529 --> 01:22:28,561
Come on.

834
01:22:28,655 --> 01:22:30,066
You all right?

835
01:22:32,200 --> 01:22:33,825
Get me up out of here.

836
01:22:34,913 --> 01:22:37,783
The place'll be stinking with cops
in a minute.

837
01:22:40,168 --> 01:22:42,873
Grab those guns. Let's get out of here.

838
01:22:53,182 --> 01:22:55,721
- Ellie! Ellie, open up!
- Yes!

839
01:22:58,772 --> 01:23:00,480
My God! What happened?

840
01:23:01,358 --> 01:23:02,638
He's been shot.

841
01:23:06,030 --> 01:23:07,608
Put him on the couch.

842
01:23:08,740 --> 01:23:11,279
Didn't want to tell you on the phone.

843
01:23:23,258 --> 01:23:24,918
Ellie, call Sam.

844
01:23:25,552 --> 01:23:28,469
- You need a real doctor, baby.
- I said, call Sam.

845
01:23:42,988 --> 01:23:43,937
Easy.

846
01:23:52,832 --> 01:23:53,863
Blade.

847
01:23:55,168 --> 01:23:56,626
Get on the phone.

848
01:23:57,295 --> 01:24:00,628
We gonna need some more brothers.
With guns this time.

849
01:24:05,763 --> 01:24:08,514
Bumpy'll handle the transportation.

850
01:24:32,750 --> 01:24:34,411
Had to bring you to, Johnny.

851
01:24:34,503 --> 01:24:37,788
Can't fix anything else,
till you tell me where you hurt.

852
01:24:39,049 --> 01:24:40,543
Wall to wall, Sam.

853
01:24:42,887 --> 01:24:44,761
Ellie, give me that phone.

854
01:24:46,140 --> 01:24:48,014
- Get those boys?
- Got eight.

855
01:24:50,937 --> 01:24:52,218
Know where they took her?

856
01:24:52,314 --> 01:24:55,813
One of the brothers tailed them.
He's watching the place now.

857
01:24:56,150 --> 01:24:57,895
What about the back exit?

858
01:24:58,237 --> 01:25:00,644
Everything's cool, baby. Don't worry.

859
01:25:01,157 --> 01:25:02,901
Did you run into a train?

860
01:25:04,119 --> 01:25:07,618
Tight as you can get it.
I got to get up soon as you're done.

861
01:25:12,670 --> 01:25:15,077
Damn, those were some tough white boys.

862
01:25:15,715 --> 01:25:18,087
You're gonna have one hell of a time.

863
01:25:18,217 --> 01:25:20,543
Got a bad sprain on that right wrist.

864
01:25:20,720 --> 01:25:21,634
Tape it.

865
01:25:21,722 --> 01:25:25,470
I did, damn it. What do you think I am,
an amateur?

866
01:25:26,600 --> 01:25:29,472
Too good of a job, Sam.
I didn't even feel it.

867
01:25:46,957 --> 01:25:48,155
Wrong number.

868
01:25:48,250 --> 01:25:51,287
Cut the crap, man. This is Shaft.
I saw Marcy.

869
01:25:51,838 --> 01:25:53,249
Is she all right?

870
01:25:54,132 --> 01:25:55,591
Scared to death, but okay.

871
01:25:55,800 --> 01:25:59,086
I need three cabs,
on the corner of Ninth and Washington.

872
01:26:00,222 --> 01:26:02,678
- To pick up some of Ben's people.
- How soon?

873
01:26:02,767 --> 01:26:04,225
Now, man, now!

874
01:26:20,620 --> 01:26:23,027
Okay, you two! Outside! Move, move!

875
01:26:24,165 --> 01:26:25,244
Let's go!

876
01:26:27,877 --> 01:26:29,206
Tie them up!

877
01:26:31,215 --> 01:26:33,421
All right, where are the uniforms?

878
01:26:53,406 --> 01:26:56,027
- Who's that?
- The night janitor. He's okay.

879
01:26:56,909 --> 01:26:59,662
Use him to find out
which room they got her in.

880
01:27:01,456 --> 01:27:03,864
- Getting it together?
- Yeah, right on.

881
01:27:15,304 --> 01:27:16,467
Beautiful.

882
01:27:25,149 --> 01:27:26,429
Just beautiful.

883
01:27:28,319 --> 01:27:30,063
Jerry, how are you doing, baby?

884
01:27:34,367 --> 01:27:35,482
Hey, boy?

885
01:27:40,374 --> 01:27:42,414
Send up two coffees and a Coke.

886
01:27:43,669 --> 01:27:45,080
Glass or a straw?

887
01:27:46,422 --> 01:27:47,668
For the Coke.

888
01:27:48,008 --> 01:27:49,383
Make it a straw.

889
01:27:53,638 --> 01:27:54,634
Straw?

890
01:27:55,265 --> 01:27:56,844
You heard me, straw.

891
01:27:58,936 --> 01:28:00,395
Right.

892
01:28:03,066 --> 01:28:04,690
You're a shrewd cat, Shaft.

893
01:28:04,776 --> 01:28:07,777
You and your boys blow it
and I'll be one dead cat!

894
01:28:08,405 --> 01:28:10,979
You all know the plan. No mistakes.

895
01:28:12,950 --> 01:28:14,031
Let's go.

896
01:28:48,533 --> 01:28:51,569
There you are, sir.
Two coffees, a Coke and a straw.

897
01:28:51,828 --> 01:28:53,785
- Want me to take it in?
- Whoa.

898
01:28:57,084 --> 01:28:58,080
Right.

899
01:29:05,510 --> 01:29:06,921
Hey, thank you!

900
01:29:08,513 --> 01:29:10,304
- I'll be seeing you.
- Okay.

901
01:30:17,380 --> 01:30:18,460
Shut up!

902
01:30:22,636 --> 01:30:24,962
- What do you guys want?
- Your coat.

903
01:30:54,463 --> 01:30:55,874
Rope and harness.

904
01:31:13,317 --> 01:31:14,562
Go ahead down.

905
01:31:47,855 --> 01:31:49,480
Did you hear anything?

906
01:33:17,704 --> 01:33:19,911
This damn thing won't burn hot enough.

907
01:33:19,999 --> 01:33:22,668
You got something else
in there that'll burn?

908
01:33:39,437 --> 01:33:40,682
It's gin, man.

909
01:33:45,610 --> 01:33:47,068
What else you got?

910
01:33:51,240 --> 01:33:52,321
Gasoline.

911
01:34:03,588 --> 01:34:04,619
Come on!

912
01:34:36,707 --> 01:34:38,251
Give me a cigarette.

913
01:34:49,389 --> 01:34:51,298
- You know what to do?
- Yeah.

914
01:37:24,810 --> 01:37:26,637
Let's get out of here!

915
01:37:53,299 --> 01:37:54,331
Come on!

916
01:37:55,886 --> 01:37:56,965
Let's go!

917
01:38:49,027 --> 01:38:50,308
Androzzi, here.

918
01:38:51,029 --> 01:38:54,234
- Vic, your case just busted wide open.
- So close it for me.

919
01:38:54,325 --> 01:38:56,484
Cut the crap, man. This is Shaft.

920
01:38:56,910 --> 01:39:00,031
"You'll have to close
it yourself, Shitty! "

