It's hormonal.
I mean, I don't usually fall back on...
You know, it's women's issues.
But child-proofed how? Gates and stuff?
Dude, she did the drawers.
We don't even know
if this whole fertility thing's gonna work.
She's screwed in these little jobbies
where you can't even open the drawers.
At all?
No. They open, you know, like an inch,
then you gotta dig your finger in.
- I mean, it's a nightmare.
- I guess sooner or later.
Yeah, well, a lot later.
She did the upper cabinets.
Kid will be 30 before he can reach them,
assuming, you know, we have a kid.
It is natural for her to feel protective.
Don't even... You have women's issues.
Please. You of all people.
Oh, come on. It's a jinx.
It guarantees that we won't get pregnant.
And it takes me about 20 minutes
to get a fucking beer.
Guys. Guys!
Stockholm went south.
Seriously?
I thought they were looking good.
What cracked?
I haven't seen the footage.
Word's just going around.
Well, that's never been a stable scenario.
Everyone knows you can't trust Swedes.
That means there's just Japan.
Japan and us.
It's not the first time
it's come down to that.
Japan has a perfect record.
We're number two. We try harder.
- But, guys, if we fail, then...
- Please. We haven't had a glitch since '98.
We know what we're doing, Lin.
Or we have it written down, somewhere.
You guys better not be
messing around in there.
Does this mean you're not
in the betting pool this year? Big money.
I'm just saying, it's a key scenario.
No, I hear what you're saying.
In '98,
it was the chem department's fault, right?
Where do you work, again?
Wait. It's coming back to me now.
It's gonna be a long weekend
if everyone's that puckered up.
So, you wanna come over Monday night?
I'm gonna pick up some power drills.
Liberate my cabinets.
Are you even listening to me?
Professor Fuckwad.
Why haven't you stuck that asshole's
picture on the dartboard yet?
It's not that simple... Oh, my God!
- Your hair. It's blonde.
- Very fabulous, no?
I can't believe you did it.
But very fabulous, right?
Hurry up with the "very fabulous."
I'm getting insecure about it now.
God, no, no, it looks awesome.
Curt's gonna lose it.
Curt's gonna thank me. And so will you.
- While we're burning this picture.
- Not ready.
Seriously, this isn't his fault.
What's not his fault?
Fucking his student
or breaking up with her by e-mail?
I knew what I was getting into.
Oh, please.
You know what you're getting into
this weekend?
This.
And if Holden's as cute as Curt says he is,
possibly getting out of it.
Okay, that is the last thing that I want.
If you guys treat this like a setup,
I'm gonna have no fun at all.
I'm not pushing.
But we're packing this!
Which means we definitely
won't have room for...
What if I get bored?
These will help?
"Soviet Economic Structures"?
"Aftermath of the... "No!
We have a lake and a keg.
- No more learning!
- Think fast.
Faster than that.
Sorry. Sorry. Move along.
- Nice!
- Is that Holden?
We'll be right down.
He just transferred from State.
Best hands on the team. He's a sweet guy.
And he's good with his hands.
Hey, I'm kind of seeing this girl,
but you're way blonder than she is.
But I was thinking, you know, maybe...
What is this?
What are these?
What are you doing with these?
Okay, I get it. I'll leave the books.
No, no, no. Who gave you these?
Who taught you about these?
I learned it from you, okay?
I learned it from watching you!
Seriously, Professor Bennett,
he covers this whole book in his lectures.
You should read this.
Gurovsky. Now this is way more interesting.
Also, Bennett doesn't know it by heart,
so he'll think you're insightful.
And you have no pants.
Oh, shit!
- That pretty much it?
- Fucking better be.
You know, Jules, it's a weekend,
not an evacuation.
Trust me when I say
there is nothing in those cases
you won't be glad I brought.
I'm shutting right up.
Oh, my God.
Marty!
Fuck is wrong with you, bro?
People in this town drive
in a very counterintuitive manner.
That's what I have to say.
All right, do you wanna spend
the weekend in jail?
'Cause we'd all like to check out
my cousin's country home.
Marty, honey, that's not okay.
Statistical fact.
Cops will never pull over a man
with a huge bong in his car.
Why?
They fear this man.
They know he sees further than they,
and he will bind them with ancient logics.
Have you gone gray?
You're not bringing that thing
in the Rambler.
What? A giant bong in your father's van?
What are you, stoned?
Hey, man.
Dana, you fetching minx!
You have any food?
- Everybody ready?
- Yeah!
- Yeah?
- Okay, I'm ready!
Let's get this show on the road!
Fuck, yeah!
Nest is empty. We're right on time.
I hope this is the right road.
It doesn't even show up on the GPS.
It is unworthy of global positioning.
That's the whole point.
Get off the grid, right?
No cell phone reception,
no traffic cameras.
Go someplace for one goddamn weekend
where they can't
globally position my ass, man.
This is the whole issue.
Is society crumbling, Marty?
No. Society is binding. Right?
It's filling in the cracks with concrete.
Everything's filed or recorded
or blogged, right?
Chips in our kids' heads
so they won't get lost.
Society needs to crumble.
We're all just too chickenshit to let it.
I've missed your rants.
You will come to see things my way.
Identification, please.
Mr. Sitterson.
- Mr. Hadley.
- Thank you.
- What's your name?
- Daniel Truman, sir.
This isn't the military, Truman.
You can drop the "sir."
But Sitterson does like
to be called "ma'am."
- Or "honey toes."
- He will also answer to "honey toes."
You clear
on what's gonna be happening here?
I've been prepped. Extensively.
And did they tell you that being prepped
is not the same thing as being prepared?
They told me. I'll hold my post, Mr.
Hadley.
Good man.
Okay. System's online.
Acquiring target. Let's see what we got.
All right.
I'm thinking this thing
doesn't take credit cards.
I don't think it knows about money.
I think it's barter gas.
Hello?
Hey, Holden.
- Holden!
- I don't think there's gonna be any...
You come here uninvited?
Fuck! Dude.
Sign says "closed."
Yeah, we were looking to buy some gas.
Does this pump work?
If you know how to work it.
We also wanted to get directions.
Yeah, we're looking for...
What's it called?
Tillerman Road.
Do you know if it's this way?
Tillerman Road takes you
up the hill, there.
Dead-ends at the old Buckner place.
My cousin bought a house up there.
You go through, like, a mountain tunnel,
there's a lake.
- Would that be the...
- Buckner place.
Always someone looking to sell that plot.
You knew the original owners?
Yeah, not the first.
I seen plenty come and go.
Hell, I been here since the war.
- Which war?
- You know damn well which war!
Would that have been
with the blue and some in gray?
Brother, perhaps,
fighting against brother in that war?
You sassing me, boy?
You were rude to my friend.
That whore?
- What'd you say?
- I think we got enough gas.
You got enough to get you there.
Getting back, that's your concern.
Well, good luck with your business, sir.
I know the railroad's
coming through here any day now.
That's gonna be big.
Streets paved with actual street.
Fucker,
Guys, take a look.
This must be it.
Oh, my God. It's beautiful.
One spider, and I'm
sleeping in the Rambler.
I mean it.
Come on. Give me a hand.
This is awesome.
It is kind of cool.
Are you gonna kill us a raccoon to eat?
I will use its skin to make a cap.
Everybody get your suits on.
In 10 minutes, we're hitting the lake.
- Yeah.
- I was not informed
there would be calisthenics.
Yeah, I don't think so.
No way.
Shit.
This is happening.
Hold up!
You've gotta be fucking kidding me.
That's just creepy.
It was pioneer days.
People had to make
their own interrogation rooms.
Who did your cousin buy this place from?
We should check the rest of the rooms,
make sure this is the only one.
'Cause you know Marty wants to
watch us pounding away.
I didn't even like hearing that.
Don't be an ape, Curt.
How about we switch?
Not that I'd...
I mean, I'd put the picture back,
but you might feel better
if we switched rooms?
I really would.
Thanks. For being decent.
It's the least I could do,
since Curt and Jules
sold you to me for marriage.
They're not subtle.
Well, I'll just be flattered
and keep it to myself.
Yeah, I'm not looking for...
But I'm still grateful
that you're not a creep.
Let's not jump to any conclusions there.
I had kind of an internal debate
about showing you the mirror.
Shouting on both sides. Blood was spilled.
So, you're bleeding internally?
Pretty bad.
Well, Jules is pre-med.
You should probably talk to her.
Okay.
Yeah, I don't think so.
- I gotta say, I like my room.
- Over here.
Places, everyone. We are live.
Engineering, we got a room change.
Polk is now in two, McCrea is in four.
Operations, do you copy?
We need a scenario adjustment.
Miss Lin.
We've got the blood work back on Louden.
Her levels are good,
but we're recommending
a 50-milligram bump of Rhohyptase
- to increase libido.
- Sold.
Do we pipe it in,
or do you wanna do it orally?
Ask me that again, only slower.
You're a pig.
Guess how we're slowing down cognition.
I don't know.
The hair dye.
Dumb blonde. Very artistic.
Works its way into the blood,
through the scalp. Very gradual.
Chem department keeps their end up.
I'll see it when I believe it.
- Control?
- Yeah, go ahead.
I have the harbinger on line two.
Oh, Christ. Can you take a message?
I don't think so. He's really pushy.
To be honest, he's kind of freaking me out.
Okay. Put him on.
Mordecai, baby, what's happening?
How's the weather up top?
The lambs have passed through the gate.
They are come to the killing floor.
Well, you're doing a great job out there.
By the numbers, man.
You got us started off just right.
So, we'll talk to you later, okay?
Their blind eyes see nothing
of the horrors to come.
Their ears are stopped.
They are the gods' fools.
Well, that's how it works.
Cleanse them. Cleanse the world
of their ignorance and sin.
Bathe them in the crimson of...
Am I on speakerphone?
No. Absolutely not.
Speakerphone, no. No, I wouldn't do that.
Yes, I am. I can hear the echo.
Oh, my God. You're right.
Hang on one second, I'll take you off.
That's rude. I don't
know who's in the room.
Fine. There. You're off.
Thank you.
Don't take this lightly, boy.
It wasn't all by your numbers.
The fool nearly derailed the invocation
with his insolence.
The Ancient Ones see everything.
And they will not be...
I'm still on speakerphone, aren't I?
Oh, my God. Mordecai!
I can't believe it. It did it again!
Mordy?
What happens next?
That's cold!
Yeah? HOW cold? IS it worth it?
Come on, Jules. Life is risk.
Yeah, I might just risk
lying out in the sun for a while.
Hey, what is that?
- What?
- In the lake, right there.
- Come on.
- You guys, I'm serious. Right there.
There! There!
God, it looks just like my girlfriend!
Oh, my God!
There's something else in the lake!
It's a gorgeous man!
I'm gonna kill you!
Don't kill the gorgeous man!
We're endangered!
All right. Last chance. It's post time.
Dig deep, people.
Betting windows are closing.
Okay, who's still out?
Let's see. We got Engineering,
we got R&D, and we got Electrical.
Did you see who they picked? They're
practically giving their money away.
You should talk, Aquaman.
- What do you mean?
- Nothing.
Okay, all right.
I'm not even sure we have one of these.
Zoology swears we do.
They'd know. Okay. All right, people.
Hey, what do you got?
No, they've already been picked.
What? No. Who took them?
- Maintenance.
- Maintenance?
- They pick the same thing every year.
- What do you want from me?
If they were creative,
they wouldn't be in Maintenance.
Now, you're gonna have to split this
if you win. You wanna switch?
I don't know, I don't know.
What do you think?
More than anything,
I just want this moment to end.
- Not betting?
- Not for me. Thanks.
Seems a little harsh, doesn't it?
It's just people letting off steam.
This job isn't easy,
however those clowns may behave.
Does The Director...
Do they know about this downstairs?
The Director doesn't care about this stuff.
As long as everything
goes smoothly upstairs,
as long as the kids do as they're told.
But then it's fixed.
No, no, no.
How can you wager on this
when you control the outcome?
No, we just get them in the cellar.
They take it from there.
No, they have to make the choice
of their own free will.
Otherwise the system doesn't work.
It's like the harbinger.
It's this creepy old fuck,
practically wears a sign, "You will die."
Why do we put him there? The system.
They have to choose to ignore him,
and they have to choose
what happens in the cellar.
Yeah, we rig the game
as much as we need to,
but in the end, they don't transgress...
They can't be punished.
So what's it gonna be, Truman?
You in? Window's closing.
I'm fine.
Okay. That's it, gang!
The board is locked!
Let's get this party started!
Yeah, okay, who wants a beer?
There you go.
Okay, my turn.
Jules.
Truth or dare?
- Let's go dare.
- All right.
I dare you to make out with...
Please say "Dana," please say "Dana,"
please say "Dana."
...that moose, over there.
Marty, have you ever seen a moose before?
Whatever that mysterious beast is.
- That's a wolf.
- That's clearly a wolf.
I'm living in a womb of reefer,
leave me alone.
Jules,
I dare you to make out with that wolf.
No problem.
Who?
Me?
Why, yes, I am new in town.
How did you know?
Oh, my God. That is so sweet of you to say.
I just colored it, in fact.
No, no, no.
There's no need to huff and puff.
I'll let you come in.
Thank you.
- Yeah.
- All right.
- Yeah, baby!
Now, then.
- Dana.
- Truth.
What's that supposed to mean?
I'm just skipping ahead.
You're gonna say dare.
She's gonna dare you
to do something you don't like,
and then you'll puss out
and say that you wanted truth all along.
Really?
Okay, Jules. Dare.
What the hell was that?
It's the cellar door.
The wind must've blown it open.
That makes what kind of sense?
What do you think is down there?
Why don't we find out?
Dana.
I dare you.
How long do I have to stay down here?
You know, just till morning.
Dana.
You Okay?
Yeah.
Sorry, I just scared myself.
Well, you called for help.
That voids the dare. Take your top off.
What?
I don't make up the rules.
Oh, my God.
Look at all this.
Guys,
I'm not sure it's awesome to be down here.
Guys?
Dude, seriously,
your cousin is into some weird shit.
Yeah, well, I'm pretty sure this ain't his.
Maybe it was the people
who put in that mirror thing.
Some of this stuff looks really old.
It's beautiful.
Maybe we should go back upstairs.
I dare you all to go upstairs.
Guys?
Guys, listen to this.
"April 4th.
"Father was cross with me
and said I lacked the true faith.
"I wish I could prove my devotion
"as Judah and Matthew proved
on those travelers."
What is that?
"Diary of Anna Patience Buckner, 1903.
"Mama screamed most of the night.
"I prayed that she might find faith,
"but she only stopped
when Papa cut her belly
"and stuffed the coals in.
"Judah told me in my dream
"that Matthew took him to the black room,
so I know he is killed.
"I want to understand the glory of the pain
like Matthew,
"but cutting the flesh
makes him have a husband's bulge
"and I do not get like that."
- Jesus. Can we not...
- No, no. Go on.
- Why?
- I want to know.
"I have found it
"in the oldest books,
the way of saving our family.
"My good arm is hacked up
"and et, so I hope this will be readable.
"That a believer will come
and speak this to our spirits.
"Then we will be restored
and the great pain will return."
And then there's something in Latin.
Okay, I'm drawing a line
in the fucking sand, here.
Do not read the Latin.
Read it.
What the fuck?
Read it out loud.
No, no, no.
Stop being a fucking baby.
- Curt!
- It's a diary.
- It doesn't even mean anything.
- Dana!
We have a winner!
It's the Buckners, ladies and gentlemen.
The Buckners pull a
All right. That means
that congratulations go to Maintenance,
who share the pot with Ronald the intern.
- Yeah!
- Wait. That's not fair. I had zombies, too.
Yes, you did. Yes, you had zombies.
But this is
"Zombie Redneck Torture Family," see?
They're entirely separate species.
Like the difference between an elephant
and an elephant seal.
There's always next year.
They're like something from a nightmare.
No. They're something nightmares are from.
Everything in our stable
is remnant of the old world,
courtesy of you-know-who.
Monsters. Magic.
Gods.
You get used to it.
Should you?
Oh, man. I'm sorry.
- He had the conch in his hands.
- I know. I know.
A couple more minutes,
who knows what might've happened?
I am never gonna see a merman. Ever.
Dude, be thankful.
Those things are terrifying.
And the cleanup on them is a nightmare.
So, the Buckners.
Yeah, well, they may be zombified,
pain-worshipping, backwoods idiots.
But they're our zombified,
- With a 100% clearance rate.
- True.
So should we call Japan?
Tell them to take
the rest of the weekend off?
Yeah, right. They're Japanese.
What are they gonna do? Relax?
I'd just like to see them
fall on their asses for once.
Oh, God, don't even joke.
Every other branch has air-balled.
We need the Japanese crew to get it done.
There's too much riding on this.
Fuck, yeah, baby.
This is so classy.
Come on,
like you wouldn't want a piece of that.
Can we not talk
about people in pieces anymore tonight?
Are you feeling lonely, Marty?
Marty and I were sweeties
in our freshman hall.
We made out once.
I never did buy that ring.
But we're still
close.
I have a theory about all this.
That's our cue to bail.
Tommy Chong here has a theory.
Come on, baby.
Don't worry, you can tell
it to Egghead, here,
if he's not too busy de-virginizing Dana.
Jules, do you wanna go lie down?
That's exactly the point.
Come on. Mush. Mush.
- Don't push me around.
- Not around, baby. Straight line.
You seriously believe
nothing weird is going on?
Conspiracy?
The way everybody's acting.
Why is Jules suddenly a celebu-tard?
And since when does Curt
pull this alpha-male bullshit?
I mean, he's a sociology major.
He's on full academic scholarship,
and now he's calling his friend an egghead?
Curt's just drunk.
I've seen Curt drunk.
Jules, too.
Well, then, maybe it's something else.
You're not seeing
what you don't wanna see.
Puppeteers.
- Puppeteers?
- Pop-Tarts?
Did you say you have Pop-Tarts?
Marty, I love you, but you're really high.
We are not who we are.
I'm gonna go read a book with pictures.
Thank you.
"The pain outlives the flesh.
"The flesh returns..."
or "has a meeting place."
What is that?
The Latin that you read in the basement.
You speak Latin?
Not well. Not since 10th grade.
Weird how it all comes back.
Well, it's a weird kind of night.
I'm sorry about tonight.
Everybody...
Do I lose points if I tell you
I'm having a pretty nice time?
No. You can tell me that.
What are you running away for?
Don't spill on me!
Did I get a little beer on your shirt?
I guess it'll have to come off, huh?
Not here.
Baby, come on.
We're all alone.
I'm chilly.
Okay, guys. That's it. Let's go.
We've got a job to do.
Your basic human needs disgust me.
Get out of here.
Do we have temperature control
in this sector?
On it.
Engaging pheromone mists.
It's so dark.
Take me inside?
Come on. This is why we came here.
It's romantic.
Okay, baby. Let's see some boobies.
Show us the goods.
Does it really matter if we see her...
We're not the only ones watching, kid.
Gotta keep the customer satisfied.
You understand what's at stake, here?
Score.
Jules!
Fuck.
Curt!
No! No!
Please! Please!
No!
Curt!
This we offer in humility and fear.
For the blessed peace
of your eternal slumber.
As it ever was.
Nemo, man, you gotta wake up.
Your shit is topsy-turvy.
I'm gonna go for a walk.
Okay. I swear to fucking God,
somebody is talking.
Or I'm pretty sure someone is.
I'm gonna go for a walk.
Enough!
What are you saying?
What do you want?
You think I'm a puppet, huh?
You think I'm a puppet? Gonna do a little
fucking puppet dance!
I'm the boss of my own
brain, so give it up.
I'm gonna go for a walk.
I don't wanna... I mean, I've never...
- I don't mean "never"...
- Hey.
Nothing you don't want.
He's got a husband bulge.
I thought there'd be stars.
We are abandoned.
- Fuck!
- Fucking run!
Curt!
Dead bitch!
Jesus, what happened?
- Curt!
- What the fuck?
Curt, what the fuck?
- Where are you hurt?
- Hold on. Hold on.
Is all of this from you?
It's okay! Curt, you're okay!
Where's Jules?
She's gone.
We've gotta get out of here.
No. No. Wait.
- Dana, don't open that...
- I'm not leaving here without Jules.
That dead girl's out there!
No!
Dana, come on!
What is that thing?
- Fuck!
- I don't know, but there's more of them.
More of them?
Yeah. I saw a young girl.
All zombied like him,
but she was missing an arm.
Oh, my God. Patience.
- The diary.
- Look.
- We gotta lock this place down.
- He's right.
We'll go room by room.
Barricade every window and door.
We gotta play it safe.
No matter what happens,
we have to stay together.
Fuck!
Calm down.
Watch the master work.
This isn't right.
What? What's the matter?
This isn't right. We should split up.
We can cover more ground that way.
Yeah.
Yeah. Good idea.
Really?
All right, guys, you
guys, get in your rooms.
Lock them in.
What the fuck?
What the...
That's not good.
Out of the way. Out of the way.
Out of the way.
Chem department,
I need 500 ccs of Thorazine
- pumped into room three.
- No, no, no.
Stand by, Chem.
Judah Buckner to the rescue.
What the fuck?
Fuck! What the fuck?
Oh, my God.
I'm on a reality TV show.
My parents are gonna think
I'm such a burnout.
No! No! No!
Help me! Help me!
Must be getting excited downstairs.
Greatest show on Earth.
Somebody open the door!
Come on!
- Use the bed!
- Come on! Come on!
Holden.
- It's empty.
- Go.
- Curt?
- Unlock the door.
I can't. Get down to the basement.
This is the black room.
Which?
From the diary.
This is where he killed them.
This is where he kills us.
No way. No.
He's not gonna kill us.
We just gotta find a door.
Okay?
Let's just check the walls, okay?
Curt?
I mean, there's gotta be...
You like pain?
How's that work for you?
These fucking zombies.
Remember when you could
just throw a girl in a volcano?
How old do you think I am?
Let's move! Come on! Come on! Go!
What about Marty?
They got him.
FUCK you!
Fuck you! Fuck you! Fuck you! Fuck you!
- You seeing this?
- Perfect record, huh?
The Japan crew should've had this
in the bag. They fucked us.
How hard is it to kill 9-year-olds?
Zero fatality. Total wash.
I'm telling you, you want good product,
you gotta buy American.
Any word from downstairs?
Downstairs doesn't care about Japan.
The Director trusts us.
Hey, you just sweat the chem, Lin.
While these morons are singing
What a Friend We Have in Shinto,
we are bringing the pain.
Yeah, and what the fuck's up
with this guy's pot, anyway?
He's supposed to be drooling
and instead he almost makes us?
We treated the shit out of it.
Okay, we've got the Rambler
heading toward the tunnel.
The fool's toast anyway.
And so are we
if you don't get this under control.
- Shit.
- What? "Shit" Why?
- Gotta go. Work to do.
- You guys are humanity's last hope.
If the Ancients rise, we...
- There's no cave-in.
- What?
The fucking tunnel's open!
Control to Demolition.
We're dark on the whole sector.
Try to bypass it.
- What the fuck do you think I'm doing?
- Okay, open the door.
Look out! Get out of the way!
Make a hole.
- What the fuck's going on?
- We don't know.
Electrical said there was a glitch up top.
That tunnel should've blown hours ago.
- Yeah, well, we didn't get the order.
- Come on.
Right there.
Hadley, what is going on?
Hadley? Why hasn't the tunnel blown?
Fuck!
No.
No, no. No fucking way!
Can't believe this, man.
This ain't happening.
It's right there.
All right. We got any climbing gear? Ropes?
Yeah. In my fucking dorm room.
We can't go back. There's no way across.
What are we gonna do? Jump?
Dude.
What?
Curt, are you sure about this?
I've done bigger jumps than this.
You've got a smooth run
and maybe a five-foot differential
on the other side.
But you've gotta give it everything.
Curt.
Look, you guys just stay in the Rambler.
I'll get help.
If I wipe out, I'll fucking limp for help.
But I'm coming back here.
I'm coming back with cops and choppers
and large fucking guns,
and those things are gonna pay.
For Jules.
Don't hold back.
Never do.
No!
Curt!
No! Oh, God!
Oh, God!
He hit something. There's nothing.
What'd he hit?
Puppeteers.
Marty was right.
Get in the van.
Dana.
Marty was right.
You're going back.
I'm going through.
And we'll just drive.
There's gotta be another road.
- Another way out of here.
- It won't work.
Something will happen.
It will collapse, it will wash away.
Then we just leave the roads altogether.
Drive as far as we can into the forest
and we go on foot from there.
You're missing the point.
Please, do not go nuts on me, okay, Dana?
You're all I've got now.
I'm okay.
Good, okay, 'cause I need you calm.
Okay, no matter what happens,
we gotta stick...
- Goddamn, that was close!
- Yeah, photo-fucking-finish.
I don't understand. You're celebrating?
They're celebrating. I'm drinking.
But she's still alive.
How can the ritual be complete?
The virgin's death is optional,
as long as it's last.
Main thing is that she suffers.
That she did.
It's so strange.
I'm actually rooting for this girl.
She's got so much heart.
And you think of all the pain and the...
Tequila is my lady! My lady!
Come on in, guys! Come on in. Come on in.
You're welcome.
Tequila! From darkness, there is light.
I wish that I could do what you do.
- Oh, my God.
- Yeah, it's masterful.
I don't know. Tonight was solid.
I don't know.
Are you kidding? Classic denouement.
When the van hits the lake...
- I screamed.
- Right?
And the water rushing in, and the zombie...
I just think it would've been cooler
with a merman.
Do you know if we get the overtime bonus
on this one?
Accounting's over there. Ask them.
I don't need to. I already know the answer.
I'm an intern.
So I don't qualify for OT.
It's funny that you like the ballet,
because I happen to have two tickets
to your favorite...
You knuckleheads.
You almost gave me a heart attack
with that tunnel.
Like I said, it wasn't our fault.
We didn't get the order.
Okay. All right,
I'm just giving you a hard time.
- Come on. Give us a hug.
- Hey.
No, seriously. That wasn't our fault.
There was a glitch.
Power re-route from upstairs.
What do you mean, "upstairs"?
Turn the fucking music off.
Hello?
That's impossible.
Everything was done within the guidelines.
The virgin's the only one...
No. I am not doubting you.
Which one?
- Marty.
- Hi.
Dana!
Dana, come on.
Marty. Wait.
We're going in the grave?
Dana, come on!
What is this place?
Yeah. I had to dismember that guy
with a trowel.
What have you been up to?
Nobody else, huh?
Yeah, I figured.
You figured everything.
Not at all.
But I do know some stuff.
As in...
It's an elevator.
Somebody sent those dead fucks
up here to get us.
Now, there's no controls inside,
but there's maintenance overrides in there.
And I think I can get it to go down.
Do we wanna go down?
Where else are we gonna go?
Come on. Get in.
Okay, okay, okay.
Come on!
Fucking zombie arm.
Oh, shit.
Shit!
Oh, my God.
We chose.
What? What?
Fuck!
In the cellar.
All that shit we were playing with.
They made us choose.
They made us choose how we die.
We saw them go down the access drop.
They have to be in one of these.
Internal security can...
I don't care if it's not protocol.
Are you fucking high?
It's the fool! Do not touch the girl.
If he outlives her,
this whole thing goes to hell.
Take him out first.
Cleanup says the prep team
missed one of the kid's stashes.
Whatever he's been smoking's
been immunizing him to all our shit.
How does that help us right now? What?
No, if you have a confirmed kill,
take her out, too.
There.
36-06.
Gotcha.
Bring them down.
Step out of the elevator!
Why are you trying to kill us?
Step out! Just the girl!
- What?
- Just me?
DO it!
Good work, zombie arm.
All right.
You shouldn't be here.
This should have gone differently.
Ended more quickly.
I can only imagine your pain and confusion.
But know this.
What's happening to you
is part of something bigger.
Something older than anything known.
You've seen horrible things.
An army of nightmare creatures.
But they are nothing
compared to what came before.
What lies below.
It's our task to placate the Ancient Ones.
As it's yours to be offered up to them.
Forgive us.
And let us get it over with.
Come on. Go in that room.
Army of nightmares, huh?
Let's get this party started.
Hold fire!
Oh, shit.
Go! Go! Go!
Lead officer Truman to security command.
Requesting immediate reinforcements.
Code black. I repeat. Code black.
Where the fuck are you guys?
Sector 12, down. Sector 8, down.
- Sector 3, down.
- Jesus Christ!
Why aren't the defenses working?
Where's the fucking gas?
Something chewed through the connections
from the utility shaft.
- Something which?
- Something scary!
The north exit is blocked.
You can't go there.
Go, go, go!
Fuck! We're running out of time!
It's on lockdown, I'm trying to bypass.
Hadley!
Oh, come on!
Oh, my God!
God!
It's you.
No, no, no. Please, please. Please. Please.
Kill him.
Okay, Dana, come on.
Dana.
Here. It's easier with this.
Look at these.
Five of them.
What are they?
Us.
I should have seen it like you did.
This is part of a ritual.
A ritual sacrifice?
Great.
You tie someone to a stone,
get a fancy dagger and a bunch of robes.
- It's not that complicated.
- No.
It's simple.
They don't just want to see us killed.
They want to see us punished.
Punished for what?
For being young.
It's different in every culture.
And it has changed over the years,
but it has always required youth.
There must be at least five.
The whore.
She's corrupted.
She dies first.
The athlete.
The scholar.
The fool.
All suffer and die at the hands of
whatever horror they have raised,
leaving the last to live or die,
as fate decides.
The virgin.
Me?
Virgin?
We work with what we have.
But what if you don't pull it off?
- They rise.
- Who does?
What's beneath us?
The Ancient Ones.
The gods that used to rule the Earth.
As long as they accept our sacrifice,
they remain below.
But the other rituals have all failed.
The sun is coming up in eight minutes.
If you live to see it, the world will end.
Maybe that's the way it should be.
If you've got to kill all
my friends to survive,
maybe it's time for a change.
We're not talking about change.
We're talking about the agonizing death
of every human soul on the planet.
Including you.
You can die with them,
or you can die for them.
Gosh, they're both so enticing.
The whole world, Marty.
Is in your hands, Dana.
There is no other way.
You have to be strong.
Yeah, Dana.
You feeling strong?
I'm sorry.
So am I.
(Mart)'-
Marty!
Hey-
You know,
I don't think Curt even has a cousin.
How are you?
Going away.
I'm sorry.
I'm so sorry I almost shot you.
I probably wouldn't have.
Hey. Hey, no. No.
I totally get it.
I'm sorry I let you get attacked
by a werewolf and then ended the world.
No.
Hey, you were right.
Humanity...
It's time to give someone else a chance.
Giant evil gods.
I wish I could've seen them.
I know.
That would have been a fun weekend.